Data length: 25344
0x0  /  0x3120  : 
0x1  /  0x3121  : Welcome to Adventure Quest from Level 9. Enter English phrases (without punctuation) to play, find and defeat the Demon Lord AGALIAREPT to win.


0x2  /  0x3182  : 

What next?


0x3  /  0x318e  : I don't understand
0x4  /  0x319b  : Please be more specific
0x5  /  0x31aa  : You can't do that
0x6  /  0x31b3  : You don't have it
0x7  /  0x31be  : It's not on the ground
0x8  /  0x31c8  : Your lamp is lit and shines brightly
0x9  /  0x31dd  : Your lamp is off
0xa  /  0x31e8  : 

The water extinguishes your lamp
0xb  /  0x31fc  : You have:


0xc  /  0x3203  : Nothing
0xd  /  0x3209  : "Do that again and you'll regret it!", snarls the djinn
0xe  /  0x322c  : The djinn appears: 

0xf  /  0x323a  : The djinn blocks your way. 

0x10  /  0x324b  : 

A pack of wolves emerges from the trees!
0x11  /  0x3263  : 

A pack of wolves is stalking you
0x12  /  0x3276  : 

The wolves attack..
0x13  /  0x3282  : 

The wolves are startled and run off
0x14  /  0x3296  : Tree branches bend to block the path
0x15  /  0x32ab  : The unicorn snorts disdainfully
0x16  /  0x32bf  : The unicorn takes the orchid, nods and walks off north. He gestures for you to follow
0x17  /  0x32ef  : 

They retreat slightly and then lunge forward again
0x18  /  0x3310  : 

A robed wizard is standing waiting. She hands you a scroll, smiles and fades away
0x19  /  0x333f  : "Take the Talisman to the Black Tower through the four elements twice. It can defeat the Demon Lord, but only a companion can bring victory at the end. The Talisman is nearby, but you will also need 4 Stones to gain entry and these are guarded by servants of the Enemy. You are the only hope for Middle Earth - the High Council lied when they pretended otherwise. The blesssing of Typo, god of Adventures, goes with you. Good Luck!"
0x1a  /  0x3434  : 
0x1b  /  0x3435  : 

Oh dear! You got yourself killed
0x1c  /  0x3449  : 

FOOL! You got killed again!
0x1d  /  0x345b  : 

This is becoming a habit!
0x1e  /  0x346b  : 

Do you want to be resurrected?


0x1f  /  0x3482  : Sorry, I've run out of orange smoke..
0x20  /  0x349b  : 

There is a puff of orange smoke..
0x21  /  0x34b0  : 

Do you really want to stop?


0x22  /  0x34c2  : 

Do you want to try again?


0x23  /  0x34d5  : 

Please answer YES or NO


0x24  /  0x34e6  : Your hands are full
0x25  /  0x34f2  : That was just what you needed
0x26  /  0x3505  : it is full of water
0x27  /  0x350e  : it is full of oil
0x28  /  0x3518  : The liquid soaks into the ground
0x29  /  0x3529  : You're carrying too much to climb up
0x2a  /  0x3542  : The orchid is two foot above your reach
0x2b  /  0x3558  : 

You are standing on the table
0x2c  /  0x3566  : The pipes play oriental music
0x2d  /  0x3579  : You sever the rope bridge, preventing pursuit
0x2e  /  0x3593  : 

A rope bridge spans the chasm from east to west
0x2f  /  0x35ae  : 

The stick grows incredibly as it hits the ground. Buds form, leaves burst from them and drink in the light, and then the stick is a mass of flowers! Fruit quickly swells and falls onto the ground and the leaves are shed. It is just a stick again
0x30  /  0x362a  : The 'onion' tastes very odd: it is garlic! However as you are obviously ravenous (why else would anyone want to eat an entire onion) you gulp it down. Then you notice movement nearby and turn 
in fascination: all the vegetation down-wind has curled up
0x31  /  0x36c2  : 

It is dark, you cannot see
0x32  /  0x36d2  : 

You are underwater
0x33  /  0x36dd  : 


0x34  /  0x36df  : 

You are 

0x35  /  0x36e5  : You swing the silver ball around in the sling and release it. 

0x36  /  0x3703  : You have no sling stone
0x37  /  0x3711  : There is nothing here worth opening
0x38  /  0x3726  : You have no keys (or crowbar)
0x39  /  0x373a  : The Talisman shines with a clear blue light and 
you seem to hear triumphal music
0x3a  /  0x376c  : , all the orcs about you shrink back
0x3b  /  0x3780  : , the Demon Lord shrieks and flees through an opening behind His throne
0x3c  /  0x37a4  : You cannot move in that direction
0x3d  /  0x37b8  : It tastes delightful
0x3e  /  0x37c5  : 

The orcs fall upon you with cries of triumph
0x3f  /  0x37df  : The giant picks you up in one hand and carries you off for lunch
0x40  /  0x3808  : 

The giant dodges and runs off: "Stay there, I'm just off to fetch my helmet", he booms
0x41  /  0x3840  : .


0x42  /  0x3843  : The snowman is free and leaps about joyfully
0x43  /  0x385c  : You aren't strong enough to move the rocks
0x44  /  0x3872  :  but with the snowman's help they move! The orcs in the tower flee as the giant stones bounce towards them followed by the abominable snowman. Eventually the dust settles: the mountain seems to be deserted
0x45  /  0x38db  : 

A fearsome dark shape flies at you: claws and tentacles flail the air!
0x46  /  0x3908  : The shape engulfs you..
0x47  /  0x3918  : 

A gigantic worm rises from the sand, swallowing all in its path!
0x48  /  0x393e  : 

A rushing noise is nearly upon you!
0x49  /  0x3954  : 

Sand is sliding nearby
0x4a  /  0x3962  : 

You can hear sand sliding softly in the distance
0x4b  /  0x397c  :  Including you!
0x4c  /  0x3987  : A cavern opens to the north
0x4d  /  0x3994  : 

You are very thirsty
0x4e  /  0x39a0  : 

You are very thirsty and will die without water
0x4f  /  0x39ba  : You must be joking! That sphinx looks dangerous!
0x50  /  0x39da  : The snakes rear up, spitting venom, and block your way to the temple
0x51  /  0x39fd  :  and the snakes dance away into holes
0x52  /  0x3a13  : 

It lands with a splash in the distance
0x53  /  0x3a28  : 
0x54  /  0x3a29  : A blast of air roars from the bag
0x55  /  0x3a3d  : : blowing the djinn towards a nearby lamp
0x56  /  0x3a54  : The ruby ball explodes, surrounding you with a ball of searing flame!
0x57  /  0x3a79  : The ruby explodes as it lands, destroying everything nearby in a ball of fire
0x58  /  0x3aa3  : The priestess gives you a small ruby in exchange for the sun-dial. She vanishes, mouthing "Be careful!"
0x59  /  0x3ade  : A priestess greets you: "I can help your quest if you return my sun-dial", she says, "It was stolen and hidden in a cave near the oasis. Without it I am powerless and dare not leave the temple!"
0x5a  /  0x3b53  : 

Water bubbles from the ground!


0x5b  /  0x3b66  : 

Your blows bounce off its thick skin
0x5c  /  0x3b7e  : 

"Right, you asked for it!", he shouts, gesticulating crudely..
0x5d  /  0x3baa  : The Djinn is furious!
0x5e  /  0x3bb7  : 

The ruby vanishes in a hissing cloud of steam


0x5f  /  0x3bcf  : 

You cannot breath!
0x60  /  0x3bd9  : 

You can breath again!
0x61  /  0x3be6  : 

You are swept over the rapids 

0x62  /  0x3bf7  : and held under for a long time..
0x63  /  0x3c0e  : 

A shark circles round, eying you
0x64  /  0x3c1f  : 

The shark attacks!
0x65  /  0x3c2a  : 

But the trident protects you!
0x66  /  0x3c3f  : The clam opens, belches out a cloud of decaying 
filth in your direction, and then snaps tight shut again. Its shell contains nothing but clam.
0x67  /  0x3c93  : The jelly floats just out of reach
0x68  /  0x3ca2  : You catch the luminous jelly with the net
0x69  /  0x3cb7  : A huge octopus leaps out and bites at your treasure. 

0x6a  /  0x3cd7  : It starts on the wind-bag, inflates like a balloon and whizzes off!
0x6b  /  0x3d00  : Then it reaches for you..
0x6c  /  0x3d0f  : 

The luminous jelly shrivels to nothing as it dries
0x6d  /  0x3d2b  : The current sucks it down a hole!
0x6e  /  0x3d3d  : 

There is a sensation of rapid movement..
0x6f  /  0x3d55  : "ARMED INTRUDER! ARMED INTRUDER! ARMED INTRUDER! ARMED INTRUDER! ARMED INTRUDER! ARMED INTRUDER!" yells a gargoyle overhead. The door slams
0x70  /  0x3d7e  : 

An arrow lands nearby
0x71  /  0x3d8d  : 

An arrow is fired. It gets you! A cry of triumph echoes round the hall "A head for Melkor!"
0x72  /  0x3dc1  : 

An orc archer is crouched, peering down into the gloom. When he sees you he jumps up and runs north to his kin standing there
0x73  /  0x3e01  : The status nods in thanks and gives you its rune-encrusted sword. It uses the eye to look around for a while and then hides it in one marble fist
0x74  /  0x3e52  : An enormous spider leaps out as you reach for the stone! 

0x75  /  0x3e72  : You are defenceless! It bites you..
0x76  /  0x3e86  : You fight it off with your sword but the Earth-Stone is lost! Far below, an orc snatches a small object and runs away south-west
0x77  /  0x3ec8  : As you cross the bridge the alarm is raised! A host of orcs rush onto the bridge after you
0x78  /  0x3ef9  : The dragon's fire drives you back. It grins happily and settles itself, watching you carefully
0x79  /  0x3f31  : The dragon stretches and swallows it in one gulp!
0x7a  /  0x3f4d  :  A belch of steam explodes from the dragon's mouth. It hiccoughs and backs away, coughing smoke
0x7b  /  0x3f87  : 

north-east
0x7c  /  0x3f8d  : 

north-west
0x7d  /  0x3f91  : 

west
0x7e  /  0x3f96  : 

south-west
0x7f  /  0x3f9b  : 

south-east
0x80  /  0x3fa2  : 

east
0x81  /  0x3fa6  : 
0x82  /  0x3fa7  : 

A blast of fire licks you into the crater..
0x83  /  0x3fbe  : 

They all miss!
0x84  /  0x3fca  : 

A living flame leaps at you from the wall!
0x85  /  0x3fe1  : 

A sheet of living flame is attacking you
0x86  /  0x3ff6  :  but the insulation cloak protects you
0x87  /  0x400e  : The flame vanishes into the sword! A hundred voices seem to shout in disappointment from the walls of Hell Well
0x88  /  0x404d  : 
0x89  /  0x404e  : You must be joking! Those coals are red-hot!
0x8a  /  0x406c  : 

Fortunately your feet are protected
0x8b  /  0x4085  : The cloak covers the coals, shutting off their heat
0x8c  /  0x40a4  : But you're standing on it!
0x8d  /  0x40b3  : The egg falls into the nest which burns brighter, throwing up a pillar of sparks which rises to 
the ceiling. Then a shape seems to come together within the flames, getting ever clearer. A proud bird flies from the now-fading fire: the PHOENIX is born again!
0x8e  /  0x4142  : The stately phoenix perches nearby, watching you
0x8f  /  0x415e  : A BALROG stands astride the bridge, holding its 
whip of flames. You are trapped!
0x90  /  0x418e  : 

The Balrog's fire-whip strikes out..
0x91  /  0x41a5  :  It gets you!
0x92  /  0x41ae  :  It misses!
0x93  /  0x41b6  : Your blows pass through it with no effect!
0x94  /  0x41d1  : You smite the bridge assunder and the Balrog plummets into the chasm. But its whip catches you even as it falls and you are dragged down
0x95  /  0x421d  : You fall into the abyss
0x96  /  0x4228  : 

You fall for hours, it seems, but then a thick 
mist gently slows your speed..


0x97  /  0x4257  : You should only attack enemies
0x98  /  0x4268  : 

A puny effort!
0x99  /  0x4275  : 

Not bad.. for a beginner
0x9a  /  0x4287  : 

You are hereby admitted to the ranks of Adventuredom as an "Adventurer"
0x9b  /  0x42b3  : 

You are clearly a Master Adventurer!
0x9c  /  0x42c9  : 

All Middle-Earth hails thee: "Grandmaster Adventurer!". Congratulations, you are one of the elite who have cracked this game.
0x9d  /  0x431a  : 
0x9e  /  0x431b  : 

You are severely chilled and must have warmth
0x9f  /  0x4335  : 

Without heat you will die of exposure


0xa0  /  0x434f  : 

The orcs are closing in
0xa1  /  0x435a  : 

The food warms you a little
0xa2  /  0x436a  : 

You die of thirst!
0xa3  /  0x4375  : 

The brazier warms you instantly!
0xa4  /  0x4388  : The brazier shrinks into a tiny ornament
0xa5  /  0x43a0  : The brazier expands, giving out a welcome warmth
0xa6  /  0x43bd  : You slide down a scree slope. The orcs daren't follow..
0xa7  /  0x43de  : 
0xa8  /  0x43df  : A reflected face in the marsh looks back. Your gaze is locked!
0xa9  /  0x4406  : You cannot escape the hypnotic link
0xaa  /  0x441b  : 

You take a step towards the face..
0xab  /  0x442f  : 

Ripples disrupt the reflection. You are free!
0xac  /  0x444e  : 

The quicksand sucks you down!
0xad  /  0x4460  : 

You stumble into the marsh. 

0xae  /  0x446d  : 

A skeletal hand is gripping your leg and dragging you into the marsh!
0xaf  /  0x4491  : You sever the hand which falls back into the marsh
0xb0  /  0x44a7  : You cannot move!
0xb1  /  0x44af  : 

You are surrounded by cold shadowy ghosts which are feeding from your very life energy
0xb2  /  0x44db  : 

The blast of heat banishes the shadows
0xb3  /  0x44f0  : 
0xb4  /  0x44f1  : The bell rings and the door creaks open. A gravelly voice croaks from the darkness: 'Enter.. The master awaits..'
0xb5  /  0x4531  : 

A cloaked figure stands at the back of the hall. It walks slowly forwards and then springs! 

0xb6  /  0x4564  : 'Ugh! Garlic! I'm leaving!' The vampire flees
0xb7  /  0x4585  : "I'm so glad that someone has finally dropped in for a bite. Just tilt your head to one side..."
0xb8  /  0x45c4  : As you insert the stone the alarms sound. It's the wrong one! The corridoor fills with gas..
0xb9  /  0x45f5  : The door swings open
0xba  /  0x45ff  : You stand before the throne where the Demon Lord sits laughing. You cannot move!
0xbb  /  0x4627  : 

"Come in!", sneers an evil voice, "I have watched your pitiful efforts against MY servants. Surely you did not expect to defeat ME!!". Dozens of orcs surround you and herd you north


0xbc  /  0x469f  : 

The Demon shrieks in terror, struggles through 
the skins lining the north wall and is gone
0xbd  /  0x46cd  : You hear pursuit close behind
0xbe  /  0x46dd  : The orcs run past and the sound of pursuit dies 
away
0xbf  /  0x46f9  : The Demon Lord freezes you with a look: "You will still fail!", he snarls, "No amulet can work so close to the centre of my power." 

0xc0  /  0x4745  : 
0xc1  /  0x4746  : 
0xc2  /  0x4747  : 

But the PHOENIX dives at the fire, destroying it completely! The Demon Lord screams and implodes to nothing: your mission is successful!!

 


0xc3  /  0x479a  : You scored 

0xc4  /  0x47a1  :  
out of about 6000.


0xc5  /  0x47af  : A giant sits in the middle of the path, blocking it. He is picking at the bones of some unfortunate creature
0xc6  /  0x47e6  : You sever the bridge which falls away into the cavern, preventing any pursuit
0xc7  /  0x480f  : 

Fires leap from the crater to the:
0xc8  /  0x4822  : Nothing happens
0xc9  /  0x482d  : 

A unicorn stands in the clearing
0xca  /  0x483f  : 

A sphinx guards the pyramid
0xcb  /  0x4851  : 

Poisonous snakes cover the pyramid
0xcc  /  0x4866  : 

A stone slab blocks the way north
0xcd  /  0x4877  : You can't get near to it
0xce  /  0x4885  : 

A Djinn stands before you, guarding the oasis to the south
0xcf  /  0x48a2  : 

The tower is surrounded by orcs
0xd0  /  0x48ac  : 

The snowman is chained to the mountain
0xd1  /  0x48bd  : 

There is a small stalagmite near the edge
0xd2  /  0x48d2  : 

A pile of giant rocks lies beside the steps
0xd3  /  0x48ea  : 

A rock bridge spans the chasm
0xd4  /  0x48fa  : 

A dragon fills the cave!
0xd5  /  0x4908  : 

Orcs block the way north
0xd6  /  0x4915  : 

A rope hangs down into the darkness below
0xd7  /  0x492a  : You have nothing to drink
0xd8  /  0x4939  : There is no suitable liquid within reach
0xd9  /  0x4952  : 

The door is rusted solid
0xda  /  0x495d  : 

The door is locked
0xdb  /  0x4964  : You oil the door and think that it might open now
0xdc  /  0x497e  :  

0xdd  /  0x4980  : The Earth-Stone
0xde  /  0x4987  : The Mist-Stone
0xdf  /  0x498e  : The Star-Stone
0xe0  /  0x4995  : The Sun-Stone
0xe1  /  0x499c  : The Medallion of Good
0xe2  /  0x49a7  : a pair of water-proof boots
0xe3  /  0x49b8  : a bottle: 

0xe4  /  0x49c1  : a tiny brazier
0xe5  /  0x49cb  : a bunch of keys
0xe6  /  0x49d6  : an insulation cloak
0xe7  /  0x49e2  : a crystal compass enscribed 'this game Copyright (C) 1983 Level 9 Computing'. Unauthorised copying or loan is prohibited.
0xe8  /  0x4a36  : a bird's egg
0xe9  /  0x4a3f  : an emerald eye
0xea  /  0x4a47  : a ruby
0xeb  /  0x4a4c  : a lung-fish token
0xec  /  0x4a59  : some fruit
0xed  /  0x4a60  : a luminous jelly-fish
0xee  /  0x4a6f  : a little lamp
0xef  /  0x4a78  : a fishing net
0xf0  /  0x4a80  : an onion
0xf1  /  0x4a85  : a rare orchid
0xf2  /  0x4a8e  : a set of pan pipes
0xf3  /  0x4a99  : a crooked stick
0xf4  /  0x4aa3  : a coil of rope
0xf5  /  0x4aad  : a scroll
0xf6  /  0x4ab3  : a small silver ball
0xf7  /  0x4abc  : a sling
0xf8  /  0x4ac2  : an abominable snowman, following you
0xf9  /  0x4ad5  : The Sacred Sun-Dial
0xfa  /  0x4ae3  : a richly-worked sword
0xfb  /  0x4af1  : a kitchen table
0xfc  /  0x4afb  : a three-pronged trident
0xfd  /  0x4b0b  : an inflated leather bag
0xfe  /  0x4b18  : 
0xff  /  0x4b19  : 
0x100  /  0x4b1a  : 
0x101  /  0x4b1b  : 
0x102  /  0x4b1c  : 
0x103  /  0x4b1d  : 
0x104  /  0x4b1e  : An insulating cloak lies nearby
0x105  /  0x4b32  : The Earth-stone is here!
0x106  /  0x4b40  : The Mist-Stone is here!
0x107  /  0x4b4c  : The Star-Stone is here!
0x108  /  0x4b58  : The Sun-Stone is here!
0x109  /  0x4b64  : An ancient medallion lies on the ground
0x10a  /  0x4b77  : A pair of boots lies nearby
0x10b  /  0x4b89  : A bottle lies nearby: 

0x10c  /  0x4b99  : A cool brazier sits, glowing like a commercial
0x10d  /  0x4bb5  : A bunch of keys is here
0x10e  /  0x4bc4  : A cloak of insulation material lies nearby
0x10f  /  0x4bdd  : 
0x110  /  0x4bde  : There is a bird's egg here
0x111  /  0x4bed  : An emerald eye is here
0x112  /  0x4bfa  : A ruby is here
0x113  /  0x4c03  : A model of a lung-fish lies on the ground
0x114  /  0x4c19  : Some fruit is lying here
0x115  /  0x4c27  : A luminous jelly-fish floats overhead
0x116  /  0x4c3f  : An oriental lamp is here
0x117  /  0x4c4f  : There is a fishing net here
0x118  /  0x4c5e  : An onion rolls on the ground
0x119  /  0x4c6b  : There is a rare orchid here
0x11a  /  0x4c7a  : Pan pipes lie on the ground
0x11b  /  0x4c87  : A stick lies on the ground
0x11c  /  0x4c93  : There is a coil of rope here
0x11d  /  0x4ca3  : A scroll is here
0x11e  /  0x4cad  : A silver ball is here
0x11f  /  0x4cb9  : A small sling is here
0x120  /  0x4cc3  : An abominable snowman lurks nearby
0x121  /  0x4cd8  : The Sacred Sun-Dial is here!
0x122  /  0x4ceb  : A fine sword is here
0x123  /  0x4cf7  : A small table is here
0x124  /  0x4d01  : A trident is here
0x125  /  0x4d0c  : A small leather bag lies here, moving slightly as if it held a live creature
0x126  /  0x4d35  : 
0x127  /  0x4d36  : 
0x128  /  0x4d37  : 
0x129  /  0x4d38  : 
0x12a  /  0x4d39  : 
0x12b  /  0x4d3a  : 
0x12c  /  0x4d3b  : 
0x12d  /  0x4d3c  : lost in the forest
0x12e  /  0x4d44  : lost in the forest
0x12f  /  0x4d4c  : lost in the forest
0x130  /  0x4d54  : lost in the forest
0x131  /  0x4d5c  : lost in the forest beside a huge oak tree with branches resting on the ground
0x132  /  0x4d81  : in dense forest, surrounded by clinging plants and small biting insects
0x133  /  0x4da1  : at the end of a road from the north, outside a small brick building. A river flows south through a narrow valley and there is dense woodland all around
0x134  /  0x4dea  : in a narrow north-south valley through the forest. A small stream, clogged by dead vegetation, seeps sluggishly south. A miasma of decay pervades the scene
0x135  /  0x4e3a  : in a north-south valley. A small steam flows from the north and seeps away into the swampy ground
0x136  /  0x4e65  : in a 20 foot deep depression in the floor of a steep valley. The remains of an iron grate can just be made out, set into the ground, but it is blocked by concrete and has almost rusted away
0x137  /  0x4ec3  : stumbling over sharp stones in a steeply sloping gulley
0x138  /  0x4ee0  : at the top of a high cliff which slices across the land. Far below you are the southern lowlands: once a prosperous farming area but now devastated by drought, plague and war. A few animals roam the dry fields
0x139  /  0x4f54  : on the steep east side of a valley, overgrown with brambles and stinging plants
0x13a  /  0x4f7c  : at the base of a stone pinnacle which rises from the gloom of the trees into the sunlight above. A narrow path spirals round it, climbing upwards
0x13b  /  0x4fc7  : on a road north of the building. All around is desolate scrub-land where sparse weeds strive for life in the poisoned ground
0x13c  /  0x500a  : at the edge of the 'fertile' land. Nothing grows in the desert which stretches north as far as the eye can see. Heat haze blurs your vision, but you can just make out the shape of a high mountain within it
0x13d  /  0x5077  : sitting on a gnarled tree-branch which is half-split from its parent trunk and resting on the ground
0x13e  /  0x50ad  : in the building. Steps lead down a well in the centre of the floor. A white dot is marked over the door
0x13f  /  0x50de  : in the well. A message on the wall says "Congratulations on bringing light to the dark well! Give yourself a 1000 point bonus for being lucky!!"
0x140  /  0x5132  : in a small woodland clearing carpetted with buttercups and sweet grasses
0x141  /  0x5159  : in a grove of tall trees, relics of the original "Great Forest" which covered this area before the coming of the Desolation
0x142  /  0x5199  : on a path through dense forest
0x143  /  0x51a8  : in woodland above the valley. A path leads north into dense forest
0x144  /  0x51c9  : on a path winding round the rock pinnacle
0x145  /  0x51dc  : at the top of a stone pinnacle high above the forest. A steep escarpment falls away to the south, leading down to once-fertile lowlands. A forest of tangled trees smothers the higher land around you and to the north is baked desert. A mountain rises above the sands, and you can just make out a stone tower on its slopes
0x146  /  0x527b  : on trackless desert
0x147  /  0x527f  : on trackless desert
0x148  /  0x5283  : on trackless desert
0x149  /  0x5287  : on trackless desert
0x14a  /  0x528b  : on trackless desert
0x14b  /  0x528f  : on trackless desert
0x14c  /  0x5293  : on trackless desert beside a black pillar. The pillar is round, and perfectly smooth but for a single white dot half-way up
0x14d  /  0x52cf  : on trackless desert above a deep canyon. A small oasis sits in the bottom of the canyon, nestling at the foot of the southern cliffs below
0x14e  /  0x5308  : on trackless desert south of a canyon
0x14f  /  0x5313  : on trackless desert south of a canyon. A large flat-topped pyramid with steps on all sides rises from the desert, and to the east an outcrop ofpolished rock resists the shifting sands
0x150  /  0x536b  : inside a small temple to the sun god on the pyramid. It is surrounded by stone pillars and has a large central altar, but is roofless of course
0x151  /  0x53ae  : on top of the pyramid outside a small temple
0x152  /  0x53c2  : on a rocky outcrop overlooking the desert and the pyramid. A path leads down to the north into a chasm between the outcrop and its parent mountain
0x153  /  0x5409  : at the southern edge of a vast desert, baked by 
the burning sun. Great lines of dunes seem to march north
0x154  /  0x543e  : beside giant rocks which block the valley
0x155  /  0x5453  : in a dry east-west canyon with sheer rocky walls
0x156  /  0x546b  : in a dry canyon. Cliffs tower overhead and you can see an oasis to the south
0x157  /  0x548f  : on the side of a mountain rising from the desert
0x158  /  0x54a4  : in a sheltered wadi. Oil seeps from the rocks
0x159  /  0x54bb  : where the wadi ends at a mountain. You could climb up
0x15a  /  0x54db  : at the north edge of an oasis
0x15b  /  0x54e8  : in an oasis beside a deep pool of cool water
0x15c  /  0x54ff  : swimming in a clear desert pool
0x15d  /  0x5510  : in a looted treasure cave. It has been cleaned out completely and on one wall is written "Ali wuz here"!
0x15e  /  0x5548  : in a sheltered east-west valley, protected from 
the burning sun by high rocky walls
0x15f  /  0x5573  : on a stone staircase zig-zagging up the mountain
0x160  /  0x558e  : on a stone staircase up the mountain
0x161  /  0x55a0  : on the stone staircase some distance below a stone tower. A body hangs from a gallows and a notice reads "KEEP AWAY OR YOU WILL DIE"
0x162  /  0x55f5  : on an east-west track round the mountain
0x163  /  0x5606  : on a climbing path up the mountain
0x164  /  0x5617  : on a track up the mountain
0x165  /  0x5624  : on a sheep-track leading upwards
0x166  /  0x5635  : on a sheep-track looping back round the mountain
0x167  /  0x564c  : on stone steps some way above a stone tower. A narrow path joins the stairway from the west
0x168  /  0x567d  : on steps leading upwards
0x169  /  0x5689  : on a bleak rocky mountainside buffetted by cruel winds which whistle round the peak. A wide stone staircase leads down to the lower slopes
0x16a  /  0x56ce  : on a steep path through sparse vegetation hung with tatters of bleached lichin
0x16b  /  0x56f5  : standing on a snowfield outside a small dark mountain cave
0x16c  /  0x5710  : in a smelly cave: the sound of running water reverberates from the walls. A white dot is marked 
on the roof, and at the back of the cave is a sheer drop down into darkness
0x16d  /  0x5763  : outside the south door of a stone tower which stands astride the stairway
0x16e  /  0x5785  : outside the north door of the tower
0x16f  /  0x5793  : in the south tower room. A spiral staircase leads upwards and there are doors to south and east
0x170  /  0x57c1  : in the north tower room. Doors lead north and south
0x171  /  0x57d9  : in a small room used by the orc guards
0x172  /  0x57eb  : on a tight spiral staircase up the inside of the tower
0x173  /  0x5804  : on a spiral staircase half-way up the tower
0x174  /  0x581b  : outside a small door. A foul smell seeps from behind it
0x175  /  0x5838  : in a small gloomy room with an alcove in the north wall
0x176  /  0x5850  : in a tiny alcove at the back of a squalid room
0x177  /  0x5868  : on a wide stone staircase climbing up the mountain. A narrow uneven path joins it from the westand leads round the mountain
0x178  /  0x58a6  : on a ledge. It collapses, hurling you into a fast-flowing underground river! You are swept along helplessly
0x179  /  0x58e5  : in a raging torrent
0x17a  /  0x58ef  : buffeted by the swift current
0x17b  /  0x5902  : swept round a bend in the river
0x17c  /  0x5914  : in a series of rapids
0x17d  /  0x591f  : on the brink of a stretch of rapids
0x17e  /  0x5932  : tossed around by the rapids
0x17f  /  0x5942  : in a quiet pool below the rapids and near a gravel beach
0x180  /  0x5962  : on a featureless lake-bed
0x181  /  0x5971  : on the lake-bed. A huge clam is firmly rooted to the rocks
0x182  /  0x5991  : on the lake bed
0x183  /  0x5999  : on the lake bed
0x184  /  0x59a1  : on the lake bed above a deep dark trench
0x185  /  0x59b8  : on the lake bed above a deep dark trench
0x186  /  0x59cf  : safe in a thick mass of water weed
0x187  /  0x59e3  : in a drowned grave yard, outside a church. A ringing sound can be heard
0x188  /  0x5a08  : inside the drowned church. A slow ringing can be heard from the west, behind the pulpit
0x189  /  0x5a35  : inside the belfry, below a tolling bell
0x18a  /  0x5a48  : at the west end of an underwater trench. A swift current flows away through a small gap in the rocks
0x18b  /  0x5a7a  : at the east end of an underwater trench, outside a small cave. You think that there may be movement in the cave
0x18c  /  0x5ab0  : in shallow water at the edge of the lake
0x18d  /  0x5ac2  : inside an octopus lair. The water is warm and there is a white dot on the wall
0x18e  /  0x5ae5  : on a small gravel beach to the south of a lake in a volcanic crater. You can see a door on the opposite shore, almost hidden in deep shadows
0x18f  /  0x5b29  : on a ledge along the side of a deep chasm, above a swift river
0x190  /  0x5b48  : on a ledge above a series of rapids
0x191  /  0x5b5b  : south of a huge door on the north shore of the crater lake. A host of carved stone heads glare at you from above the door, seeming to follow your every move. To the east is a second, smaller entrance, marked with a black dot
0x192  /  0x5bcc  : at the south of a magnificent cave with holes all around. A huge door stands open behind you
0x193  /  0x5bfc  : at a dead end
0x194  /  0x5c05  : in the centre of a magnificent cave. A web-covered stalagmite reaches upwards towards the sculpted roof
0x195  /  0x5c40  : clinging to a web-covered stalagmite. The cavern floor is far below
0x196  /  0x5c66  : in the middle of a huge web at the top of the stalagmite. A thick web walkway continues upwards
0x197  /  0x5c9b  : in the lair of a giant spider, surrounded by a maze of web strands
0x198  /  0x5cb9  : at a dead end decorated with ornate carvings cut into the rock
0x199  /  0x5cdb  : at the north of a magnificent cave with holes all around
0x19a  /  0x5cfa  : in a small dead-end room. An ancient statue of a warrior elf stands in the centre. One of his eyes is covered by a jewelled patch - the other is missing
0x19b  /  0x5d47  : in an east-west passage decorated with carvings
0x19c  /  0x5d61  : in a sloping corridoor warmed by rising hot air
0x19d  /  0x5d78  : at a dead end
0x19e  /  0x5d81  : in a steeply-sloping east-west passage which winds upwards through the rock
0x19f  /  0x5da7  : at a junction between north-south and east-west 
passages
0x1a0  /  0x5dc5  : on a ledge clinging to the west wall of a huge cavern. The cavern floor is just visible, far below
0x1a1  /  0x5df7  : on a ledge which clings to the west wall of a large cavern
0x1a2  /  0x5e16  : trapped at a dead end
0x1a3  /  0x5e24  : at the entrance to an orc lair. Crude passages are hacked to east and south and an opening looks out over the east side of an immense cavern. The lair is unguarded
0x1a4  /  0x5e75  : in a smelly store-room
0x1a5  /  0x5e80  : in a feast-hall full of celebrating orcs. You'll have to guess what they are feasting upon
0x1a6  /  0x5eb5  : in a jagged north-south passage. The roof is supported by rotting tree-trunks. The noise of a celebration comes from an opening to the east
0x1a7  /  0x5efd  : at the end of the passage: it is blocked by a cave-in. A narrow opening leads west
0x1a8  /  0x5f25  : in a tiny store-room
0x1a9  /  0x5f2f  : in a mass of giant rocks
0x1aa  /  0x5f3c  : in a sloping corridoor lit from the west by a weird flickering light. The floor and walls feel warm to the touch
0x1ab  /  0x5f76  : in a round smooth cave with several exits
0x1ac  /  0x5f8f  : in the dragon's lair. The floor is covered in gold coins but, sadly for you, the dragon's breath has fused them solid. "Why don't all dragons do this", you wonder
0x1ad  /  0x5feb  : in a cave overlooking a huge volcanic crater
0x1ae  /  0x6000  : on a ledge over the crater. A path spirals anticlockwise to a cave far below
0x1af  /  0x6025  : on a ledge north-east of the crater
0x1b0  /  0x6031  : on a ledge north-west of the crater
0x1b1  /  0x603c  : on a ledge west of the crater, opposite two caves on the far side. The path slopes up towards one cave and down to the other
0x1b2  /  0x6078  : on a ledge south-west of the crater
0x1b3  /  0x6084  : on a ledge south-east of the crater
0x1b4  /  0x6091  : on a ledge east of the volcanic crater, beside a cave entrance. The heat from the bubbling lava 
just below is immense. A path slopes up clockwise to another cave high above
0x1b5  /  0x60e8  : in a cave opening onto a volcanic crater. A huge hole almost fills the cave floor and a ramp spirals down into it. Warning runes are carved at the top of the ramp
0x1b6  /  0x6135  : on a spiral ramp at the top of Hell-well. The walls of the well are inset with small niches containing small flickering lights
0x1b7  /  0x6169  : on a spiral ramp half way up Hell-well. The walls are inset with small niches containing trapped flames
0x1b8  /  0x619a  : on a spiral ramp near the bottom of Hell-well. The walls of the well are inset with small niches holding tiny flames
0x1b9  /  0x61cd  : standing on shattered rocks at the bottom of Hell-well. A broken door leads west
0x1ba  /  0x61ed  : at a crossing between passages. The floor is made up of red-hot coals
0x1bb  /  0x6214  : in a hot room. The north door is marked with a black dot
0x1bc  /  0x622e  : in an ornate room decorated with symbols of infinity. A nest burns on a marble plinth in the centre of the room: yet it is not consumed, and neither does it give off any smoke or heat
0x1bd  /  0x6294  : in a hot east-west corridor. To the east is a bed of glowing coals
0x1be  /  0x62b2  : standing by the alter
0x1bf  /  0x62bb  : on the east side of a bottomless chasm
0x1c0  /  0x62ce  : on a narrow stone bridge poised over the chasm
0x1c1  /  0x62e4  : on the west of the chasm. Steps lead up to an altar above you
0x1c2  /  0x6303  : iQ a very hot passage. The floor is covered by hot coals to the west
0x1c3  /  0x6327  : on a bleak moor
0x1c4  /  0x632c  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists. A black tower rises above the fog to the south
0x1c5  /  0x6349  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists. A black tower rises from the fog to the south
0x1c6  /  0x6367  : on a bleak moor
0x1c7  /  0x636c  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists. A black tower rises from the fog to the south
0x1c8  /  0x638a  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists
0x1c9  /  0x6397  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists
0x1ca  /  0x63a4  : on a bleak moor
0x1cb  /  0x63a9  : on a bleak moor
0x1cc  /  0x63ae  : on a bleak moor overlooking a deep ravine
0x1cd  /  0x63c1  : on a bleak moor between mists and a deep ravine
0x1ce  /  0x63d9  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists
0x1cf  /  0x63e6  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists
0x1d0  /  0x63f3  : on a bleak moor south of a barrow-topped hill
0x1d1  /  0x6407  : on a hill-top outside a long barrow. The lintel 
over the door of the barrow is marked with a black dot. The hill is surrounded on three sides by sheer cliffs and from the other orcs are closing in
0x1d2  /  0x6464  : on a tiny ledge clinging to a steep cliff
0x1d3  /  0x647a  : on a bleak moor above a deep ravine
0x1d4  /  0x6488  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists
0x1d5  /  0x6495  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists. A black tower rises through the fog to the south
0x1d6  /  0x64b3  : on a bleak moor
0x1d7  /  0x64b8  : on a bleak moor above a deep ravine
0x1d8  /  0x64c6  : on a bleak moor above swirling mists. A black tower rises above the fog to the south
0x1d9  /  0x64e3  : on a bleak moor. A path leads down into a ravine
0x1da  /  0x64f7  : on a steep path in a deep ravine. A black tower 
rises above the fog to the south
0x1db  /  0x651b  : on a bleak moor
0x1dc  /  0x6520  : on a north-south path winding through a dank marsh. Bubbles of gas pop round you
0x1dd  /  0x654b  : surrounded by a circle of thirteen standing stones on a small hill in the marsh. There is a dead silence
0x1de  /  0x6571  : lost in the marsh! There is no visible path
0x1df  /  0x6587  : on a narrow east-west path between pools of stinking water
0x1e0  /  0x65a3  : lost in the marsh. A light beckons in the east
0x1e1  /  0x65b6  : lost in the marsh
0x1e2  /  0x65bb  : in deadly quicksand
0x1e3  /  0x65c9  : lost in the marsh. A light flickers from the east
0x1e4  /  0x65df  : deep in the marsh. You can see a lantern in the 
east
0x1e5  /  0x65f6  : deep in the marsh with no way out. Every way you look seems blocked by areas of quicksand. A Will o'Wisp dances overhead in triumph
0x1e6  /  0x6646  : on a north-south path through the marsh
0x1e7  /  0x6653  : on a path deep in the marsh
0x1e8  /  0x665d  : lost in the marsh
0x1e9  /  0x6662  : on an east-west causeway through the marsh
0x1ea  /  0x6672  : in deadly quicksand
0x1eb  /  0x6680  : on an island outside the door of an ancient house. Lightning flashes, illuminating bats flying overhead, and gusts of wind rattle the flapping shutters
0x1ec  /  0x66d0  : in a ancient panelled entrance hall of a decaying house. Rats scurry behind the walls. There are doors to north and south
0x1ed  /  0x6710  : in the main hall. Steps lead upwards
0x1ee  /  0x6723  : in a high room. A window looks out onto the marsh to the south, and you catch a glimpse of a huge black tower nearby
0x1ef  /  0x675c  : on a small ledge south of a small door marked with a black dot. There is a window in the wall above
0x1f0  /  0x6786  : on a dark granite ramp at the foot of the BLACK 
TOWER
0x1f1  /  0x67a4  : on slippery steps behind falling mists
0x1f2  /  0x67b9  : on steps behind a waterfall. Water drips from every stone
0x1f3  /  0x67d9  : on steps leading behind a waterfall. A dark tower shows to the south, briefly
0x1f4  /  0x67fb  : at the foot of a flight of steps leading upwards through the mist
0x1f5  /  0x6818  : below the Door of Rock. A small opening in the door is just large enough to take one of the Stones
0x1f6  /  0x6841  : below the Door of Gold. A small opening in the door is just large enough to take one of the Stones
0x1f7  /  0x686b  : below the Door of Silver. A small opening is just large enough to take one of the Stones
0x1f8  /  0x6892  : below the Door of Glass. You can see nothing behind the door. An opening is large enough for a Stone
0x1f9  /  0x68c3  : at the south of a magnificent throne-room
0x1fa  /  0x68d8  : at an open doorway in a narrow north-south corridor
0x1fb  /  0x68f2  : in front of a carved granite throne in a magnificent room lined with decorated leather. This seems to be fashioned from human skin
0x1fc  /  0x693b  : at a crossing of passages
0x1fd  /  0x6949  : at a dead end
0x1fe  /  0x6952  : at a dead end
0x1ff  /  0x695b  : in an east-west corridor
0x200  /  0x6967  : in an east-west passage by a narrow entrance to 
the north
0x201  /  0x6982  : at a crossover between passages
0x202  /  0x6995  : at a dead end
0x203  /  0x699e  : at a dead end
0x204  /  0x69a7  : at a dead end
0x205  /  0x69b0  : surrounded by doorways. To the east is a curtained alcove
0x206  /  0x69c7  : at a dead end
0x207  /  0x69d0  : hidden in a curtained alcove
0x208  /  0x69de  : in a long dusty north-south passage
0x209  /  0x69ef  : at the top of a stairway
0x20a  /  0x69fb  : on gloomy stairs leading downwards
0x20b  /  0x6a0d  : at the south of the Pit. The Demon Lord AGALIAREPT crouches over a green bane-fire in the middle of the room, shrieking curses
0x20c  /  0x6a4a  : standing by the Bane-fire. But you can't get near enough to use the Amulet because of the evil radiance from the flames!
0x20d  /  0x6a8f  : on a wide ramp up the side of the Black Tower
0x20e  /  0x6aa4  : in Purgatory. You will have to stay here for a century or two.. if you're lucky!
0x20f  /  0x6ad8  : 
0x210  /  0x6ad9  : 
0x211  /  0x6ada  : 
0x212  /  0x6adb  : 
0x213  /  0x6adc  : 
0x214  /  0x6add  : 
0x215  /  0x6ade  : 
0x216  /  0x6adf  : 
0x217  /  0x6ae0  : 
0x218  /  0x6ae1  : 
0x219  /  0x6ae2  : 
0x21a  /  0x6ae3  : 
0x21b  /  0x6ae4  : 
0x21c  /  0x6ae5  : 
0x21d  /  0x6ae6  : 
0x21e  /  0x6ae7  : 
0x21f  /  0x6ae8  : 
0x220  /  0x6ae9  : 
0x221  /  0x6aea  : 
0x222  /  0x6aeb  : 
0x223  /  0x6aec  : 
0x224  /  0x6aed  : 
0x225  /  0x6aee  : 
0x226  /  0x6aef  : 
0x227  /  0x6af0  : 

0x6af0
