Data length: 27392
0x0  /  0x2860  : 
0x1  /  0x2861  : 

Welcome to Colossal Adventure, the original classic mainframe adventure, from Level 9 Computing


0x2  /  0x28a4  : Rubbing the electric lamp is unexciting. Anyway, nothing happens except that you polish the lamp to a fine finish
0x3  /  0x28e5  : That was just what you needed!
0x4  /  0x28f9  : You can't move in that direction
0x5  /  0x290d  : I don't understand


0x6  /  0x291a  : Please be more specific
0x7  /  0x2927  : Eh?
0x8  /  0x292b  : You can't see it
0x9  /  0x2936  : You don't have it
0xa  /  0x2942  : You have:
0xb  /  0x2949  : Nothing
0xc  /  0x294f  : 


0xd  /  0x2951  : 

What now?


0xe  /  0x295b  : The lamp is on
0xf  /  0x2962  : The lamp is off
0x10  /  0x296a  : The grate is locked
0x11  /  0x2974  : The grate is unlocked
0x12  /  0x297f  : It clangs shut
0x13  /  0x2989  : You have no keys, or hairpins
0x14  /  0x299f  : The bottle is full up
0x15  /  0x29ab  : The water soaks away into the ground
0x16  /  0x29bc  : The oil splashes on the ground
0x17  /  0x29cb  : Nothing happens
0x18  /  0x29d5  : You can almost catch the bird, but it keeps fluttering away just as you are about to close your 
hand on it
0x19  /  0x2a15  : When you entered the bird was singing happily. Now it flies away in total panic and flutters against the ceiling
0x1a  /  0x2a52  : The bird is dead and its body vanishes
0x1b  /  0x2a67  : It's not hungry, just pining for the fjords
0x1c  /  0x2a82  : You fall to the rocks below
0x1d  /  0x2a8f  : No fear!
0x1e  /  0x2a96  : Zingg! A crystal bridge appears spanning the chasm
0x1f  /  0x2ab3  : The bridge vanishes
0x20  /  0x2abd  : The snake rears up above you, blocking the way out. Venom drips from its fangs, burning smoking 
holes in the rocky floor
0x21  /  0x2b04  : No way!
0x22  /  0x2b0a  : The bird attacks the snake and in a flurry of feathers drives it off!
0x23  /  0x2b31  : 

A hollow voice says 'PLUGH'


0x24  /  0x2b4a  : The shadowy figure waves back
0x25  /  0x2b5c  : Its a carnivore, so there's nothing here that it wants to eat (except you of course)
0x26  /  0x2b90  : You attack the dragon with your bare hands and with an incredible display of martial arts prowess you win! Who would have thought it possible?
0x27  /  0x2be1  : The bird attacks the dragon and in a flurry of feathers is eaten! The dragon licks its lips and 
returns to sleep
0x28  /  0x2c1d  : It bounces off the dragon's scales. The dragon opens an eye and glares at you
0x29  /  0x2c45  : The clam won't open
0x2a  /  0x2c50  : The clam opens and you realise that it is really an oyster. A gleaming pearl springs out and rolls away downhill out of sight.
0x2b  /  0x2c95  : You crawl through a network of twisty passages, 
get totally disorientated and end up back at Witt's End. The Witt Construction company have been practicing for years with one way schemes above ground so you will not get away easily!
0x2c  /  0x2d1a  : Get it right, dummy


0x2d  /  0x2d2a  : The precious vase shatters into a million tiny pieces on the hard ground!
0x2e  /  0x2d51  : Your hands are full, you can't carry anything else unless you drop something first
0x2f  /  0x2d81  : The bear snaps dangerously, forcing you to back 
away to the far side of the room
0x30  /  0x2dac  : The chain clicks open and falls to the floor. The bear is free and stretches joyfully
0x31  /  0x2dd5  : The bear dodges, sadly, and you miss
0x32  /  0x2dec  : The bear shambles towards the troll and rears up on its hind legs. The troll gives a loud shriek and runs away in panic. The bear follows it for a short distance and then returns
0x33  /  0x2e49  : The chain is locked
0x34  /  0x2e53  : You fell into a pit in the dark: dangerous places these caves
0x35  /  0x2e75  : 

You seem to have got yourself killed
0x36  /  0x2e8e  : 

Clumsy oaf! You are making quite a habit of this aren't you. Please try to be more careful in future!
0x37  /  0x2ec6  : 

Good grief, you've done it again! You are supposed to at least try to stay alive you know!
0x38  /  0x2efe  : You can't climb back up to the pit from the Hall of Mists
0x39  /  0x2f19  : There is nothing here to climb
0x3a  /  0x2f29  : The gate squeaks but does not budge. It seems to be rusted solid
0x3b  /  0x2f51  : It is dark, you cannot see
0x3c  /  0x2f61  : Please be more specific
0x3d  /  0x2f6e  : You are already carrying it
0x3e  /  0x2f7c  : A huge troll jumps out and blocks your way, snarling 'Gotcha! Thought you could evade paying the toll did you? Well I was much too quick for you.. you had no chance of outwitting me.. an expert bridge-keeper for a thousand years.. never missed a day..' etc. etc. Eventually the troll shuts up and stands blocking the bridge, one hand outstretched for payment of a treasure
0x3f  /  0x3053  : The troll blocks your way, holding out a fist for payment
0x40  /  0x3074  : The troll catches the axe, snorts 'Not even sharp!', and tosses it back. You just manage to catch it without getting cut
0x41  /  0x30b8  : Missed! The axe clatters to the ground
0x42  /  0x30cc  : A hit! The dwarf vanishes in a puff of foul smelling, greasy smoke
0x43  /  0x30f5  : One dwarf vanishes in a puff of greasy smoke
0x44  /  0x3112  : It's already open
0x45  /  0x311e  : There's no liquid here to fill it with
0x46  /  0x3133  : Your bottle is already empty
0x47  /  0x3147  : You have none
0x48  /  0x3151  : The plant bursts into incredible growth, reaching upwards into the air and throwing out enormous leaves. Eventually it stops, towering over your head and yelling 'WATER! WATER!' in your ear
0x49  /  0x31b5  : The beanstalk grows even larger than before, almost filling the pit and stretching high into the air. The tip reaches into an opening in the wall above!
0x4a  /  0x31fd  : You have OVER-WATERED it! The beanstalk flails about and collapses, falling in a mass to the floor of the pit where it shrivels up. All that remains is a tiny plant whispering 'water, water'
0x4b  /  0x3269  : The gate creaks open, dislodging a shower of rusty flakes
0x4c  /  0x328b  : The plant shakes the oil from its leaves in fury
0x4d  /  0x32a8  : Are you mad? You should only attack enemies
0x4e  /  0x32c5  : Dwarves are too agile for YOU to catch. You only succeed in getting out of breath
0x4f  /  0x32f3  : The main headline is 'Don't go West'. The lead story is about the success of the Dwarven King who has added the heads of another two elves to his collection. The editorial denounces the perverted ways of 'Elvies' and page 3 features a female dwarf whose long grey beard has been positioned ingeniously. The rest is adverts, mainly for Witt Construction Plc (dungeons a speciality) and Acorn Forestry (oaks take a long time to grow - order now for your grandchildren)
0x50  /  0x3403  : Your score is 

0x51  /  0x340d  :  
out of 1100


0x52  /  0x3417  : 

You scored 

0x53  /  0x3421  : Do you really want to stop?


0x54  /  0x3432  : The bear gobbles the food hungrily, and licks your face in thanks. It seems quite placid
0x55  /  0x3464  : You can't reach the mirror
0x56  /  0x3473  : Ugh! No thank you!
0x57  /  0x347f  : To whom?
0x58  /  0x3486  : The troll snaps 'Worthless' and tosses it back
0x59  /  0x34a3  : The troll takes the treasure and leaves, chortling
0x5a  /  0x34bd  : When you reach the middle of the bridge it collapses under the bear's weight, throwing you into 
the chasm.
0x5b  /  0x34f3  : 

A dwarf appears and throws an axe which misses 
you. The dwarf curses and runs off round a corner
0x5c  /  0x352c  : 

An evil little dwarf appears!
0x5d  /  0x3541  : 

Out from the shadows behind you pounces a bearded pirate! "HAR, HAR", he chortles, "I'll just take all this booty and hide it with me chest deep in the maze!". He snatches all of your treasure and vanishes into the gloom


0x5e  /  0x35bd  : 

A sharp little knife is thrown at you


0x5f  /  0x35d4  : It gets you!
0x60  /  0x35dc  : It misses!
0x61  /  0x35e3  : There is one threatening little dwarf here
0x62  /  0x35f8  : There are 

0x63  /  0x35fe  :  
threatening little dwarves here
0x64  /  0x3610  : 
0x65  /  0x3611  : You are standing beside a small brick building at the end of a road from the north. A river flows south. To the north is open country and all around is dense forest
0x66  /  0x365c  : You are in a valley beside a stream which cascades along a rocky bed on its way south. The valley is lined by woodland trees and you can hear birds singing from their branches
0x67  /  0x36b1  : You are in a tree-lined valley beside a stream which seeps away down many small cracks in the ground. Downstream, to the south, the valley narrows and the streambed contains only dry rocks
0x68  /  0x3706  : You are in a 20-foot depression in a deep, narrow valley sloping down to the south. The steep sides of the valley are overgrown with brambles
0x69  /  0x374c  : You are in a steep rocky gulley which slopes down to the south
0x6a  /  0x3769  : You are at the top of a dried-up waterfall. A sheer east-west cliff slices through the land, giving you an astonishing view of the southlands spread out like a map below you. A river emerges from the base of the cliff 1000 feet below and meanders away, but there is no way down to it. A steep gulley winds down towards you from the north through the woods on top of the cliff
0x6b  /  0x3822  : You are in dense forest, completely surrounded by trees
0x6c  /  0x383e  : You are in a pleasant wood on the east side of a valley. You can hear the sound of rushing water from a river below
0x6d  /  0x3872  : You are lost in the forest
0x6e  /  0x387e  : You are lost in the forest
0x6f  /  0x388a  : You are standing beside a huge oak tree in the depths of the forest. A partly-broken branch hangs down, resting one end on the ground, and you could easily climb the tree if you tried
0x70  /  0x38e5  : You are sitting in the branches of a huge tree and have a splendid view of the forest which stretches in all directions. You can see a huge spire to the south: beyond this the land seems to fall away. In the far north an active volcano belches fumes into the air, and to the west a narrow valley cuts through the trees
0x71  /  0x397a  : You are at a picnic spot littered with small tables and benches carved roughly from tree-trunks. In the centre a large stencilled sign saying 'no litter' is attached to one of the tables
0x72  /  0x39dd  : You are in a small building with a well in the middle of the only room. A rusty ladder leads down the well into darkness
0x73  /  0x3a14  : You are on a small hill. To the north, an active volcano throws a plume of ash into the air. A path leads east and you can see a small brick building surrounded by woodland far away to the west. To the south, a spire rises into the clouds
0x74  /  0x3a89  : You are at a cliff edge. A path from the west ends here
0x75  /  0x3aa3  : You are in a tiny rocky cave below a grate to the surface. A low crawl leads west into darkness
0x76  /  0x3ad0  : You are in the Plover room: a small chamber glowing with an eerie green light. An extremely narrow crack leads west and an ominous dark corridoor exits to the north-east
0x77  /  0x3b20  : You are in Heaven, sitting on a cloud and strumming a harp. It's not quite what you expected: rather boring in fact
0x78  /  0x3b60  : You are in Hell. The air is very hot and there is a strong stench of brimstone. It is definitely not boring, but slightly more painful than Heaven was!
0x79  /  0x3bb2  : You are in open countryside. A road leads to a building in the south, surrounded by woods. A spire rises into the clouds beyond
0x7a  /  0x3bf1  : You are on scrubland, in a thicket of dense hawthorn
0x7b  /  0x3c0f  : You are on a vast expanse of lava south of an active volcano. There is a small hill to the south
0x7c  /  0x3c3d  : You are surrounded by an expanse of jagged rocks,split by former volcanic eruptions
0x7d  /  0x3c6e  : You are at the very rim of a volcano, above a pit of bubbling lava. Far below you is a small opening in the side of the crater but there is no way down to it. A huge plume of ash rises slowlyfrom the fires below and floats sluggishly downto the east
0x7e  /  0x3ce6  : You are in a room with matt black walls. A plaque reads 'Congratulations on bringing light to the dark room!'. The only exit is south
0x7f  /  0x3d24  : You are crawling painfully over cobbles in a low passage. A dim light filters from the east
0x80  /  0x3d51  : You are in a room filled with debris washed from the surface. The cobbles end here, but an awkward canyon continues west. 'The magic word is XYZZY' is scratched on the wall in crude runes
0x81  /  0x3db5  : You are in an awkwardly sloping east-west canyon
0x82  /  0x3dcb  : You are in a splendid chamber in an east-west canyon. The walls are frozen rivers of orange stone and a carved pillar rises to the ceiling 30 feet above. The floor is formed from smooth marble slabs, and is slightly worn in the centre
0x83  /  0x3e38  : The passage from the east ends here. At your feet is a pit from which mist coils upwards
0x84  /  0x3e6a  : You are on the north-east side of a deep chasm crossed by a rickety bridge. A draught blows towards an opening where the path enters the cliff to the north-east
0x85  /  0x3eb6  : You are in a low east-west corridor
0x86  /  0x3ec1  : You are at a fork in the path with openings to west, north-east and south-east. A steady draught blows north-east and you can hear a quiet rumbling noise
0x87  /  0x3f0a  : You are at a junction with warm walls. From a passage to the north comes a continuous roar, so loud that the entire cave trembles. Other entrances lead east and south
0x88  /  0x3f58  : You are in a small chamber filled with huge boulders. The walls are very warm and the heated air is stifling. The only exit is a crawl to the west, from which direction comes a low rumbling
0x89  /  0x3fb7  : You are at the edge of a volcano with a fantastic view over the crater. Great gouts of molten lava surge upwards before cascading into the depths and the thunder from the pit is deafening. The cracked and broken rocks of the cavern walls glare blood-red with an eerie light which reflects in macabre shifting shapes. An immense river of fire plummets from a gorge in the far wall, crashing into the pit, and to your left a column of blistering steam screams into the air. A dark forboding passage leaves to the south. The very Devil himself could have created this
0x8a  /  0x40dd  : You are in a steeply sloping limestone passage lined with twisted rock formations
0x8b  /  0x4104  : You are in a barren room outside a small room used for keeping animals: a sign reads 'WARE BEAR'. A passage slopes upwards
0x8c  /  0x4149  : You are inside the bear room
0x8d  /  0x4155  : You are down a dry well which smells rather disgusting. A ladder leads up to a small circle of light far above
0x8e  /  0x418d  : 
0x8f  /  0x418e  : 
0x90  /  0x418f  : 
0x91  /  0x4190  : 
0x92  /  0x4191  : 
0x93  /  0x4192  : 
0x94  /  0x4193  : 
0x95  /  0x4194  : 
0x96  /  0x4195  : You are at the east end of the Hall of Mists, filled with wisps of cloud which sway to and fro as if alive. There are passages on both sides and a narrow path leading up to a small opening above. A grand stone staircase leads downwards to the north
0x97  /  0x4202  : You are in a long low room with a crude note pinned to the wall saying 'You won't get it up to the pit'
0x98  /  0x4235  : You are in the Hall of the Mountain Kings, a huge room decorated with majestic statues. The east wall is covered by trophies and the mounted heads of elves and monsters with a carved granite throne standing beneath them. The hall is hung about with the tattered remains of rich tapestries and has large doorways on all sides
0x99  /  0x42d3  : You are in the south side chamber of the Hall of the Mountain Kings
0x9a  /  0x42ee  : You are in a low north-south passage at a hole in the floor. This goes down to an east-west passage below
0x9b  /  0x4314  : You are in a huge room with passages to the south and west and a maze of broken rock to the east. 'Y2' is carved on a rock in the very centre of the room
0x9c  /  0x4352  : You are at a window overlooking a huge canyon. The floor is just visible over 50 feet below, covered by drifting white mist. On the opposite side of the canyon is a window into a lighted room 
and you can just make out a shadowy figure watching your every movement
0x9d  /  0x43d5  : You are in a jumble of rocks with small cracks everywhere
0x9e  /  0x43f1  : You are on the east bank of a wide fissure slicing completely across the Hall of Mists. The white fog is very thick here and the fissure is much too wide to jump
0x9f  /  0x443d  : You are on the west bank of a wide fissure slicing completely across the Hall of Mists. Dense fog rises from the fissure and spreads out on either side of it
0xa0  /  0x4487  : You are at the west end of the Hall of Mists. To the south is a little passage, six feet off the ground. A low wide crawl continues west and another goes north
0xa1  /  0x44ca  : You are at the east end of a very long hall apparently without side chambers. A low crawl continues east, and to the north is a small round hole
0xa2  /  0x4509  : You are at the west end of a very long featureless hall which joins up with a narrow north-south passage
0xa3  /  0x453b  : You are at a cross-over of high north-south passage and a low east-west one
0xa4  /  0x455d  : You are at a dead end
0xa5  /  0x4566  : You are in the west side chamber of the Hall of 
the Mountain Kings. A passage continues west
0xa6  /  0x4592  : You are in a secret east-west canyon above a very tight north-canyon 15 feet below. If you climbed down, you might not be able to get back up again
0xa7  /  0x45dc  : You are in a wide north-south canyon partly filled with shifting mist, at a place where a slab of floor has collapsed into the room below to leave a large hole
0xa8  /  0x4629  : You are at the junction between the south end of a secret north-south canyon and the west end of a secret east-west canyon
0xa9  /  0x4659  : You are in a huge north-south canyon, partly filled by white mist seeping from the north. Far above, an enormous two-sided mirror is suspended between the cavern walls. (The mirror is obviously provided for the use of the dwarves who are extremely vain.) There is a small window in either wall, level with the mirror.
0xaa  /  0x46f8  : You are on the edge of a massive underground reservoir which stretches as far as the eye can see. An opaque cloud of white mist rises from the lake and streams upwards and south through the only exit. You can hear splashing water from within the mist: obviously the lake is filled by a large stream
0xab  /  0x4791  : You are in a magnificent cavern with a rushing stream which cascades over a sparkling waterfall, flows into a roaring whirlpool and disappears through a hole in the floor. Huge passages exit to south and west
0xac  /  0x47f7  : You are on the brink of a small, clean, climable pit. A crawl leads west
0xad  /  0x481d  : You are at the bottom of a pit, standing in about 6 inches of icy water
0xae  /  0x483e  : You are at the top of a steep incline above a large room. You could climb down, but would not be able to climb back up. A passage leads back the way you came, from the north
0xaf  /  0x4895  : You are following a wide path round the outer edge of a large cavern far below. Through thick white mist, splashing water can be heard in the distance below. The mist rises from the cavern and up through a hole in the roof. The path exits to south and west
0xb0  /  0x4914  : You are in an anteroom leading to a large passage to the east. Small passages go west and up. The remains of recent digging are evident and a sign floating in mid-air flashes 'CAVE UNDER CONSTRUCTION: PROCEED AT YOUR OWN RISK (Witt Construction Plc)'
0xb1  /  0x49ad  : You are at Witt's End. A maze of tiny passages have been dug in all directions as the first phase in constructing a new cavern
0xb2  /  0x49ef  : You are in an alcove at the end of a winding path from the north-west. An eerie light shines through an extremely tight entrance to the east
0xb3  /  0x4a31  : You are in an arched hall. The ceiling has collapsed so you will have to return the way you came
0xb4  /  0x4a63  : You are in a steeply sloping corridor with sharp walls
0xb5  /  0x4a7c  : You are in a cul-de-sac at the lower end of a steeply sloping passage. Pieces of broken shell are strewn all over the floor
0xb6  /  0x4ab5  : You are in Bedquilt, a long east-west passage with holes all around. There are so many holes that you can't tell which is which and so exploration can only be at random
0xb7  /  0x4b0a  : You are at a dead end crawl
0xb8  /  0x4b17  : You are in the soft room. The walls are hidden behind velvet curtains, a thick pile carpet covers the floor, and dense moss grows on the ceiling
0xb9  /  0x4b5d  : You are in a tall east-west canyon with a narrow chink to the north
0xba  /  0x4b75  : The north-south canyon ends in a mass of boulders: there is no way to go further north
0xbb  /  0x4ba3  : You are at a wide place in a very tight north-south canyon
0xbc  /  0x4bbc  : You are at the south end of a very tight north-south canyon. The canyon becomes too narrow for you to go further
0xbd  /  0x4bec  : You are in a twisting corridor which leads north in one direction and slopes down in the other.
0xbe  /  0x4c15  : You are in the east pit beside an oil well
0xbf  /  0x4c26  : You are at the west end of the twopit room, above a deep pit. A passage continues west
0xc0  /  0x4c4c  : You are at the bottom of the west pit - 20 feet 
below the floor of two-pit. You can see a large 
hole in the wall far above
0xc1  /  0x4c87  : You are on the south west side of a chasm crossed by a rickety bridge. The path crossing the bridge joins a tunnel to the south-west
0xc2  /  0x4cc5  : You are in a long narrow corridor, stretching out of sight to the west. To the east is a hole through which you can see a profusion of leaves.
0xc3  /  0x4d07  : You are in the Giant Room filled with enormous furniture and with no ceiling (or perhaps it is just too high for your lamp to show it). Cavernous passages lead north, south and east. On the west wall is the inscription 'FEE FIE FOE FOO'
0xc4  /  0x4d82  : The passage is blocked by a recent cave-in and you cannot go further east. You will have to retrace your steps
0xc5  /  0x4dc2  : You are in a secret north-south canyon above a sizable passage
0xc6  /  0x4dd9  : You are in a dirty broken passage. To the east is a low crawl and to the west is a large passage. There is a hole in the ceiling above
0xc7  /  0x4e0c  : You are in a large room knee-deep in dust. There are cracks everywhere and a passage leading east. You could wriggle down a hole to a junction below
0xc8  /  0x4e56  : You are in a large low room with exits to north, south-east and south-west
0xc9  /  0x4e76  : This is the oriental room. Oriental tapestries and drawings cover the walls, and chimes make quiet music high above. Gently sloping passages lead north, west and south-east
0xca  /  0x4ecc  : You are at a complex junction. A low hands and knees passage from the north joins a higher crawl from the east to make a 5 foot passage going west. You could also climb up through a hole in the ceiling. A salty smell blows from the north and you can hear a quiet murmuring
0xcb  /  0x4f59  : You are in a room decorated with millions of shells embedded in the walls. A shallow passage leads down and a steeper one leads up. A low passage leaves to the south. You can hear the sound of the sea far away and seem to feel salt spray on your face
0xcc  /  0x4fd3  : You are in a room whose walls resemble swiss cheese. It smells a bit cheesy too. Obvious passages lead west, east and north-east, but there could well be others
0xcd  /  0x5027  : You are at the eastern end of a long room with two pits in the floor. You are near the east pit, and the many thin stone slabs littering the room would make descending it simple. A path bypasses the pits to connect passages from east and west. There are holes all around, but the only large one is high above the west pit, out of easy reach
0xce  /  0x50ca  : You are in a large, low, circular room almost filled by a huge slab of rock fallen from the ceiling. To east and west are large passages, completely filled by boulders. Low, small passages lead north and south: the south one bends east round some boulders
0xcf  /  0x5140  : You are in a gigantic north-south passage
0xd0  /  0x5151  : You are at a window overlooking a huge canyon. On the other side is a lighted window at which you can just make out a shadowy figure peering back
0xd1  /  0x5199  : You are at a junction between a secret north-south canyon and a passage to the south-east
0xd2  /  0x51be  : You are at the southern end of a secret north-south canyon. A stalagtite hangs down from the ceiling: you could climb down it to a room below but not get back up
0xd3  /  0x5209  : 
0xd4  /  0x520a  : 
0xd5  /  0x520b  : 
0xd6  /  0x520c  : 
0xd7  /  0x520d  : You are at a dead end
0xd8  /  0x5216  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same. You could climb down a massive orange column, but might not be able to climb back up. The maze continues on this level
0xd9  /  0x5264  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xda  /  0x526b  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xdb  /  0x5272  : You are at a dead end
0xdc  /  0x527b  : You are at a dead end
0xdd  /  0x5284  : You are at a dead end
0xde  /  0x528d  : You are at a dead end
0xdf  /  0x5296  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xe0  /  0x529d  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xe1  /  0x52a4  : You are at a dead end
0xe2  /  0x52ad  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xe3  /  0x52b4  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xe4  /  0x52bb  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xe5  /  0x52c2  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xe6  /  0x52c9  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xe7  /  0x52d0  : You are at a dead end
0xe8  /  0x52d9  : You are at a dead end
0xe9  /  0x52e2  : You are at a dead end
0xea  /  0x52eb  : You are at a dead end
0xeb  /  0x52f4  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xec  /  0x52fb  : You are at a dead end
0xed  /  0x5304  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xee  /  0x530b  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xef  /  0x5312  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xf0  /  0x5319  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all the same
0xf1  /  0x5320  : 
0xf2  /  0x5321  : 
0xf3  /  0x5322  : 
0xf4  /  0x5323  : 
0xf5  /  0x5324  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different. There is a vending machine marked 'batteries for sale' and a notice saying 'the pirate keeps his chest in the other maze'
0xf6  /  0x5374  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xf7  /  0x537f  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xf8  /  0x538a  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xf9  /  0x5395  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xfa  /  0x53a0  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xfb  /  0x53ab  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xfc  /  0x53b6  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xfd  /  0x53c1  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xfe  /  0x53cc  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0xff  /  0x53d7  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x100  /  0x53e2  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x101  /  0x53ed  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x102  /  0x53f8  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x103  /  0x5403  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x104  /  0x540e  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x105  /  0x5419  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x106  /  0x5424  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x107  /  0x542f  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x108  /  0x543a  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x109  /  0x5445  : You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all different
0x10a  /  0x5450  : You are on a steep hillside rising up through the wood
0x10b  /  0x546b  : You are on a very steep hillside rising high above the surrounding woodland
0x10c  /  0x5492  : The trees thin out and an unclimable spire of polished rock rises from a clearing in the forest.
0x10d  /  0x54c3  : You are at the north-east end of a vast cave, surrounded by snoring dwarves. A welded grate covers a pit of green snakes and young beanstalks, and bits of broken vending machine litter the floor. Hundreds of small passages, just large enough for the dwarves but not for you, lead in all directions
0x10e  /  0x5553  : You are at the south-west end of a vast hall filled with a loud snoring emerging from a large heap at the other side. Bats skim around the ceiling far above and high in one wall is stuck a trident (perhaps it lodged in a crevice when thrown at one of the bats). The cavern walls are honeycombed with tiny passages, just too small for you
0x10f  /  0x55f4  : You are in a narrow east-west corridor, carved crudely out of the rock. The floor is littered with rock fragments left when the secret stone door at the east end of the corridoor was shattered
0x110  /  0x564f  : The east-west corridoor continues
0x111  /  0x565e  : You are in an east-west corridor beside an iron 
ladder which reaches up through a round hole in 
the ceiling. The corridoor continues
0x112  /  0x5698  : The east-west coridor continues, but is completely blocked by rubbish. You had better retrace your steps
0x113  /  0x56d4  : You are on a metal ladder rising up a stone shaft
0x114  /  0x56ef  : You are further up the ladder
0x115  /  0x56fe  : You are on a metal ladder, climbing up through a stone shaft
0x116  /  0x571f  : You are near the top of a metal ladder. There is a circular opening above
0x117  /  0x5743  : You are a in network of stone passages beside a 
pit. The passages lead in all directions
0x118  /  0x5768  : You are in a network of stone passages, which lead in all directions
0x119  /  0x5787  : You are in a network of stone passages, which lead in all directions
0x11a  /  0x57a6  : You are in a network of stone passages, which lead in all directions
0x11b  /  0x57c5  : You are in a network of stone passages, which lead in all directions
0x11c  /  0x57e4  : You are in a network of stone passages, which lead in all directions
0x11d  /  0x5803  : You are in a network of stone passages, which lead in all directions
0x11e  /  0x5822  : You are in a network of stone passages, which lead in all directions
0x11f  /  0x5841  : You are in a network of stone passages
0x120  /  0x584f  : You are in an east-west passage lined with large square stones, from each of which hangs a set of rusty iron manacles. The ceiling drips water which falls onto heaps of decaying refuse covering the floor. There is an open trap-door in the roof and a small stone staircase leads up into the darkness behind it
0x121  /  0x58e8  : You are in a torture chamber with an exit to the west. The room is cluttered with odd and unusual items which fortunately you do not recognise!
0x122  /  0x5935  : You are in long straight passage, lined with slabs of stone from which hang rusted manacles. The passage gets wider to the west. Scratches on the floor lead to a narrow entrance sloping downwards to the north, as if many heavy objects had been dragged in that direction
0x123  /  0x59bd  : You are at a dead end
0x124  /  0x59c6  : You are in a wide east-west dungeon walkway between cells to the north and south. The passage continues to east and west. The cells have no doors: clearly these would not be necessary as there are enough chains suspended from the walls to hold any number of prisoners
0x125  /  0x5a4e  : You are in a dingy dungeon cell with an entrance to the south. Rows of manacles line the east and west walls
0x126  /  0x5a82  : You are in a dingy dungeon cell with an entrance to the north. Rows of manacles line the east and west walls
0x127  /  0x5ab6  : You are on the east bank of a wide fissure which cuts completely across the dungeon walkway. A river of lava bubbles far below in the chasm, and foul acrid fumes rise up
0x128  /  0x5b12  : 
0x129  /  0x5b13  : You are on the west bank of a wide fissure which cuts right across the dungeon walkway. Far below in the fissure a river of lava bubbles slowly, sending up clouds of foul acrid fumes
0x12a  /  0x5b75  : You are in an east-west dungeon walkway near the dungeon entrance
0x12b  /  0x5b94  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x12c  /  0x5ba5  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x12d  /  0x5bb6  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x12e  /  0x5bc7  : You are at the bottom of the pit, in a large pentagonal room inscribed with weird symbols. The floor is caked with dried blood, scratched with complex markings. A wide stone staircase winds up from the pit towards a dim circle of light at the top of the staircase, far above
0x12f  /  0x5c51  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x130  /  0x5c62  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x131  /  0x5c73  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x132  /  0x5c84  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x133  /  0x5c95  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x134  /  0x5ca6  : You are on a spiral stone staircase
0x135  /  0x5cb7  : You are at the top of a high stone pinnacle surrounded by clouds. You look down through gaps between them and see a carpet of trees far below, stretching in all directions. To the north, the forest eventually thins into scrub as it approaches the slopes of a volcano. To the west a stream winds south along a narrow valley, and to the east the woodland continues as far as the eye can see. The staircase is the only way down
0x136  /  0x5d8a  : You at the edge of a huge cavern which is almost filled by a huge web hanging from the centre of the ceiling. Behind you, to the west, is an exit back to the spiral staircase
0x137  /  0x5dde  : You are south-west of a huge web, hanging heavily from the cavern roof
0x138  /  0x5dfd  : You are south of a huge, dirty web
0x139  /  0x5e11  : You are south-east of a huge web which hangs heavily from the cavern ceiling
0x13a  /  0x5e35  : You are east of a huge web which hangs down from the cavern roof
0x13b  /  0x5e53  : You are north-east of a huge web which hangs heavily from the cavern roof
0x13c  /  0x5e77  : You are in amongst the strands of a huge web that rises to the roof. You might be able to escape up a strand
0x13d  /  0x5eac  : You are north of a huge web which hangs in folds from the cavern ceiling
0x13e  /  0x5ecd  : You are north-west of a huge web, rising up towards the cavern ceiling
0x13f  /  0x5ee9  : You are clinging to thick strands of sticky grey web in the middle of a huge cavern. You can either go up, further into the web, or back down to the cavern floor far below
0x140  /  0x5f3d  : You are on a ledge above the cavern. It was once a magnificent place, judging from the fabulous carvings jutting out of the mess. A large round passage, exactly the same size as the spider, leads west
0x141  /  0x5fa7  : You are in the spider's lair, surrounded by thick sticky web. The stench is unbearable but fortunately there is no spider in sight. Round, narrow entrances lead east and west through the web
0x142  /  0x600c  : You are in a slimy east-west passage, almost blocked by strands of thick grey web to the east. A rain of water cascades from the walls and ceiling, forming a small stream which trickles away to the west. The drip of water drowns out all other sounds
0x143  /  0x6082  : You are in a low east-west passage beside an underground stream. Water trickles down the sides of the passage leaving brown stains and the stream is really getting quite deep
0x144  /  0x60c7  : You are beside an underground stream. To the west the stream completely fills the passage but there is a narrow opening to the north
0x145  /  0x60fe  : You are at a dead end
0x146  /  0x6107  : You are lost in the forest
0x147  /  0x6113  : You are swept along by the stream and held below the water. The current is not particularly strong, however, so you feel that you are in no danger. Fortunately your lamp seems to be waterproof
0x148  /  0x6179  : 
0x149  /  0x617a  : 
0x14a  /  0x617b  : 
0x14b  /  0x617c  : 
0x14c  /  0x617d  : 
0x14d  /  0x617e  : 
0x14e  /  0x617f  : There is a large padlocked grate set into the ground
0x14f  /  0x6199  : 
0x150  /  0x619a  : 
0x151  /  0x619b  : 
0x152  /  0x619c  : 
0x153  /  0x619d  : 
0x154  /  0x619e  : 
0x155  /  0x619f  : 
0x156  /  0x61a0  : 
0x157  /  0x61a1  : 
0x158  /  0x61a2  : 
0x159  /  0x61a3  : 
0x15a  /  0x61a4  : 
0x15b  /  0x61a5  : There is a large padlocked iron grate above you
0x15c  /  0x61c0  : 
0x15d  /  0x61c1  : 
0x15e  /  0x61c2  : 
0x15f  /  0x61c3  : 
0x160  /  0x61c4  : 
0x161  /  0x61c5  : 
0x162  /  0x61c6  : 
0x163  /  0x61c7  : 
0x164  /  0x61c8  : 
0x165  /  0x61c9  : 
0x166  /  0x61ca  : 
0x167  /  0x61cb  : 
0x168  /  0x61cc  : 
0x169  /  0x61cd  : 
0x16a  /  0x61ce  : 
0x16b  /  0x61cf  : 
0x16c  /  0x61d0  : 
0x16d  /  0x61d1  : 
0x16e  /  0x61d2  : 
0x16f  /  0x61d3  : 
0x170  /  0x61d4  : 
0x171  /  0x61d5  : 
0x172  /  0x61d6  : 
0x173  /  0x61d7  : 
0x174  /  0x61d8  : 
0x175  /  0x61d9  : 
0x176  /  0x61da  : 
0x177  /  0x61db  : 
0x178  /  0x61dc  : 
0x179  /  0x61dd  : 
0x17a  /  0x61de  : 
0x17b  /  0x61df  : 
0x17c  /  0x61e0  : 
0x17d  /  0x61e1  : 
0x17e  /  0x61e2  : A huge green snake hisses fiercely at you
0x17f  /  0x61fd  : 
0x180  /  0x61fe  : 
0x181  /  0x61ff  : 
0x182  /  0x6200  : 
0x183  /  0x6201  : 
0x184  /  0x6202  : 
0x185  /  0x6203  : 
0x186  /  0x6204  : 
0x187  /  0x6205  : 
0x188  /  0x6206  : 
0x189  /  0x6207  : 
0x18a  /  0x6208  : 
0x18b  /  0x6209  : 
0x18c  /  0x620a  : 
0x18d  /  0x620b  : 
0x18e  /  0x620c  : There is a large oriental dragon here, sitting on a large oriental carpet
0x18f  /  0x6232  : 
0x190  /  0x6233  : 
0x191  /  0x6234  : 
0x192  /  0x6235  : 
0x193  /  0x6236  : 
0x194  /  0x6237  : 
0x195  /  0x6238  : 
0x196  /  0x6239  : 
0x197  /  0x623a  : 
0x198  /  0x623b  : 
0x199  /  0x623c  : 
0x19a  /  0x623d  : 
0x19b  /  0x623e  : 
0x19c  /  0x623f  : 
0x19d  /  0x6240  : 
0x19e  /  0x6241  : 
0x19f  /  0x6242  : 
0x1a0  /  0x6243  : 
0x1a1  /  0x6244  : 
0x1a2  /  0x6245  : 
0x1a3  /  0x6246  : 
0x1a4  /  0x6247  : 
0x1a5  /  0x6248  : 
0x1a6  /  0x6249  : 
0x1a7  /  0x624a  : 
0x1a8  /  0x624b  : 
0x1a9  /  0x624c  : 
0x1aa  /  0x624d  : 
0x1ab  /  0x624e  : 
0x1ac  /  0x624f  : 
0x1ad  /  0x6250  : 
0x1ae  /  0x6251  : 
0x1af  /  0x6252  : 
0x1b0  /  0x6253  : 
0x1b1  /  0x6254  : A huge clam is anchored firmly to the floor
0x1b2  /  0x626d  : 
0x1b3  /  0x626e  : 
0x1b4  /  0x626f  : 
0x1b5  /  0x6270  : A rusty gate blocks the way north
0x1b6  /  0x6280  : 
0x1b7  /  0x6281  : 
0x1b8  /  0x6282  : 
0x1b9  /  0x6283  : 
0x1ba  /  0x6284  : 
0x1bb  /  0x6285  : 
0x1bc  /  0x6286  : The grate is open
0x1bd  /  0x628f  : 
0x1be  /  0x6290  : 
0x1bf  /  0x6291  : 
0x1c0  /  0x6292  : 
0x1c1  /  0x6293  : 
0x1c2  /  0x6294  : 
0x1c3  /  0x6295  : 
0x1c4  /  0x6296  : 
0x1c5  /  0x6297  : 
0x1c6  /  0x6298  : 
0x1c7  /  0x6299  : 
0x1c8  /  0x629a  : 
0x1c9  /  0x629b  : The grate is open and light streams in through it
0x1ca  /  0x62b3  : 
0x1cb  /  0x62b4  : 
0x1cc  /  0x62b5  : 
0x1cd  /  0x62b6  : 
0x1ce  /  0x62b7  : 
0x1cf  /  0x62b8  : 
0x1d0  /  0x62b9  : 
0x1d1  /  0x62ba  : 
0x1d2  /  0x62bb  : 
0x1d3  /  0x62bc  : 
0x1d4  /  0x62bd  : 
0x1d5  /  0x62be  : 
0x1d6  /  0x62bf  : 
0x1d7  /  0x62c0  : 
0x1d8  /  0x62c1  : A huge ugly troll stands by the bridge, palm outstretched
0x1d9  /  0x62e2  : 
0x1da  /  0x62e3  : 
0x1db  /  0x62e4  : 
0x1dc  /  0x62e5  : 
0x1dd  /  0x62e6  : 
0x1de  /  0x62e7  : 
0x1df  /  0x62e8  : 
0x1e0  /  0x62e9  : 
0x1e1  /  0x62ea  : 
0x1e2  /  0x62eb  : 
0x1e3  /  0x62ec  : 
0x1e4  /  0x62ed  : 
0x1e5  /  0x62ee  : 
0x1e6  /  0x62ef  : 
0x1e7  /  0x62f0  : 
0x1e8  /  0x62f1  : 
0x1e9  /  0x62f2  : 
0x1ea  /  0x62f3  : 
0x1eb  /  0x62f4  : 
0x1ec  /  0x62f5  : 
0x1ed  /  0x62f6  : 
0x1ee  /  0x62f7  : 
0x1ef  /  0x62f8  : 
0x1f0  /  0x62f9  : 
0x1f1  /  0x62fa  : 
0x1f2  /  0x62fb  : A crystal bridge spans the fissure
0x1f3  /  0x630d  : A crystal bridge spans the fissure
0x1f4  /  0x631f  : 
0x1f5  /  0x6320  : 
0x1f6  /  0x6321  : 
0x1f7  /  0x6322  : 
0x1f8  /  0x6323  : 
0x1f9  /  0x6324  : 
0x1fa  /  0x6325  : There are some coins here
0x1fb  /  0x6331  : 
0x1fc  /  0x6332  : 
0x1fd  /  0x6333  : 
0x1fe  /  0x6334  : 
0x1ff  /  0x6335  : 
0x200  /  0x6336  : 
0x201  /  0x6337  : 
0x202  /  0x6338  : 
0x203  /  0x6339  : 
0x204  /  0x633a  : 
0x205  /  0x633b  : 
0x206  /  0x633c  : 
0x207  /  0x633d  : 
0x208  /  0x633e  : 
0x209  /  0x633f  : 
0x20a  /  0x6340  : 
0x20b  /  0x6341  : 
0x20c  /  0x6342  : 
0x20d  /  0x6343  : 
0x20e  /  0x6344  : 
0x20f  /  0x6345  : 
0x210  /  0x6346  : 
0x211  /  0x6347  : 
0x212  /  0x6348  : 
0x213  /  0x6349  : 
0x214  /  0x634a  : A huge beanstalk reaches up to an opening above
0x215  /  0x6361  : A huge ugly troll stands by the bridge
0x216  /  0x6376  : 
0x217  /  0x6377  : 
0x218  /  0x6378  : 
0x219  /  0x6379  : 
0x21a  /  0x637a  : 
0x21b  /  0x637b  : 
0x21c  /  0x637c  : 
0x21d  /  0x637d  : 
0x21e  /  0x637e  : 
0x21f  /  0x637f  : There is a huge oyster here
0x220  /  0x638a  : 
0x221  /  0x638b  : 
0x222  /  0x638c  : 
0x223  /  0x638d  : The north gate is open
0x224  /  0x6399  : 
0x225  /  0x639a  : 
0x226  /  0x639b  : 
0x227  /  0x639c  : a bunch of keys
0x228  /  0x63a7  : a small brass lamp
0x229  /  0x63b3  : some sandwiches
0x22a  /  0x63bc  : 
0x22b  /  0x63bd  : a small gilded cage
0x22c  /  0x63c9  : a black rod
0x22d  /  0x63d0  : 
0x22e  /  0x63d1  : a heavy gold nugget
0x22f  /  0x63df  : silver bars
0x230  /  0x63e7  : some valuable jewelry
0x231  /  0x63f6  : some diamonds
0x232  /  0x63fd  : a bear lumbering along behind you
0x233  /  0x6412  : a platinum pyramid
0x234  /  0x641e  : an emerald as big as a plover's egg
0x235  /  0x6435  : some gold eggs
0x236  /  0x643e  : a patchwork pillow
0x237  /  0x644a  : a Ming Vase
0x238  /  0x6452  : a trident
0x239  /  0x6459  : a pearl
0x23a  /  0x645f  : this week's issue of Spelunker's Gazette
0x23b  /  0x6477  : some assorted coins
0x23c  /  0x6484  : a fine silver chain
0x23d  /  0x6491  : an oriental rug
0x23e  /  0x649b  : the pirate's gold-encrusted chest
0x23f  /  0x64af  : some spices
0x240  /  0x64b5  : a beautifully engraved throwing axe
0x241  /  0x64cb  : a stick of dynamite with 'blast' written on it
0x242  /  0x64e7  : a small jade pentacle
0x243  /  0x64f5  : the Elixir of Life
0x244  /  0x6501  : an elvish orb
0x245  /  0x650a  : an elvish sceptre
0x246  /  0x6515  : an elvish crown
0x247  /  0x651e  : 
0x248  /  0x651f  : 
0x249  /  0x6520  : 
0x24a  /  0x6521  : There is a bunch of keys here
0x24b  /  0x6531  : There is a small brass lamp here
0x24c  /  0x6541  : There are some sandwiches here
0x24d  /  0x6550  : 
0x24e  /  0x6551  : There is a gilded cage here
0x24f  /  0x655e  : There is a black rod here
0x250  /  0x656a  : There is a little bird here, singing merrily
0x251  /  0x6581  : There is a large gold nugget here
0x252  /  0x6594  : There are silver bars here
0x253  /  0x65a2  : There is some jewelry here
0x254  /  0x65ae  : There are some diamonds here
0x255  /  0x65ba  : There is a bear wandering about
0x256  /  0x65cb  : There is a platinum pyramid here
0x257  /  0x65dd  : There is an emerald here as big as a plovers egg
0x258  /  0x65f9  : There are some golden eggs here
0x259  /  0x6609  : There is a pillow here
0x25a  /  0x6614  : There is a Ming Vase here
0x25b  /  0x6620  : There is a trident here
0x25c  /  0x662b  : There is a glistening pearl here
0x25d  /  0x663c  : There is a copy of Spelunker's gazette here
0x25e  /  0x6654  : There are some coins here
0x25f  /  0x6660  : There is a fine silver chain here
0x260  /  0x6672  : There is an oriental rug here
0x261  /  0x6681  : There is the pirate's chest here
0x262  /  0x6691  : There are some rare spices here
0x263  /  0x669f  : There is a small axe here
0x264  /  0x66ab  : There is a stick of dynamite here
0x265  /  0x66bb  : There is a small jade pentacle here
0x266  /  0x66cc  : There is some elixir here
0x267  /  0x66d7  : There is an orb here
0x268  /  0x66e0  : There is a sceptre here
0x269  /  0x66ec  : There is a crown here
0x26a  /  0x66f6  : 
0x26b  /  0x66f7  : 
0x26c  /  0x66f8  : 
0x26d  /  0x66f9  : 
0x26e  /  0x66fa  : 
0x26f  /  0x66fb  : 
0x270  /  0x66fc  : 
0x271  /  0x66fd  : 
0x272  /  0x66fe  : 
0x273  /  0x66ff  : 
0x274  /  0x6700  : 
0x275  /  0x6701  : 
0x276  /  0x6702  : a bird in a gilded cage
0x277  /  0x6710  : There is a caged bird here
0x278  /  0x671e  : 

'CLICK. The cave is closing. Please leave by the main door. Thank you. CLICK.'


0x279  /  0x6750  : A chained bear lies peacefully on the ground
0x27a  /  0x6768  : A bear strains at its chain, trying to get at you
0x27b  /  0x6784  : A ming vase rests gently on a patchwork pillow
0x27c  /  0x679e  : an empty bottle
0x27d  /  0x67ab  : a bottle of water
0x27e  /  0x67b4  : a bottle of oil
0x27f  /  0x67bd  : There is an empty bottle here
0x280  /  0x67cd  : There is a bottle of water here
0x281  /  0x67db  : There is a bottle of oil here
0x282  /  0x67e9  : A tiny wilting seedling whispers 'water, water'
0x283  /  0x6803  : A fair-sized beanstalk sways about, waving its leaves and shouting 'WATER! WATER!'
0x284  /  0x6835  : The elf waves his cloak over you and your surroundings shimmer and fade. All is dark, but then the darkness grows less and you realise that you 
are at one end of a huge room
0x285  /  0x6890  : 
0x286  /  0x6891  : The eggs reappear!
0x287  /  0x689f  : The eggs vanish!
0x288  /  0x68ab  : I have it now
0x289  /  0x68b5  : Something that you're carrying is too big to fit through the gap


0x28a  /  0x68da  : The machine grabs the money and replaces your batteries. It then whirs, clicks brokenly and stops. A sign lights up saying 'MACHINE EMPTY'
0x28b  /  0x692d  : The dynamite explodes. 

0x28c  /  0x693c  : The dwarves all wake up. They all throw their sharp little knives, every one of which hits you!


0x28d  /  0x6971  :  
The roof collapses, killing all of the dwarves. 

0x28e  /  0x698f  : The blast collapses the ceiling at the north-west end of the cavern, killing all of the evil dwarves. The vibration from the collapse causes a huge hole to appear in the western wall through which you can see a corridor
0x28f  /  0x69f7  : 

Water is trickling in from nearby
0x290  /  0x6a0b  : The water is over your head!
0x291  /  0x6a18  : The water is up to your waist
0x292  /  0x6a25  : 

Unfortunately, you have failed to escape from the flood. You drown in the water


0x293  /  0x6a55  : 

An enormous blast rocks the dungeon as water meets lava
0x294  /  0x6a76  : You are killed by an enormous explosion as water meets lava
0x295  /  0x6a95  : The rocks on the floor come to life and dance about for a while. Then, seemingly tired, they lie back down for a rest
0x296  /  0x6ad3  : The skeletons regenerate back into handsome elves, and you notice a few humans amongst them (possibly former adventurers). All the resurrected folk cluster round you, proclaiming their thanks. Then, as if at some secret signal, they dance off singing joyfully, leaving you alone
0x297  /  0x6b78  : Lots of skeletons are chained to the walls
0x298  /  0x6b8d  : 

I'm not very good at this ... but do you want me to try and resurrect you?


0x299  /  0x6bbd  : There is a puff of choking green smoke. It gradually clears and...


0x29a  /  0x6be5  : Curses, the green smoke is used up!
0x29b  /  0x6bfc  : 

An elf appears - you recognise him as the warrior who gave you the map to Colossal Cavern. He congratulates you on your success and then says 'Please free my people, for their plight is an abomination. Will you do this?'


0x29c  /  0x6c85  : Coward! The elves will long remember your name with hatred
0x29d  /  0x6ca8  : Good luck! Be careful, and make sure to rescue ALL the elves


0x29e  /  0x6cce  : 

Would you like another game?


0x29f  /  0x6ce4  : A giant spider lurks on the web
0x2a0  /  0x6cf8  : A heavy dungeon door opens onto the stairway
0x2a1  /  0x6d10  : The dungeon door is locked
0x2a2  /  0x6d1e  : The combined weight of you and the spider together is too much for the web. It rips across, hurling you to the floor of the cave far below
0x2a3  /  0x6d64  : A huge spider is staring at the pentacle
0x2a4  /  0x6d77  : A puny effort!
0x2a5  /  0x6d82  : Not bad.. for a novice and a bumpkin!
0x2a6  /  0x6d9e  : A reasonable score.
0x2a7  /  0x6dab  : A good score indeed!
0x2a8  /  0x6dba  : You are now an Adventurer
0x2a9  /  0x6dc6  : You are now a Master Adventurer, an expert amongst the hosts of Adventuredom! Clearly it will be but a short while before you attain the exulted rank of Grandmaster
0x2aa  /  0x6e20  : The elves raise you on high and carry you through the forest in triumph, singing 'All hail to the conquering hero, victorious over the perils of the depths!

All hail to the saviour of the elvish race!

All hail to thee, GRANDMASTER ADVENTURER!'


0x2ab  /  0x6eb3  : A lightning bolt smites you, litter bug!
0x2ac  /  0x6ecb  : The spider blocks your way, glaring at you in an evil manner
0x2ad  /  0x6eee  : You hurl the pentacle into space and the spider 
follows
0x2ae  /  0x6f0c  : The spider grabs the pentacle and eats you
0x2af  /  0x6f22  : The elves are waiting for you in a golden host surrounding their king. They cheer wildly as you 
emerge into the sunlight.


0x2b0  /  0x6f62  : A hundred elves are chained to the wall
0x2b1  /  0x6f75  : You free a few elves and they unlock the rest. They all dance off, singing your praises
0x2b2  /  0x6fa3  : 

Your lamp is flickering and growing dim: its batteries are running out. You would be advised to find the vending machine and buy some new batteries from it


0x2b3  /  0x6ff8  : 

Your lamp fades and goes out. It looks like the end of the game for you this time, but continue if you like


0x2b4  /  0x7035  : The sound reverberates, waking the dwarves which look around angrily and see you. Instantly, every single dwarf hurls a sharp little knife at you and every single one of these hits! Perhaps you made a little mistake there
0x2b5  /  0x70b3  : 

0x70b3
