Data length: 27392
0x0  /  0x1e00  : Welcome to Dungeon Adventure from Level 9. Enter English phrases (no punctuation) to play, collect treasure and return to civilisation along the forest road to win.
0x1  /  0x1e66  : 

What next?


0x2  /  0x1e72  : I don't understand
0x3  /  0x1e7e  : Please be more specific
0x4  /  0x1e8c  : You can't do that
0x5  /  0x1e97  : Don't be silly!
0x6  /  0x1ea1  : Yeuch!!
0x7  /  0x1ea9  : Are you sure?
0x8  /  0x1eb2  : Please answer YES or NO


0x9  /  0x1ec5  : Nothing happens
0xa  /  0x1ed0  : You don't have it
0xb  /  0x1ed9  : You can't see it
0xc  /  0x1ee2  : 

Really stop?


0xd  /  0x1eed  : 

Another game?


0xe  /  0x1ef9  : 

Want to be resurrected?


0xf  /  0x1f09  : 

You have managed to get yourself killed!
0x10  /  0x1f1f  : 

You have got killed again!


0x11  /  0x1f2f  : 

Dead yet again!!


0x12  /  0x1f3d  : 

Your ghost rushes along 

0x13  /  0x1f4c  : but fades rapidly.. You are completely dead
0x14  /  0x1f66  : and enters the machine in the homely house. Your body regenerates rapidly 

0x15  /  0x1f8e  : and you are alive again


0x16  /  0x1f9d  : but the machine has been overworked. Something is wrong! Your new body slumps to the floor
0x17  /  0x1fd1  : 

You cannot see


0x18  /  0x1fda  : A faint light shines in
0x19  /  0x1fe8  : The sun hangs low in the sky
0x1a  /  0x1ff7  : The sun is setting!
0x1b  /  0x2003  : 

You have:


0x1c  /  0x200b  :  Nothing
0x1d  /  0x2012  : 

You are 

0x1e  /  0x2017  : .


0x1f  /  0x201a  : You can't move in that direction


0x20  /  0x202f  : The way is barred
0x21  /  0x2038  : There's a shut door in the way!


0x22  /  0x2049  : You must be joking!
0x23  /  0x2056  : There's nothing worth attacking!
0x24  /  0x2068  : Nice try, but that magic word is used up
0x25  /  0x2081  : 

And you are wearing:


0x26  /  0x2090  : ,


0x27  /  0x2093  : 


0x28  /  0x2095  : You can't carry any more
0x29  /  0x20a4  : You're too weak!
0x2a  /  0x20ae  : You didn't get very far!
0x2b  /  0x20bd  : OK for a beginner
0x2c  /  0x20c8  : You had some success
0x2d  /  0x20d6  : A worthy efort!
0x2e  /  0x20e1  : You have earned the rank of Adventurer
0x2f  /  0x20f4  : You're clearly an experienced Adventurer!
0x30  /  0x210e  : Congratulations, Master Adventurer! You'll soon 
be a Grandmaster
0x31  /  0x2136  : All hail to thee, Grandmaster Adventurer!!
0x32  /  0x2154  : It dodges
0x33  /  0x215b  : Your blow is deadly!
0x34  /  0x2165  : Gulp! The return blows kill you
0x35  /  0x2175  : Your attack is futile
0x36  /  0x2181  : You're not close enough
0x37  /  0x218e  : The sphere swallows you
0x38  /  0x219b  : The willow drops everything and wraps branches round its trunk
0x39  /  0x21bd  : You hack at a branch, blunting your axe
0x3a  /  0x21d6  : "Sorry!", says your sword, "Can't let you do that. It's against the rules for me to fight anything but dragins!"
0x3b  /  0x221b  : The sword protests: "See here guv, you're not gonna ditch me 'til I fight a dragin!"
0x3c  /  0x2252  : You've no weapons
0x3d  /  0x225e  : 62
0x3e  /  0x2261  : The room inverts!
0x3f  /  0x2269  : A yellow light scans your body and a copy flickers in the machine
0x40  /  0x228e  : 

Some seeds are dislodged and fall with loud explosions
0x41  /  0x22ae  : You're temporarily deaf
0x42  /  0x22bd  : You can't hear much
0x43  /  0x22c9  : Two evil giants are asleep in the clearing
0x44  /  0x22e3  : Two fierce giants are asleep below
0x45  /  0x22f9  : It hits one giant, waking him. Seeing no other source for the attack, he attacks the other and they rush off, fighting
0x46  /  0x233d  : A young girl, with flowing locks, sits on the island
0x47  /  0x235a  : The girl sings: she is a siren! You flounder into treacherous waters
0x48  /  0x2380  : You're deaf to the siren's song! She flees in panic
0x49  /  0x239a  : The tree grabs you
0x4a  /  0x23a4  : The tree grabs it with a branch, raising it high into the air
0x4b  /  0x23c6  : "Stop! Woodman, spare that tree! I'll give you a reward! OK?"


0x4c  /  0x23ef  : She gives you a carving and makes the tree drop 
everything
0x4d  /  0x2410  : It is very valuable!


0x4e  /  0x241d  : It is enchanted!


0x4f  /  0x2428  : It is nothing special
0x50  /  0x2434  : A sleep spell hits you! 

0x51  /  0x2444  : You wake on the mud-bank
0x52  /  0x2451  : But your mirror reflects it! You hear snoring from the south
0x53  /  0x2470  : Your foot breaks a twig: SNAP! A masked man leaps up and flees
0x54  /  0x2497  : Dazzling lightening spears the hilltop and a host of fierce flames spring forth: they are Rakshasa! Their leader floats forwards. 

0x55  /  0x24e4  : "How about a game: If you win I'll strengthen the flames of your soul. If you lose, I get your body. OK?"


0x56  /  0x2526  : I'll roll a dice: 1-3 you lose, 4-6 you win. 

0x57  /  0x2542  : It's a 

0x58  /  0x2548  : ! YOU LOSE!
0x59  /  0x2553  : ! YOU WIN! The Rakshasa envelop you briefly before leaving
0x5a  /  0x2579  : 91
0x5b  /  0x257c  : It won't burn
0x5c  /  0x2585  : It burns to ash
0x5d  /  0x258e  : You've no fire
0x5e  /  0x2598  : The pig dissolves
0x5f  /  0x25a4  : You feel much stronger!
0x60  /  0x25b3  : You're too weak!
0x61  /  0x25bd  : The wood burns brightly
0x62  /  0x25cc  : 99
0x63  /  0x25cf  : There's nothing worth opening
0x64  /  0x25e0  : The stick emits a reedy whistle
0x65  /  0x25f1  :  
and the door swings open
0x66  /  0x2600  : It's too risky!
0x67  /  0x260c  : There's nothing to fill it with
0x68  /  0x261c  : 

Your score is 

0x69  /  0x2626  :  
out of 600.


0x6a  /  0x2630  : You don't find anything
0x6b  /  0x263e  : OK, you lose then
0x6c  /  0x2649  : And I'll even use your dice to be fair..




0x6d  /  0x2665  : The sword slays the dragon and they fade away, leaving the dragon's teeth and its golden bed
0x6e  /  0x2694  :  

0x6f  /  0x2696  : , 
burning brightly
0x70  /  0x26a3  : You've no weapon
0x71  /  0x26ae  : A beautiful dryad springs from the tree. 

0x72  /  0x26c9  : The willow drops everything and wraps branches round its trunk
0x73  /  0x26eb  : The tree has run out of branches: all 6 are in use!
0x74  /  0x2709  : The sun sets!
0x75  /  0x2712  : A gentle dryad stands beside the tree
0x76  /  0x2725  : An enormous dragon lies on a golden bed
0x77  /  0x273b  : A grotesque bloated yellow bird with big ears squats on the nest
0x78  /  0x275d  : . This sound scares the bird away
0x79  /  0x2771  : You find:


0x7a  /  0x2778  : The octopus waves its arms and you can see. Thus "many hands make light work"!


0x7b  /  0x27ab  : "NOT AUTHORISED TO GO THERE!"
0x7c  /  0x27c9  : It's blocked by a slab of rock
0x7d  /  0x27d9  : You're dead...
0x7e  /  0x27e1  : A boulder rolls on a carpet of moss
0x7f  /  0x27f6  : A mossy lump sits in one corner
0x80  /  0x280a  : The moss moves from walls and floor to the stopped stone
0x81  /  0x2829  : The bolt slides back
0x82  /  0x2834  : You turn one stone and nothing happens
0x83  /  0x284a  : Another stone turned, still nothing
0x84  /  0x285f  : Now no stone is left unturned the slab slides from the doorway
0x85  /  0x287e  : The door is bolted
0x86  /  0x2887  : The bolt barrs the door
0x87  /  0x2893  : An exit appears to the east
0x88  /  0x28a1  : The exit closes again
0x89  /  0x28ad  : An opening leads east
0x8a  /  0x28b8  : RIGHT! Your vision blurs...
0x8b  /  0x28cd  : WRONG! The room heats up...
0x8c  /  0x28de  : There is a square pit in the floor
0x8d  /  0x28f1  : The door is locked!
0x8e  /  0x28fa  : A host of skeletons are guarding a bearded dwarf
0x8f  /  0x2916  : The skeletons are in the way
0x90  /  0x2923  : As you wave the skeleton staff they all clank off, leaving the dwarf. "Thank you", she says, "You saved my life. I've found a rich vein of ore above the stone face and will share it if you visit the area!"
0x91  /  0x299f  : A dwarf is following you


0x92  /  0x29ae  : Armed skeletons leap on you
0x93  /  0x29bf  : A party of skeletons stand to attention as you enter. (Greetings Master), they signal in semaphore, (We have captured an intruder dwarf and await your signals)!
0x94  /  0x2a1f  : "That's not the way to the ore!", cries the dwarf, "I'm not going that way!". Do you turn back?


0x95  /  0x2a58  : The dwarf dives into a hidden opening. You hear 
frantic hammering and cries of "Follow me!"
0x96  /  0x2a8c  : A vampire bites you
0x97  /  0x2a98  : A vampire cowers back
0x98  /  0x2aa6  : The sharp wood kills the vampire
0x99  /  0x2ab7  : "ONLY ARCHERS ALLOWED"
0x9a  /  0x2ace  : You hear a body fall into water far below
0x9b  /  0x2ae1  : A hurled flint splinters in front of your face, 
driving you back
0x9c  /  0x2b07  : The water trickles out. Try a thicker liquid
0x9d  /  0x2b21  : There's nothing to fill it with
0x9e  /  0x2b31  : You scoop up a good pot-full of slime
0x9f  /  0x2b4a  : , full of slime
0xa0  /  0x2b54  : The slime is too sticky!
0xa1  /  0x2b62  : The ground is very slippery


0xa2  /  0x2b71  : A fierce goat is on guard
0xa3  /  0x2b82  : The goat prances daintily about and butts you off the cliff
0xa4  /  0x2ba7  : The goat dances forward but loses its footing and slips off the cliff
0xa5  /  0x2bcf  : 

The pot shatters
0xa6  /  0x2bd9  : , and slime oozes out
0xa7  /  0x2be5  : , only a stump is left
0xa8  /  0x2bf1  : 

The wood flickers
0xa9  /  0x2bfc  : 

The burning branch is going out!
0xaa  /  0x2c0f  : 171
0xab  /  0x2c13  : 172
0xac  /  0x2c17  : 173
0xad  /  0x2c1b  : 174
0xae  /  0x2c1f  : 175
0xaf  /  0x2c23  : 176
0xb0  /  0x2c27  : 177
0xb1  /  0x2c2b  : 178
0xb2  /  0x2c2f  : 179
0xb3  /  0x2c33  : 

You can hear a boulder rolling down from above


0xb4  /  0x2c4f  : 

Sounds of a bounding boulder echo up from below


0xb5  /  0x2c6b  : 

The boulder gets you!
0xb6  /  0x2c78  : 

You're safe when the boulder passes


0xb7  /  0x2c8d  : "OI! YOU CAN ONLY ENTER IF YOU SAY THE PASSWORD!"
0xb8  /  0x2cbe  : "Pass friend!"
0xb9  /  0x2cc9  : The main door north of the bridge is shut
0xba  /  0x2cdd  : Ghostly orcs guard the junction
0xbb  /  0x2cf2  : "You may not pass", intone the ghosts. "We failed the Master and our doom is to remain here whilst He lives."
0xbc  /  0x2d2f  : You catch the will o'wisp in your helmet lamp
0xbd  /  0x2d48  : It evades your clutches
0xbe  /  0x2d59  :  which shines brightly
0xbf  /  0x2d68  : A face looks back: your gaze is locked! You stumble towards it.. then CRUNCH! You tread on a mechanical mask
0xc0  /  0x2da8  : 

A great roc carries you off!
0xc1  /  0x2dbc  : 

A skeletal hand reaches from the earth but crumbles to dust
0xc2  /  0x2dde  : A silken rope emerges!
0xc3  /  0x2dec  : A rope hangs down
0xc4  /  0x2df8  : There's nothing to tie it to
0xc5  /  0x2e07  : An evil force in the gem launches itself at your mind!
0xc6  /  0x2e2a  : 

The gem is attacking your mind


0xc7  /  0x2e3d  : 200
0xc8  /  0x2e41  : A pit opens in the floor!
0xc9  /  0x2e50  : The pit closes
0xca  /  0x2e58  : The room fills briefly with light
0xcb  /  0x2e69  : The entire throne rises through a trapdoor in the ceiling. It comes to rest in an odd little room
0xcc  /  0x2e9b  : The throne sinks back down
0xcd  /  0x2eab  : Alarms sound
0xce  /  0x2eb5  : Fire jets cross the floor!
0xcf  /  0x2ec5  : "Master: I beg to report that all internal eyes 
are dead and enemies are in the caves. Also, thousands of enemy orcs are advancing upon us."
0xd0  /  0x2f0d  : You are somewhere else!
0xd1  /  0x2f1b  : 

A humming black sphere floats in mid-air!
0xd2  /  0x2f37  : Imps clothe you in gold armour and drop you into the sea
0xd3  /  0x2f52  : Searing flames leap up: "You can live for ever by remaining in the fire!" cackles a demon, but you can't of course
0xd4  /  0x2f94  : "While humans are divided there will be war, so 
I will unite them. Your body will serve as a zombi in My army!"
0xd5  /  0x2fd8  : You win a little present
0xd6  /  0x2fe5  : "You'll get nothing all right! No body, no life..."
0xd7  /  0x300a  : , but it's a bomb!
0xd8  /  0x3016  : Your body becomes a pillar of salt!
0xd9  /  0x302a  : The pig dissolves!
0xda  /  0x3037  : A humming black sphere floats in mid-air!
0xdb  /  0x3052  : An army of orcs is camped all around
0xdc  /  0x3067  : The orcs block you


0xdd  /  0x3071  : The orcs run towards you and kill you
0xde  /  0x3082  : 223
0xdf  /  0x3086  : 224
0xe0  /  0x308a  : Warriors spring from the teeth 

0xe1  /  0x309b  : and attack you
0xe2  /  0x30a2  : and kill the orcs
0xe3  /  0x30ab  : The sound reverberates from the hills
0xe4  /  0x30be  :  and the orcs flee!
0xe5  /  0x30c8  : You need a hammer!
0xe6  /  0x30d2  : The gem breaks: you are free!
0xe7  /  0x30e4  : 

Your mind is sucked into the gem


0xe8  /  0x30f5  : The jelly rears up hungrily
0xe9  /  0x3106  : The jellies converge onto it
0xea  /  0x3114  : Globs of carnivorous jelly are circling round
0xeb  /  0x312f  : A mound of jelly wobbles on the floor
0xec  /  0x3143  : A giant rat guards the corridor
0xed  /  0x3155  : The rat flees from the stinking chip!
0xee  /  0x3169  : A fire elemental leaps on you
0xef  /  0x317b  : You clumsily smear cold cream all over yourself
0xf0  /  0x3197  : If you must.. You feel REALLY ILL now
0xf1  /  0x31b2  : It's deadly poison
0xf2  /  0x31be  : It tastes OK
0xf3  /  0x31c5  : It tastes fantastic!
0xf4  /  0x31d1  : 

You feel faint and have a craving for fungi!


0xf5  /  0x31ec  : You collapse, scrabbling for illusory mushrooms
0xf6  /  0x3209  : Wowee!
0xf7  /  0x320e  : . The executioner has been flattened
0xf8  /  0x3224  : 249
0xf9  /  0x3228  : You shrink
0xfa  /  0x322f  : You grow
0xfb  /  0x3234  : You're too big to go that way
0xfc  /  0x3246  : Giant ants block your path, feeling for you with sensitive antenna
0xfd  /  0x3269  : Enormous ants tower overhead as they walk past, 
completely ignoring you
0xfe  /  0x3295  : You accidentally step on some little ants
0xff  /  0x32af  : 

A ghoul emerges from the dark and eats you!
0x100  /  0x32c8  : 
0x101  /  0x32c9  : A rotting bridge leads north
0x102  /  0x32d6  : A fine golden pathway leads north
0x103  /  0x32e7  : The troll sees you and throws you out!
0x104  /  0x32fc  : You are invisible!
0x105  /  0x3307  : 

You are visible again!


0x106  /  0x3316  : A troll blocks the bridge, palm outstretched for payment
0x107  /  0x333a  : The troll takes it and leaves, gloating
0x108  /  0x334e  : No one here wants it!
0x109  /  0x335c  : "Not valuable enough! Have it back!"
0x10a  /  0x3375  : The troll's bad breath drives you back!
0x10b  /  0x338c  : Spikes shoot from the wall
0x10c  /  0x339b  :  
but bounce off your shield
0x10d  /  0x33b0  : Acid sprays at your eyes
0x10e  /  0x33c0  :  
but only destroys the blindfold
0x10f  /  0x33d6  : ! You fall backwards
0x110  /  0x33e2  : As the elephant grows, a roc swoops and carries 
it off
0x111  /  0x3406  : The elephant tries to grow to full size but there's no room. It implodes
0x112  /  0x342e  : A hooded executioner blocks the only exit
0x113  /  0x3446  : The executioner attacks
0x114  /  0x3455  : Nothing here's worth closing
0x115  /  0x3464  : You can't move!
0x116  /  0x346f  : You try to fly off the ramp
0x117  /  0x347e  : Now YOU can take the executioner's place!
0x118  /  0x349a  : Several wights are trying to get at you
0x119  /  0x34ae  : You force the wights back
0x11a  /  0x34bb  :  but they come from all sides..
0x11b  /  0x34cf  : 

A horde of wights attack!
0x11c  /  0x34df  : You need a hammer and nails
0x11d  /  0x34ee  : It is slightly ajar
0x11e  /  0x34fb  : It is nailed shut
0x11f  /  0x3506  : You nail the coffin tight shut
0x120  /  0x351a  : A zombi shambles from the coffin and attacks!
0x121  /  0x3536  : The walls at the far end clash together
0x122  /  0x354b  : The walls near you grind together
0x123  /  0x355c  :  but they're wedged!
0x124  /  0x356a  : 293
0x125  /  0x356e  : Iron bars slam down to block your escape
0x126  /  0x3586  : The bars lift
0x127  /  0x358e  : 296
0x128  /  0x3592  : A drowned snake floats from the box
0x129  /  0x35a9  : 

A black sphere follows you
0x12a  /  0x35bb  : 

The black spheres destroy each other
0x12b  /  0x35d1  : A snake leaps out and strikes!
0x12c  /  0x35e3  : a long-handelled axe
0x12d  /  0x35f1  : a small berry
0x12e  /  0x35fa  : a leather blindfold
0x12f  /  0x3607  : a dead body
0x130  /  0x3610  : a short bow
0x131  /  0x3618  : a small ornate box with a lid
0x132  /  0x362a  : a piece of resinous driftwood
0x133  /  0x363e  : a leather gauntlet
0x134  /  0x364b  : a small hammer
0x135  /  0x3654  : 
0x136  /  0x3655  : a bag of nails
0x137  /  0x3660  : a salt pig
0x138  /  0x3668  : a cracked pot
0x139  /  0x3671  : a sliver of rancid fried potato
0x13a  /  0x3683  : some silken rope
0x13b  /  0x368d  : a shield
0x13c  /  0x3694  : a wedge of wood
0x13d  /  0x369d  : 318
0x13e  /  0x36a1  : 319
0x13f  /  0x36a5  : 320
0x140  /  0x36a9  : an obscure ethnic carving
0x141  /  0x36bb  : an antique chair
0x142  /  0x36c6  : a securely fastened chest
0x143  /  0x36d8  : a selection of coins
0x144  /  0x36e5  : a jade egg
0x145  /  0x36ef  : a matched pair of lapis lazuli
0x146  /  0x3702  : a jewelled needle
0x147  /  0x370e  : an onyx oryx
0x148  /  0x3718  : a lump of valuable ore
0x149  /  0x3726  : a rock crystal
0x14a  /  0x3730  : a star pendant
0x14b  /  0x373b  : a sun medallion
0x14c  /  0x3745  : a very expensive trident
0x14d  /  0x3755  : 
0x14e  /  0x3756  : 
0x14f  /  0x3757  : an agate
0x150  /  0x375d  : an amethyst
0x151  /  0x3765  : a diamond
0x152  /  0x376c  : an emerald
0x153  /  0x3773  : an opal
0x154  /  0x3779  : a pearl
0x155  /  0x377f  : a valuable rhinestone
0x156  /  0x378e  : a ruby
0x157  /  0x3794  : a sapphire
0x158  /  0x379d  : a topaz
0x159  /  0x37a3  : a cube of "sticky" metal
0x15a  /  0x37b3  : rare spices
0x15b  /  0x37ba  : a hollow stick
0x15c  /  0x37c3  : a gilt miner's helmet with a lamp
0x15d  /  0x37d8  : 350
0x15e  /  0x37dc  : a golden bed
0x15f  /  0x37e4  : a good, strong belt
0x160  /  0x37f1  : a veneered cross
0x161  /  0x37fd  : a jewel-encrusted crucifix
0x162  /  0x3811  : a great horn, bound by metal hoops
0x163  /  0x3829  : a broken mechanical face
0x164  /  0x3839  : a magical mirror
0x165  /  0x3844  : a cuddley octopus figurine
0x166  /  0x3858  : a staff of polished bone
0x167  /  0x3867  : a magic sword
0x168  /  0x3870  : a magic wand
0x169  /  0x3878  : 
0x16a  /  0x3879  : 
0x16b  /  0x387a  : a weighted dice
0x16c  /  0x3884  : a white elephant brooch
0x16d  /  0x3895  : a giant caterpillar grub
0x16e  /  0x38a3  : a big packing case
0x16f  /  0x38af  : a dry poppy seed-pod
0x170  /  0x38c0  : a will o'wisp
0x171  /  0x38ca  : 
0x172  /  0x38cb  : a red collar
0x173  /  0x38d1  : an orange collar
0x174  /  0x38d9  : a yellow collar
0x175  /  0x38e1  : a green collar
0x176  /  0x38e8  : a blue collar
0x177  /  0x38ef  : a violet collar
0x178  /  0x38f8  : a silver collar
0x179  /  0x3900  : a mithril collar
0x17a  /  0x3908  : a jar of cold cream
0x17b  /  0x3914  : a hangman's hood
0x17c  /  0x391f  : a red-gold ring
0x17d  /  0x392a  : a set of dragon's teeth
0x17e  /  0x3938  : a livid green gem
0x17f  /  0x3944  : a glass key enscribed "This game is copyright (C) Level 9 Computing 1982 and was created by Peter R J Austin".
0x180  /  0x398e  : 
0x181  /  0x398f  : 
0x182  /  0x3990  : 
0x183  /  0x3991  : 
0x184  /  0x3992  : 
0x185  /  0x3993  : 
0x186  /  0x3994  : A long-handelled axe lies nearby
0x187  /  0x39a8  : A ripe berry is within reach
0x188  /  0x39b8  : A blindfold lies nearby
0x189  /  0x39c7  : A corpse is slumped on the ground
0x18a  /  0x39d7  : A short bow is here
0x18b  /  0x39e0  : A small ornate box lies nearby
0x18c  /  0x39f2  : There is a piece of driftwood here
0x18d  /  0x3a07  : A gauntlet lies on the floor
0x18e  /  0x3a16  : There is a hammer here
0x18f  /  0x3a23  : 
0x190  /  0x3a24  : A bag of nails lies on the floor
0x191  /  0x3a35  : A small salt pig stands on the ground
0x192  /  0x3a45  : A cracked pot is pushed into a corner
0x193  /  0x3a5a  : A sliver of rancid fried potato is stuck to the 
floor
0x194  /  0x3a78  : A silken rope lies in a heap
0x195  /  0x3a87  : A wooden shield is propped against a wall
0x196  /  0x3a9e  : A wooden wedge lies nearby
0x197  /  0x3aad  : 
0x198  /  0x3aae  : 
0x199  /  0x3aaf  : 
0x19a  /  0x3ab0  : An ethnic carving lies nearby
0x19b  /  0x3ac1  : An antique chair is here
0x19c  /  0x3acf  : A securely-fastened treasure chest is here
0x19d  /  0x3ae6  : An assortment of coins is here
0x19e  /  0x3af8  : A large jade egg is here
0x19f  /  0x3b06  : A pair of lapis lazuli stand nearby
0x1a0  /  0x3b1c  : A jewelled needle is on the ground
0x1a1  /  0x3b2c  : A small onyx oryx stands on the ground
0x1a2  /  0x3b3f  : A lump of valuable ore lies nearby
0x1a3  /  0x3b53  : A large rock crystal is here
0x1a4  /  0x3b61  : There is a star pendant here
0x1a5  /  0x3b72  : There is a sun medallion here
0x1a6  /  0x3b82  : A costly trident rusts nearby
0x1a7  /  0x3b94  : 
0x1a8  /  0x3b95  : 
0x1a9  /  0x3b96  : An agate is here
0x1aa  /  0x3b9f  : An amethyst is here
0x1ab  /  0x3baa  : A diamond is here
0x1ac  /  0x3bb3  : An emerald is here
0x1ad  /  0x3bbc  : An opal is here
0x1ae  /  0x3bc4  : A pearl is here
0x1af  /  0x3bcb  : A large valuable rhinestone is here
0x1b0  /  0x3bde  : A ruby is here
0x1b1  /  0x3be5  : A sapphire is here
0x1b2  /  0x3bf0  : A topaz is here
0x1b3  /  0x3bf8  : A small cube of metal rests on the ground
0x1b4  /  0x3c0a  : Some rare spices are here
0x1b5  /  0x3c17  : A hollow stick is on the ground
0x1b6  /  0x3c25  : A gilt miner's helmet lies nearby
0x1b7  /  0x3c3a  : 
0x1b8  /  0x3c3b  : A golden four-poster bed almost fills the room
0x1b9  /  0x3c54  : A good strong belt lies coiled on the ground
0x1ba  /  0x3c6b  : A wooden cross lies nearby
0x1bb  /  0x3c7b  : A small jewelled crucifix rests nearby
0x1bc  /  0x3c92  : A large horn lies on the ground
0x1bd  /  0x3ca0  : A battered silver face lies on the ground
0x1be  /  0x3cb3  : A silver mirror lies nearby
0x1bf  /  0x3cc4  : A cute little octopus figurine stands nearby
0x1c0  /  0x3ce1  : A staff of polished bone is here
0x1c1  /  0x3cf1  : A great sword is thrust into the stone
0x1c2  /  0x3d04  : A magic wand is here
0x1c3  /  0x3d0e  : 
0x1c4  /  0x3d0f  : 
0x1c5  /  0x3d10  : A dice rests on the ground
0x1c6  /  0x3d1c  : An elephant brooch stands nearby
0x1c7  /  0x3d32  : A huge caterpillar wriggles nearby
0x1c8  /  0x3d47  : A huge packing case, open at one end, rests on the ground
0x1c9  /  0x3d65  : A dry poppy seed pod lies nearby
0x1ca  /  0x3d7a  : A little will o'wisp floats forlornely
0x1cb  /  0x3d93  : 
0x1cc  /  0x3d94  : A red collar is here
0x1cd  /  0x3d9c  : An orange collar is here
0x1ce  /  0x3da6  : A yellow collar is here
0x1cf  /  0x3daf  : A green collar is here
0x1d0  /  0x3db8  : A blue collar is here
0x1d1  /  0x3dc1  : A violet collar is here
0x1d2  /  0x3dcb  : A silver collar is here
0x1d3  /  0x3dd4  : A mithril collar is here!
0x1d4  /  0x3ddf  : A jar of cold cream is here
0x1d5  /  0x3dec  : A black hood with eye-holes lies nearby
0x1d6  /  0x3e03  : A gold rings rolls on the ground
0x1d7  /  0x3e13  : A set of dragon's teeth lies on the ground
0x1d8  /  0x3e27  : An evil glowing green gem is here!
0x1d9  /  0x3e39  : 
0x1da  /  0x3e3a  : 
0x1db  /  0x3e3b  : The cube sticks to metal
0x1dc  /  0x3e49  : The spices are very old
0x1dd  /  0x3e54  : The stick emits a clear note when blown
0x1de  /  0x3e6a  : The helmet lamp has neither fuel nor wick
0x1df  /  0x3e82  : 
0x1e0  /  0x3e83  : It shrinks when lifted
0x1e1  /  0x3e91  : Your fingers seem to swell as you handle the belt
0x1e2  /  0x3eac  : The cross should be effective against some kinds of undead
0x1e3  /  0x3ecd  : The crucifix should be effective against some kinds of undead
0x1e4  /  0x3ef2  : The horn is decorated with pictures of fleeing enemies
0x1e5  /  0x3f0e  : As you handle the mask, a fine dust of tiny cogs trickles out
0x1e6  /  0x3f32  : "This mirror reflects more than it should"
0x1e7  /  0x3f4e  : The octopus is sickeningly cute, with eight hands and babyish eyes
0x1e8  /  0x3f77  : The staff is covered with matckstick drawings
0x1e9  /  0x3f90  : A dragon design runs along the blade
0x1ea  /  0x3fa6  : The wand has Z-runes carved along it
0x1eb  /  0x3fbc  : 
0x1ec  /  0x3fbd  : 
0x1ed  /  0x3fbe  : The dice is weighted and inscribed "I know I'm a die"
0x1ee  /  0x3fdf  : The elephant is VERY realistic
0x1ef  /  0x3ff2  : It exudes silk
0x1f0  /  0x3ffc  : The case is big enough to crawl inside
0x1f1  /  0x4012  : As you examine the pod, some seeds fall out and 
explode noisily
0x1f2  /  0x403a  : The will o'wisp is small and glows brightly
0x1f3  /  0x4050  : 
0x1f4  /  0x4051  : north of the dry swamp, below a cliff and east of a deep chasm
0x1f5  /  0x406e  : north of the dry marsh, below a sheer cliff
0x1f6  /  0x4083  : on a small mound, surrounded by fallen stones
0x1f7  /  0x409a  : beside a muddy puddle
0x1f8  /  0x40a7  : on powdery peat beside a north-south chasm
0x1f9  /  0x40bb  : on a mound of rubble
0x1fa  /  0x40c7  : on dry, powdery peat
0x1fb  /  0x40d3  : below a ramp up the outside of the black tower. 
Powdery peat leads north
0x1fc  /  0x40f6  : at the top of the "straight stairs", a short distance below a gate-house
0x1fd  /  0x411c  : half-way up the "straight stairs"
0x1fe  /  0x4130  : below the "straight stairs"
0x1ff  /  0x413e  : in a gully above the "winding stairs"
0x200  /  0x4153  : on the "winding stairs", carved into exposed rock
0x201  /  0x416d  : on the "winding stairs", leading across a vertical slab of exposed rock
0x202  /  0x4193  : in a sheltered gully below a winding staircase
0x203  /  0x41ab  : on a sturdy branch over the clearing
0x204  /  0x41bf  : in a forest clearing
0x205  /  0x41ca  : at the edge of the forest, beneath a particularly large tree. You can just glimpse a large clearing to the north
0x206  /  0x4200  : on the edge of the forest. You can go no further
0x207  /  0x4217  : on an east-west road south of the river. A gigantic orc's head is carved into the cliff north of the river, its tongue forming a bridge over the waters to you. A ruined tower stands on top of 
the cliff
0x208  /  0x4276  : on an east-west road through the forest
0x209  /  0x428a  : on an east-west road through the forest
0x20a  /  0x429e  : within a circle of distorted monoliths, etched into grotesque figures by the acid rain. Lightning arcs overhead, revealing the stark horror of this haunted place, while thunder echoes from every crag
0x20b  /  0x4313  : on the side of a steep hill which rises into the clouds. Rumblings emanate from above
0x20c  /  0x4342  : on a grassy plain
0x20d  /  0x434d  : below a small mound which is completely dwarfed 
by a huge untidy nest
0x20e  /  0x4377  : on the edge of the forest
0x20f  /  0x4381  : in a clump of bushes on the edge of the forest
0x210  /  0x4395  : in a round room with large windows and no doors. A narrow ladder leads down beneath a green pedestal
0x211  /  0x43c9  : below a tower of polished marble
0x212  /  0x43db  : in a huge nest
0x213  /  0x43e3  : on a grassy plain which seems to go on for ever
0x214  /  0x43ff  : on a wide stone bridge which stretches north-south across the placid waters of a huge river. At 
the north end, the bridge enters a gaping stone 
mouth in the cliff
0x215  /  0x444f  : outside the gatehouse
0x216  /  0x445a  : on a smooth rock dome, below a narrow path
0x217  /  0x4471  : in a crumbling stone ear. Great lumps of rock have sloughed off and you can go no further
0x218  /  0x44a2  : on the shattered right cheek of the great stone 
face
0x219  /  0x44bb  : standing on an enormous stone nose, projecting far out over the river below. To the south, at the end of the nose, is a large white building dwarfed to the apparant size of a pimple, and above is a great rock dome
0x21a  /  0x4529  : on the left cheek of the great stone face
0x21b  /  0x453c  : in a stone left ear. Paths lead west and into the rock
0x21c  /  0x4555  : in an arch-way below the gate-house. A bridge leads north to the foot of a shattered black tower. A violet pedestal stands to one side of the arch
0x21d  /  0x45a0  : on a narrow north-south bridge
0x21e  /  0x45b1  : in a sloping passage
0x21f  /  0x45ba  : on a ramp down the black tower
0x220  /  0x45cb  : on a dead-end flight of shattered steps
0x221  /  0x45e3  : in the roc's nest, where it brings "food" for storage
0x222  /  0x4604  : south of the river, on the edge of a vast field 
of poppies which stretches west as far as the eye can see. A somnolant perfume hangs heavy on the breeze
0x223  /  0x4655  : on an east-west road, south of the river and north of a steep, treeless hill
0x224  /  0x4674  : on an east-west road beside the river and north 
of a flat grassy plain. A line of stepping stones leads to a small island in the water
0x225  /  0x46b0  : on a mud-bank, north of a wide river. A stone bridge spans the waters, reaching from the granite cliffs above to the flat lands of the far bank, and a path climbs up to it
0x226  /  0x4709  : under the killer-willow tree
0x227  /  0x4718  : on the southern end of a small island, reached by stepping stones from the south. The far end of the island is occupied by a viscious-looking willow tree with six long rubbery branches
0x228  /  0x477c  : on stepping stones leading north to an island
0x229  /  0x4791  : on the floor of a cavern, beside a clump of evil green toadstools. Liquid slime oozes from the north and paths lead south and up
0x22a  /  0x47cf  : in the middle of the floor of a giant cove, in a giant ants' nest. Small footprints lead north and south
0x22b  /  0x4800  : North of the cave floor, below a huge grey mushroom
0x22c  /  0x4819  : at the end of an aqueduct designed to drip water evenly into the depths of a deep pit below. The aqueduct leads north, a narrow fissure leads south, and steps lead down into the pit
0x22d  /  0x4873  : walking on the bed of an empty aqueduct which crosses a vast dark pit
0x22e  /  0x489a  : in a damp north-south pipe
0x22f  /  0x48a7  : on an aqueduct
0x230  /  0x48b1  : in a paved tunnel below a silver pedestal. Water trickles from a silver hoop painted on one wall and seeps south. An armoured door leads east and a crack splits the north wall
0x231  /  0x4909  : standing in shallow water at the foot of the ramp. A ladder slopes northwards to a higher part of the ramp
0x232  /  0x4937  : on a wide spiral ramp which descends clockwise round an immense pit. A small dark tunnel leads north. But these are matters of little significance for the north wall of the tunnel is covered with a miriad moving images of writhing tormented creatures and your gaze is locked on them. Your sanity is draining away!! If you don't act quickly your soul will be captured by the wall
0x233  /  0x49fe  : on the ramp which descends clockwise around the 
edges of a very deep pit. To the east is an opening into a red-gold room
0x234  /  0x4a3a  : on the ramp, beside a doorway with small holes up one edge
0x235  /  0x4a55  : on the ramp, outside a dark doorway
0x236  /  0x4a61  : on a loose section of the ramp
0x237  /  0x4a6f  : on the ramp, outside a round opening
0x238  /  0x4a7e  : on a wobbly section of the ramp
0x239  /  0x4a8f  : on the ramp, outside a long room with scratches 
on floor and ceiling
0x23a  /  0x4aaf  : on the ramp. A hand sign points into a narrow opening
0x23b  /  0x4acc  : on the ramp, outside a narrow doorway from which drifts a sharp, acrid smell
0x23c  /  0x4af3  : on the ramp, outside a rubbery doorway
0x23d  /  0x4b02  : pn the ramp, outside a square doorway
0x23e  /  0x4b11  : on the ramp, outside an opening to a pale room
0x23f  /  0x4b23  : on the ramp, outside an evil dark entrance
0x240  /  0x4b37  : on the ramp. A ladder slopes southwards to a lower part of the ramp
0x241  /  0x4b54  : on the ramp. A sign over a doorway reads: "Congratulations! You have won a uniquely valuable reward! Just walk in and answer a simple question to claim your prize!"
0x242  /  0x4baf  : You are on deadly slime, slipping towards the edge of the ramp


0x243  /  0x4bcd  : on the ramp outside an ornate entrance. The ramp above looks dodgy
0x244  /  0x4bf0  : on the ramp. A doorway bears the following message: "To escape the dungeon, collect 9 gems and go through this door. Leaving without the gems will cause your death". Clearly you must be in the central dungeon of the Demon Lord!
0x245  /  0x4c6b  : on the ramp, outside a doorway
0x246  /  0x4c76  : on the ramp
0x247  /  0x4c7a  : on a massive spiral ramp which twists down into 
dark waters and up into the gloom above. Sea-spray wafts from a nearby doorway
0x248  /  0x4cc3  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of red light
0x249  /  0x4ce8  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of orange light
0x24a  /  0x4d0e  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of yellow light
0x24b  /  0x4d33  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of green light
0x24c  /  0x4d59  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of blue light
0x24d  /  0x4d80  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of violet light
0x24e  /  0x4da8  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of impenetrable darkness
0x24f  /  0x4dd5  : standing on a small round platform surrounded by a cylinder of silvery light
0x250  /  0x4dfc  : sitting on an ornate throne. There are nine numbered buttons along the left arm-rest
0x251  /  0x4e2b  : just inside the entrance to the wight house, at 
the northwest corner of a large gloomy room with four pillars. The nearest pillar has fallen and blocks your way south. In the middle of the southern wall is a shadowey alcove
0x252  /  0x4e97  : in the middle of the north wall of the wight house
0x253  /  0x4eab  : in the northeast corner
0x254  /  0x4eb5  : in the middle of the east wall
0x255  /  0x4ec2  : in the middle of the wight house, below a blue pedestal
0x256  /  0x4ede  : in the middle of the west wall. The way north is blocked by a fallen pillar
0x257  /  0x4eff  : in the southwest corner
0x258  /  0x4f09  : in the middle of the south wall of the wight house. A musty alcove opens behind you
0x259  /  0x4f33  : in the southeast corner
0x25a  /  0x4f3d  : in the crypt, beside a rotting coffin
0x25b  /  0x4f52  : in a long throne room lined with skin. There is 
a large doorway in the middle of each wall and a central granite throne
0x25c  /  0x4f8f  : in an odd little room, below a granite throne
0x25d  /  0x4fa7  : at a bend in a corridor which goes west and south
0x25e  /  0x4fbf  : in an east-west corridor beside an opening to the north
0x25f  /  0x4fd4  : in a blocked corridor
0x260  /  0x4fdf  : in a north-south corridor which ends at a t-junction
0x261  /  0x4ffd  : on a steep flight of stairs
0x262  /  0x500d  : in the pit: a large pentagonal room, blackened by some past explosion and with a wide crack in the east wall
0x263  /  0x5042  : in a cylindrical room with eight exits, hewn from the rock. A pride of lions is carved over the 
north door
0x264  /  0x5079  : dead-end room, painted matt black. You'll have to return the way you came
0x265  /  0x509d  : in a second dead-end black room
0x266  /  0x50ad  : at the west of a long room with many pillars. The only exit is at the other end
0x267  /  0x50d3  : at the east end of a long room. Its roof is supported by dozens of stone pillars
0x268  /  0x50fb  : in an empty stable with exits to east and west
0x269  /  0x5112  : in a rough-hewn store room, filled by a haystack
0x26a  /  0x512e  : at a junction in a steeply sloping u-shaped passage which leads northeast and northwest. Three round rocks protrude beside an opening to the east
0x26b  /  0x5178  : in a damp hemispherical cave with an opening to 
the east
0x26c  /  0x5193  : a room carved out of rugged rock with a large outcrop of stone in the middle of the floor. There is an exit to the west
0x26d  /  0x51cd  : on a flight of crumbling steps
0x26e  /  0x51e0  : in a steep earthy passage
0x26f  /  0x51ed  : in the lower chamber. There are 6 exits
0x270  /  0x5200  : in the upper chamber, warmed by a current of rising air. Openings lead southeast, southwest and 
down
0x271  /  0x5237  : in a round passage, blocked by a large rounded stone which is covered by a pattern of swirling grooves. There is an orange pedestal in the centre of the NE-SW passage
0x272  /  0x528d  : at a tight junction above a narrow pit
0x273  /  0x52a6  : in a tall cavern with a large central fireplace 
and a wide brick chimney leading upwards. There 
are openings all around
0x274  /  0x52e9  : in an oppressive chimney
0x275  /  0x52fa  : outside a glowing alcove
0x276  /  0x5307  : at a blockage in the chimney
0x277  /  0x5318  : in a dry north-south fissure, apparantly blocked at the southern end
0x278  /  0x533b  : at the end of a long east-west corridor lined with worn flagstones. A yellow pedestal stands in 
the middle of the road and doorways lead north and south
0x279  /  0x537d  : in a long east-west corridor with doorways to north and south
0x27a  /  0x5397  : at the junction where the corridor ends
0x27b  /  0x53ae  : in a neat panelled room. There is a walk-in cupboard to the south, a wide doorway to the east and narrow openings west and down
0x27c  /  0x53ec  : in a cupboard
0x27d  /  0x53f5  : in a filthy, dead-end cell
0x27e  /  0x5403  : in a filthy, dead-end cell
0x27f  /  0x5411  : in a filthy, dead-end cell
0x280  /  0x541f  : in a filthy, dead-end cell
0x281  /  0x542d  : in a filthy, dead-end cell
0x282  /  0x543b  : in a filthy, dead-end cell
0x283  /  0x5449  : in a crude narrow east-west corridor, hacked out of the rock
0x284  /  0x5467  : at a junction between north-south and east-west 
passages
0x285  /  0x5486  : beside a rockfall which blocks the passage
0x286  /  0x549a  : in the armoury. The weapons have rusted away, leaving stains on walls and floor
0x287  /  0x54c3  : in a looted toolroom
0x288  /  0x54cd  : in an empty store-cave
0x289  /  0x54dc  : climbing a flight of narrow, cramped steps
0x28a  /  0x54f7  : at a dead-end.
0x28b  /  0x5501  : in a giant, vacant, rats nest
0x28c  /  0x5513  : in a damp, musty north-south corridor
0x28d  /  0x5525  : clinging to a rock-face
0x28e  /  0x5534  : on a wide ledge half-way up the south side of a 
tall cave. Steps lead up and down. Several small, brightly patterned, psychaedelic mushrooms grow at the back of the ledge
0x28f  /  0x5593  : clinging to crumbling steps up the rock wall
0x290  /  0x55ab  : on a magnificent golden pathway running north-south through the air
0x291  /  0x55d1  : on a narrow ledge between the splendid golden pathway and a narrow tunnel
0x292  /  0x55fc  : in a narrow north-south passage through the rock. A peculiar sweet smell emerges from an opening to the west
0x293  /  0x5634  : in the troll's squalid store room, amidst junk of every kind. Astrological symbols and slogans cover the walls and a cloying incense smell clogs your nostrils. The only exit is east, between clumps of tasty pink mushrooms. The troll is slumped in a stupor in one corner
0x294  /  0x56c2  : on a wide ledge outside a tunnel entrance. A wooden bridge leads north across a deep cavern and 
steps lead up and down
0x295  /  0x5701  : on a sturdy bridge across a cave
0x296  /  0x5714  : on a wide ledge between a sturdy bridge and a fissure in the rock. You keep bumping into objects that you can't see
0x297  /  0x5754  : in a small fissure that narrows as it winds north
0x298  /  0x576e  : crawling through tiny cracks which lead west and south
0x299  /  0x578d  : in the strong room. An iron door leads west and 
a narrow crack splits the east wall
0x29a  /  0x57b6  : on cliff steps, broken by rock-falls
0x29b  /  0x57cd  : south a vast cavern floor, beside some small grey mushrooms. Tiny footprints lead north
0x29c  /  0x57f8  : in a viewing gallery over a deep pit. A chute leads down
0x29d  /  0x5818  : below a sign "Your fate is sealed! Your only hope is to descend into the Central Dungeon and collect 9 gems. Succeed and you will be free!"
0x29e  /  0x5868  : in a dead-end dark room
0x29f  /  0x5874  : in a dead-end dark room, below a black pedastal
0x2a0  /  0x588d  : in a treasure chamber
0x2a1  /  0x5898  : in the west crusher room beside a door into a treasure chamber
0x2a2  /  0x58b3  : in the east crusher room beside an opening back 
to the ramp
0x2a3  /  0x58cd  : in a circular room of red-gold metal.

Gold rings cover the floor
0x2a4  /  0x58f3  : in a dead end, below a gallows tree from which a bloodless corpse hangs by one foot
0x2a5  /  0x5922  : on the brink of a deep, dark pit
0x2a6  /  0x5932  : in a deep, eerie-dark pit
0x2a7  /  0x5942  : in a small soft room between five large round fleshy pillars
0x2a8  /  0x5963  : in a dusty room, entered from the west and with 
a long shelf along the east wall
0x2a9  /  0x598a  : in a short east-west corridor
0x2aa  /  0x5998  : in a room surfaced with black glass
0x2ab  /  0x59aa  : in the box room
0x2ac  /  0x59b2  : in the condemned cell. The only way out is to go west
0x2ad  /  0x59cd  : in the guard room. An exit leads north
0x2ae  /  0x59de  : in the "Skinner box": a blank room with no way out - just nine buttons in a vertical line up one wall. The buttons are numbered 1 to 9 and a discrete notice reads "choose the best"
0x2af  /  0x5a44  : in the reward room. This is empty too and has only 5 numbered buttons, labelled as follows...

 1: Great wealth;

 2: Eternal life;

 3: World peace;

 4: Mystery prize;

 5: Nothing.

A sign invites you to choose your prize
0x2b0  /  0x5acf  : in the statue room. An incomprehensible abstract sculpture of hoops, spirals and loops sprawls around on a small circular platform in the middle of the floor. The entrance is to the west
0x2b1  /  0x5b30  : in an ornate, dead-end room
0x2b2  /  0x5b3d  : in the "Exit" chamber. You seem to have survived the Central Dungeon! There is only one way out...
0x2b3  /  0x5b76  : in an empty room
0x2b4  /  0x5b7e  : in an empty room
0x2b5  /  0x5b86  : in a treasure vault. A low crawl leads west
0x2b6  /  0x5b9f  : in the Salt Cellar, surrounded by pillars of salt
0x2b7  /  0x5bb8  : 696
0x2b8  /  0x5bbc  : 697
0x2b9  /  0x5bc0  : 698
0x2ba  /  0x5bc4  : 699
0x2bb  /  0x5bc8  : on the ceiling of a fine room. A chandelier lies beside you and the floor of the room is far above
0x2bc  /  0x5bf4  : on the carpetted floor of a comfortable homely room, beside a door to the east.
0x2bd  /  0x5c17  : in a large store room. You realise that this is 
the ideal place to leave any treasures that you 
find, so as to get full points for them. Doors lead west and to the outside. A machine resembling a six-foot cube with a single red button sits 
in one corner
0x2be  /  0x5c9f  : in a smooth, round north-south passage. A flickering light is visible to the north
0x2bf  /  0x5cc2  : at a junction in the round, north-south passage, illuminated by a jet of flame from the floor.

To the east is a treasure vault, completely filled with valuables of every kind
0x2c0  /  0x5d20  : in a north-south passage. A dry red stain spreads from beneath a fallen stone
0x2c1  /  0x5d46  : in a hot alcove, lit by the flames of a fire elemental
0x2c2  /  0x5d64  : in a huge cave of glistering rock. New passages 
lead north and south
0x2c3  /  0x5d82  : in a corridor bending south and east
0x2c4  /  0x5d90  : at the bottom of a deep chasm where the earth has been split assunder by a massive explosion. Narrow cracks lead west and down
0x2c5  /  0x5dd5  : in the right eye-socket of the stone face
0x2c6  /  0x5dec  : in the left eye-socket of the stone face
0x2c7  /  0x5e03  : in a wide, smelly passage opening to the outside, high above the river
0x2c8  /  0x5e28  : in a winding, sticky east-west passage to the outside
0x2c9  /  0x5e43  : in a winding, sticky east-west passage to the outside
0x2ca  /  0x5e5e  : inside a large wooden box. A small door leads deeper into the box
0x2cb  /  0x5e7d  : in a gloomy cavern, between rows of jagged, pointed stalagmites. A fetid odour drifts from a wide round passage to the north
0x2cc  /  0x5ec1  : 717
0x2cd  /  0x5ec5  : 718
0x2ce  /  0x5ec9  : 719
0x2cf  /  0x5ecd  : in Valhalla
0x2d0  /  0x5ed5  : in Hades
0x2d1  /  0x5edc  : You fall headlong into a deep pit...
0x2d2  /  0x5ef1  : No way, the water is full of pirahnas!
0x2d3  /  0x5f06  : in Limbo
0x2d4  /  0x5f0e  : in the repository for bugs
0x2d5  /  0x5f1e  : A hollow voice intones: "This is your referee speaking. If you continue on this road you will return safe to civilisation and the game will end. Are you sure that you want to?"


0x2d6  /  0x5f84  : The poppy scent overcomes you...
0x2d7  /  0x5f99  : The ground is too slippery!
0x2d8  /  0x5fa8  : 
0x2d9  /  0x5fa9  : The rings dodge
0x2da  /  0x5fb4  : The ring grabs your finger and grows rapidly..

You shrink rapidly..
0x2db  /  0x5fdc  : A flying hand throttles you
0x2dc  /  0x5fed  : The ring lands in the hand room. You hear a struggle, then silence
0x600b 0x2
0x7405
