Data length: 27135
0x0  /  0x2082  :  
0x1  /  0x2084  :  

0x2  /  0x2086  : 
0x3  /  0x2087  : , 

0x4  /  0x208a  : . 

0x5  /  0x208d  : 


0x6  /  0x208f  :  and 

0x7  /  0x2094  : .


0x8  /  0x2097  : north
0x9  /  0x209b  : northeast
0xa  /  0x20a1  : east
0xb  /  0x20a4  : south
0xc  /  0x20a6  : southeast
0xd  /  0x20ac  : southwest
0xe  /  0x20b0  : west
0xf  /  0x20b3  : northwest
0x10  /  0x20b9  : up
0x11  /  0x20bc  : down
0x12  /  0x20c0  : in
0x13  /  0x20c2  : out
0x14  /  0x20c5  : across
0x15  /  0x20c9  : Exits are 

0x16  /  0x20d1  :  (through a door)
0x17  /  0x20db  :  (through an open door)
0x18  /  0x20e9  : 

You are 

0x19  /  0x20ee  : You own 

0x1a  /  0x20f3  : And you're wearing 

0x1b  /  0x2101  : You can see 

0x1c  /  0x2108  : 

What now?
0x1d  /  0x2110  : I don't understand
0x1e  /  0x211c  : Eh?
0x1f  /  0x2120  : Arfle barfle gloop?
0x20  /  0x212e  : You'll need to say more than that!
0x21  /  0x2143  : Could you elaborate?
0x22  /  0x2152  : Sorry, I can't guess what you mean
0x23  /  0x2169  : Could you rephrase that?
0x24  /  0x2179  : Please be more specific
0x25  /  0x2187  : I don't quite understand
0x26  /  0x2197  : Keep it simple, please
0x27  /  0x21a6  : You can't.
0x28  /  0x21ad  : Don't be silly!
0x29  /  0x21b7  : You can't see
0x2a  /  0x21bf  : You don't have
0x2b  /  0x21c8  : You already have 

0x2c  /  0x21d3  : You can't carry any more
0x2d  /  0x21e1  : You can't take
0x2e  /  0x21ea  : You can't wear
0x2f  /  0x21f3  : You're carrying too much to take
0x30  /  0x2209  : 
0x31  /  0x220a  : 
0x32  /  0x220b  : Nothing happens
0x33  /  0x2216  : Doesn't seem to work
0x34  /  0x2225  : There's no effect
0x35  /  0x2232  : Really stop?
0x36  /  0x223b  : 

Another game?
0x37  /  0x2246  : Really restore?
0x38  /  0x2250  : 

YES or NO, please
0x39  /  0x225e  : 

You score 

0x3a  /  0x2265  :  out of 1000
0x3b  /  0x226e  : Sorry, I can't tell you any more
0x3c  /  0x2282  :  nothing.


0x3d  /  0x228a  : You can't go in that direction
0x3e  /  0x229b  : You bump into a door
0x3f  /  0x22a5  : The door closes behind you
0x40  /  0x22b2  : It's already open
0x41  /  0x22be  : It's already closed
0x42  /  0x22cb  : There's nothing to open
0x43  /  0x22d8  : There's nothing to close
0x44  /  0x22e5  : Only a fool would attack
0x45  /  0x22f5  : You find nothing
0x46  /  0x22ff  : The only visible exit is 

0x47  /  0x230f  : 
0x48  /  0x2310  :  tied together
0x49  /  0x2318  :  which is open
0x4a  /  0x2321  :  (one match is lit)
0x4b  /  0x232e  :  burning brightly
0x4c  /  0x2338  :  peering down from above
0x4d  /  0x2347  :  full of water
0x4e  /  0x234f  :  tied up
0x4f  /  0x2355  :  glowing white-hot
0x50  /  0x2362  : an olive branch
0x51  /  0x236e  : a golden buckle
0x52  /  0x2379  : the jester's cap
0x53  /  0x2382  : a silicon chip
0x54  /  0x238c  : a tightly-closed box
0x55  /  0x239a  : a diamond teardrop
0x56  /  0x23a5  : an ivory tusk
0x57  /  0x23b0  : a little dragon's wing
0x58  /  0x23bd  : a dinosaur egg
0x59  /  0x23c6  : a rotten apple
0x5a  /  0x23d0  : a battered suit of armour
0x5b  /  0x23df  : a meaty bone
0x5c  /  0x23e8  : a grimy brown bottle
0x5d  /  0x23f6  : a bunch of green leaves
0x5e  /  0x2406  : a pack of playing cards
0x5f  /  0x2415  : an oriental rug
0x60  /  0x2420  : a jewellery case
0x61  /  0x242b  : a cask of ale
0x62  /  0x2434  : a green frog
0x63  /  0x243d  : a bunch of keys
0x64  /  0x244a  : a rugged gauntlet
0x65  /  0x2457  : a drinking horn
0x66  /  0x2461  : a fine golden hourglass
0x67  /  0x2470  : a little icicle
0x68  /  0x2479  : a lightsabre
0x69  /  0x2482  : an inlaid looking-glass
0x6a  /  0x2492  : a lute
0x6b  /  0x2497  : a matchbox
0x6c  /  0x24a0  : a fine metronome
0x6d  /  0x24ab  : a milestone
0x6e  /  0x24b3  : a mirror
0x6f  /  0x24b9  : a stone pot
0x70  /  0x24c0  : a delicate little screwdriver
0x71  /  0x24d1  : a Masai spear
0x72  /  0x24db  : some sweetmeats
0x73  /  0x24e7  : valerian
0x74  /  0x24ed  : The Wheel
0x75  /  0x24f2  : 
0x76  /  0x24f3  : a sharp axe
0x77  /  0x24fb  : a silver bell
0x78  /  0x2500  : a gallon petrol can
0x79  /  0x250b  : a silver candelabra
0x7a  /  0x2515  : a candle
0x7b  /  0x251b  : 
0x7c  /  0x251c  : a filmy cloak
0x7d  /  0x2527  : a stone club
0x7e  /  0x2530  : a fur coat
0x7f  /  0x2537  : a jewelled coffer
0x80  /  0x2544  : a silver coin
0x81  /  0x254a  : a jewelled crown
0x82  /  0x2556  : an emerald
0x83  /  0x255e  : 
0x84  /  0x255f  : an onyx figurine
0x85  /  0x256b  : a firefly
0x86  /  0x2572  : some delicious food
0x87  /  0x257f  : a galactic groat
0x88  /  0x2589  : a joker
0x89  /  0x258f  : a fine sharp sword
0x8a  /  0x259b  : a carved lodestone
0x8b  /  0x25a6  : a lur
0x8c  /  0x25aa  : a scrap of parchment
0x8d  /  0x25b8  : an old mattress
0x8e  /  0x25c1  : a weighted net
0x8f  /  0x25cb  : a gold nugget
0x90  /  0x25d5  : a tin opener
0x91  /  0x25dd  : a painted pebble
0x92  /  0x25e7  : a glass phial
0x93  /  0x25f1  : a grubby pick
0x94  /  0x25fb  : two short planks
0x95  /  0x2608  : a grapple-firing rocket
0x96  /  0x2617  : a coil of rope
0x97  /  0x2621  : a curved ruby
0x98  /  0x262a  : a battered rucksack
0x99  /  0x2637  : winged shoes
0x9a  /  0x263f  : a shovel
0x9b  /  0x2645  : a fallen star
0x9c  /  0x264d  : a tin of catfood
0x9d  /  0x2658  : a long trident
0x9e  /  0x2662  : a porcelain vase
0x9f  /  0x266e  : a tiger tooth
0xa0  /  0x2676  : Welcome to "Lords of Time" from Level 9 Computing. You are sitting in the comfort of your own home, debugging your latest program before submitting it for us to market. Suddenly there is a blinding flash...


0xa1  /  0x26f0  : a grandfather clock large enough to climb into
0xa2  /  0x270e  : huge cogs numbered 1 to 9
0xa3  /  0x2722  : a massive pendulum
0xa4  /  0x2730  : a cast-iron cauldron
0xa5  /  0x273e  : a pile of family rubbish
0xa6  /  0x274d  : a wall cupboard
0xa7  /  0x2758  : a weeping willow
0xa8  /  0x2761  : a red Porsche
0xa9  /  0x2769  : a wall of ice blocking the way south
0xaa  /  0x277b  : a clear lake of very cold water to the northwest
0xab  /  0x2794  : a sheet of smooth ice leading northwest
0xac  /  0x27a8  : a cube of ice round the throne
0xad  /  0x27ba  : a moored viking longship with a fierce dragon prow
0xae  /  0x27d9  : a rocking stone to the west
0xaf  /  0x27e6  : a huge iron-bound chest
0xb0  /  0x27f6  : a recessed handle
0xb1  /  0x2801  : an ottoman
0xb2  /  0x2809  : a twee little well labelled "Water of Strength"
0xb3  /  0x2826  : a grate in the south wall
0xb4  /  0x2831  : a marble basin full of water
0xb5  /  0x2842  : a crude black archway
0xb6  /  0x2852  : a jumble of broken robots
0xb7  /  0x2864  : a silicate workbench
0xb8  /  0x2871  : many cruel metal cages in which the evil Timelords have imprisoned zillions of cute creatures
0xb9  /  0x28a8  : thick bars which imprison hundreds of poor people
0xba  /  0x28c7  : a compost heap, spilling onto the path
0xbb  /  0x28d9  : a jumble of dry wood
0xbc  /  0x28e6  : a picture of a kindly old man
0xbd  /  0x28f7  : a mushroom ring
0xbe  /  0x2901  : It's dark!


0xbf  /  0x290a  : Be more careful in future!
0xc0  /  0x291c  : The picture comes to life: "I am Father Time and I have chosen youn to help defend history against 9 evil Timelords. You must collect 9 items, each marked with an hourglass. Good Luck!"
0xc1  /  0x2995  : The animals bound away
0xc2  /  0x29a3  : The people are free and hurry away, handing you 
a reward
0xc3  /  0x29c2  : The bottle is loosened
0xc4  /  0x29cf  : It's held fast
0xc5  /  0x29d9  : 

A skeleton hand strangles you!
0xc6  /  0x29ee  : 

A scorpion stings!
0xc7  /  0x29fb  : 

Lightning strikes!
0xc8  /  0x2a08  : 

Father Time appears. "Do not be afraid. What you are about to see is the future if the Timelords win. There is still time to defeat them."


0xc9  /  0x2a5b  : the Tooth Fairy
0xca  /  0x2a65  : a woolly mammoth blocking your escape
0xcb  /  0x2a7c  : a sabre-toothed tiger
0xcc  /  0x2a89  : an Allosaurus
0xcd  /  0x2a92  : a Tyrannosaurus Rex
0xce  /  0x2aa0  : a Brontosaurus
0xcf  /  0x2aa9  : a group of cavemen
0xd0  /  0x2ab5  : a caveman dragging a struggling cavewoman by her hair
0xd1  /  0x2ad3  : an animated cave skeleton
0xd2  /  0x2ae4  : a rotund bartender
0xd3  /  0x2af0  : an unfortunate wretch in the stocks
0xd4  /  0x2b07  : a thirsty messenger of the King
0xd5  /  0x2b19  : a genuine fire-breathing dragon
0xd6  /  0x2b2d  : the Black Knight
0xd7  /  0x2b31  : a fair prince
0xd8  /  0x2b3a  : Pirate Pete
0xd9  /  0x2b40  : a jester
0xda  /  0x2b45  : a shivering Viking guard
0xdb  /  0x2b54  : a ghost
0xdc  /  0x2b59  : two Roman sentries beside the gate
0xdd  /  0x2b6c  : a massively-muscled gladiator
0xde  /  0x2b7e  : a fierce lion
0xdf  /  0x2b87  : a splendid android
0xe0  /  0x2b92  : a fierce cyberman waving a sword
0xe1  /  0x2ba7  : a single beautiful narcissus standing proudly amongst the weeds
0xe2  /  0x2bcc  : a silver fox
0xe3  /  0x2bd2  : two hunting dogs
0xe4  /  0x2bdf  : Needs winding
0xe5  /  0x2be6  : The room shakes
0xe6  /  0x2bee  : That magic word doesn't work
0xe7  /  0x2c01  : A force field blocks you: "Payment, please"
0xe8  /  0x2c1f  : "Entry now authorised today"
0xe9  /  0x2c33  : An inspection panel opens
0xea  /  0x2c43  : The cyberman blocks you
0xeb  /  0x2c51  : "Ta, love"


0xec  /  0x2c5a  : No one here wants
0xed  /  0x2c67  : You can't fill
0xee  /  0x2c6f  : You can't empty
0xef  /  0x2c7a  : YEUCH! No, you can't eat
0xf0  /  0x2c8c  : There's no one to give it to
0xf1  /  0x2c9e  : You find
0xf2  /  0x2ca3  : It's closed
0xf3  /  0x2cab  : If you insist.. There's no accounting for taste!
0xf4  /  0x2cc9  : That was delicious!
0xf5  /  0x2cd6  : Your vision clears. Someone's here!
0xf6  /  0x2cec  : Something slaps the coin from your hand!
0xf7  /  0x2d02  : The fairy snatches it back. "This coin may not be taken", she trills, "It may only be exchanged 
for a tooth!"
0xf8  /  0x2d41  : You can't quite reach the keys
0xf9  /  0x2d53  : The magnetic lodestone attracts the keys
0xfa  /  0x2d6a  : The tree speaks: "When I was planted the stream 
was clear and sparkling. Now I am old, it is polluted and I just want to die."
0xfb  /  0x2db6  : You need an axe
0xfc  /  0x2dc0  : With one swift blow you cut down the tree and it falls with a peaceful sigh. One sparkling teardrop remains.
0xfd  /  0x2dff  : The planks are too short to cross the stream
0xfe  /  0x2e14  : You tie the planks into a longer plank
0xff  /  0x2e28  : The tied planks bridge the stream
0x100  /  0x2e38  : With what shall you tie them?
0x101  /  0x2e47  : The stream is too wide to cross
0x102  /  0x2e55  : You've already done that!
0x103  /  0x2e66  : 

You have no spear! The tiger attacks..
0x104  /  0x2e7e  : The lake freezes round the icicle!
0x105  /  0x2e92  : Petrol soaks into the ground.


0x106  /  0x2ea5  : You pour out the petrol and discard its can
0x107  /  0x2ebc  : That's towards the mammoth! You are trapped.
0x108  /  0x2ed5  : The petrol burns up with a whoosh!
0x109  /  0x2ee9  :  
The mammoth is so surprised that it jumps clean out of its skin and runs off in terror!
0x10a  /  0x2f1b  : You have no fire
0x10b  /  0x2f26  : It burns brightly
0x10c  /  0x2f31  : It's empty!
0x10d  /  0x2f3b  : It burns well
0x10e  /  0x2f44  : The match goes out
0x10f  /  0x2f4f  : And goes out.


0x110  /  0x2f5a  : 

The candle flickers


0x111  /  0x2f68  : 

You feel very cold!


0x112  /  0x2f75  : The cavepeople grunt to each other
0x113  /  0x2f89  : The cavepeople grunt louder, at you
0x114  /  0x2f9c  : The cavemen advance, waving sticks
0x115  /  0x2fb0  : The cavemen attack!
0x116  /  0x2fbc  : The door opens.
0x117  /  0x2fc4  : The Black Knight strides forwards
0x118  /  0x2fd1  : The Black Knight draws his sword
0x119  /  0x2fde  : The Black Knight attacks 

0x11a  /  0x2fe8  : The Black Knight attacks again!
0x11b  /  0x2ff5  : but the armour protects you. 

0x11c  /  0x3007  : The prince leaps to your defence 

0x11d  /  0x301b  : but can find no sword and is killed easily.
0x11e  /  0x3034  : and kills the evil Black Knight. He carries the 
body away
0x11f  /  0x3050  : You're in a hole
0x120  /  0x305b  : You're in a deep hole
0x121  /  0x3067  : You're in a deep hole which collapses, burying you!
0x122  /  0x3085  : 

Pirate Pete steals
0x123  /  0x3090  : The lur booms out, summoning a horde of Vikings. 

0x124  /  0x30ae  : They are furious that Pirate Pete is not here!
0x125  /  0x30c7  : They grab the pirate and drag him off, rewarding you with an olive branch
0x126  /  0x30f1  : The viking is delighted by the warm fur and hands you a lur. "There is a reward for capturing the pirate", he says
0x127  /  0x312d  : 

It's very hot


0x128  /  0x3138  : 

You'll die without water!


0x129  /  0x3146  : 

The heat is too much!


0x12a  /  0x3153  : 

The lion struggles free
0x12b  /  0x3161  : The lion attacks!
0x12c  /  0x316b  : Tears rain down from the willow tree
0x12d  /  0x317f  : The tree is dead
0x12e  /  0x3187  : Planks bridge the stream
0x12f  /  0x3194  : There's a hole to the south
0x130  /  0x31a0  : The wood burns warmly
0x131  /  0x31ad  : The dinosaur approaches menacingly
0x132  /  0x31c0  : A secret door leads east
0x133  /  0x31cc  : The plant is eating you
0x134  /  0x31d8  : I didn't expect that!
0x135  /  0x31e7  : The Timelords notice you and summon their tebbit
0x136  /  0x3202  :  releasing liquid paraquat 

0x137  /  0x3212  : which kills the plant
0x138  /  0x321f  : "Woof!"
0x139  /  0x3226  : "WOOF! WOOF! YAP! GRRR!"
0x13a  /  0x323c  : "ARF! ARF! ARF! AOOOUL!" Guards arrive..
0x13b  /  0x325c  : You feel VERY strong!
0x13c  /  0x326b  : Just what you needed! 

0x13d  /  0x327a  : , chasing the cavemen
0x13e  /  0x3287  : It wanders away
0x13f  /  0x3290  :  and from the debris appears
0x140  /  0x329f  : The air shimmers
0x141  /  0x32a8  : The dinosaur kills you
0x142  /  0x32b4  : The killer dinosaurs kill each other
0x143  /  0x32c7  : The dinosaur blocks you
0x144  /  0x32d3  : The ice cube shatters, freeing the Snow Queen. She smiles, taps your shoulder with a sword and glides away
0x145  /  0x3311  : The ice wall shatters
0x146  /  0x331c  : MMMMMMM!
0x147  /  0x3325  : Only a real dodo would kiss
0x148  /  0x3337  : The frog turns into a handsome prince!
0x149  /  0x334f  : Nice try, but the icicle is out of reach
0x14a  /  0x3366  : 

The din shakes the icicle loose
0x14b  /  0x3378  : Noisy little beggar, aren't you!
0x14c  /  0x338e  : The bad tooth comes loose easily. The tiger is delighted and bounds off joyfully
0x14d  /  0x33b9  : It has a lean and hungry look, and could be in pain. Be careful!
0x14e  /  0x33e0  : The tiger is friendly now, but seems to be in pain
0x14f  /  0x33fb  : The tiger purrs deafeningly
0x150  /  0x340b  : The tiger pats one puffy cheek with a paw
0x151  /  0x3423  : The tiger winces and roars quietly
0x152  /  0x3435  : The fox grabs the bone and slinks off
0x153  /  0x344a  : The fox trips you up
0x154  /  0x3457  : The tiger blocks you, snarling to show its impressive array of mottled teeth
0x155  /  0x3482  : You forgot to open it! 

0x156  /  0x3491  : The tiger does not like that one bit. It attacks..
0x157  /  0x34af  : Oops! Smashed to smithereens
0x158  /  0x34c1  : The vile smell of whale-meat assails your nostris
0x159  /  0x34e2  : The dragon stalks off in a huff
0x15a  /  0x34f4  : The dragon lets you climb on his back and you travel along quite happily, back the way you came, until you reach the edge of a moat. The dragon 
tries to fly over it but only succeeds in belly-flopping into the water. It slinks off, dripping
0x15b  /  0x3577  : "I feel like a walk now, would you like a ride on my back?"
0x15c  /  0x359e  : The dragon eats the food with obvious relish: "Thanks mate, that was very good - could have done with a touch more mustard though."


0x15d  /  0x35e6  : The android exchanges your coin for a Galactic Groat
0x15e  /  0x3606  : The tooth fairy examines it closely and says, "This isn't our usual kind of tooth, most odd - tell you what, I'll swap it for one silver coin. Is that a deal?"
0x15f  /  0x365e  : "Mmm. Perhaps I could throw in a firefly too. OK?"
0x160  /  0x367f  : "Then you'll get NOTHING!"
0x161  /  0x3693  : 

The fairy takes your tooth and leaves.
0x162  /  0x36a7  : The tiger gulps down the food greedily and purrs at you
0x163  /  0x36c6  : The brontosaurus grabs the leaves and pulls them into the air. It carries you out of the pit!
0x164  /  0x36f2  : "OK, the ale's yours"
0x165  /  0x3700  : Not worth enough
0x166  /  0x370b  : "Thanks very much! Just what I wanted!" The messenger drinks the ale and shares some of his food with you
0x167  /  0x3745  : The Jester laughs with glee, "Thank you my friend"! He gives you his belled cap before dancing off
0x168  /  0x377a  : The narcissus squeaks with joy and rewards you with a lodestone. He admires himself delightedly 
in the looking-glass
0x169  /  0x37bc  : The dogs gulp down the delicacies, wagging their tails, before waddling off for a nap
0x16a  /  0x37ee  : What a queer thing to do to
0x16b  /  0x37fe  : Your blows are futile
0x16c  /  0x380c  : You attack ferociously, scaring off
0x16d  /  0x3822  : 

It is marked with an hourglass symbol
0x16e  /  0x383a  : Time goes by 

0x16f  /  0x3844  : 

It is a valuable treasure
0x170  /  0x3853  :  balanced precariously on a shelf
0x171  /  0x3865  :  rolling on the ground
0x172  /  0x3871  :  hanging on the wall
0x173  /  0x387a  :  lying on blood-stained snow
0x174  /  0x388b  :  poking out of the earth
0x175  /  0x3894  :  scattered about
0x176  /  0x389f  :  on a green-baize table
0x177  /  0x38af  :  hanging on the wall
0x178  /  0x38b8  :  on the dressing table
0x179  /  0x38c1  :  on a rough wooden table
0x17a  /  0x38cf  :  sitting on a lily pad
0x17b  /  0x38da  :  pushed out of reach under the shed door
0x17c  /  0x38ec  :  in the dust
0x17d  /  0x38f2  :  on a table
0x17e  /  0x38f9  :  on the mantlepiece
0x17f  /  0x3904  :  hanging from the ceiling
0x180  /  0x3913  :  standing in a rack
0x181  /  0x391c  :  on the wall
0x182  /  0x3920  :  propped in the corner
0x183  /  0x392b  :  on the table
0x184  /  0x3930  :  in pride of place
0x185  /  0x393b  :  beside the road
0x186  /  0x3941  :  half-buried in the earth
0x187  /  0x394c  :  on a stone shelf
0x188  /  0x3956  :  on the workbench
0x189  /  0x395f  :  hanging on the wall
0x18a  /  0x3968  :  on a carved sideboard
0x18b  /  0x3977  :  hidden amongst the delphiniums
0x18c  /  0x398a  :  propped up in a corner
0x18d  /  0x3998  : 
0x18e  /  0x3999  : 
0x18f  /  0x399a  : 
0x190  /  0x399b  : 

You've been killed.


0x191  /  0x39a9  : in your own living room
0x192  /  0x39b4  : in a large, cold looking room
0x193  /  0x39c3  : inside a gigantic clock
0x194  /  0x39d0  : at the end of a gravel drive which bends to the 
southwest. The grassy lawns beside the drive are edged with the vibrant colours of summer flowers. A narrow country road runs north-south
0x195  /  0x3a2f  : at roadworks where the road ends
0x196  /  0x3a41  : on a winding gravel drive
0x197  /  0x3a4e  : outside a delightful country cottage
0x198  /  0x3a63  : in a bright hallway at the foot of a carpetted stairway
0x199  /  0x3a7e  : on the landing at the top of the stairs
0x19a  /  0x3a8e  : in a cramped store-room
0x19b  /  0x3a9b  : in a plushly carpeted master bedroom
0x19c  /  0x3aae  : in a lovely old-fashioned kitchen
0x19d  /  0x3ac3  : in the living room, a long comfortable room decorated in autumn shades of brown and gold. A patio door leads to the garden
0x19e  /  0x3b03  : on a patio, decorated with urns of flowers. A crazy-paving path winds southwest across the lawn 
to a garden shed. The garden ends at a wooden fence
0x19f  /  0x3b50  : in the flower garden
0x1a0  /  0x3b5a  : at the end of the garden beside a five foot fence covered in ivy
0x1a1  /  0x3b7b  : beside a fence on the east bank of a wide, dirty stream clogged with crisp packets and MacRonalds boxes
0x1a2  /  0x3bb1  : further upstream where the filthy stream is quite narrow. A lone narcissus grows amidst the nettles on the opposite bank
0x1a3  /  0x3bf4  : west of the stream
0x1a4  /  0x3bfc  : outside a garden shed
0x1a5  /  0x3c06  : in a cluttered garden shed
0x1a6  /  0x3c16  : beside the polluted stream
0x1a7  /  0x3c21  : at a garden gate which opens onto a paved path leading east
0x1a8  /  0x3c3f  : on a paved path which leads east-west beside the garden
0x1a9  /  0x3c5a  : in a carport with an an examination pit in the floor
0x1aa  /  0x3c76  : standing on splintered ice in a deep valley. The sky is very grey and the wind is blowing very hard
0x1ab  /  0x3ca6  : walking unsteadily across a slippery ice sheet
0x1ac  /  0x3cbf  : on very smooth ice
0x1ad  /  0x3cca  : at the edge of the ice, where drifting snow has 
banked up at the foot of the mountains
0x1ae  /  0x3cf5  : where a rocky track leads up the mountain
0x1af  /  0x3d0e  : laboriously climbing the snowcovered mountain
0x1b0  /  0x3d2a  : at an armchair hollow in the mountainside, below a cave
0x1b1  /  0x3d47  : on a ledge outside an odoriferous cave
0x1b2  /  0x3d5d  : in a huge subterranean chamber with smooth walls
0x1b3  /  0x3d7a  : in the freezing cave
0x1b4  /  0x3d83  : at a junction
0x1b5  /  0x3d87  : in a silver fox lair
0x1b6  /  0x3d91  : in the silver-veined cave
0x1b7  /  0x3d9a  : in the hidden silver vault
0x1b8  /  0x3da7  : in a splendid frost chamber
0x1b9  /  0x3db7  : in a dark, eerie cave melted from slushy black ice
0x1ba  /  0x3dd8  : in the frozen forest, amidst tall, snow-laden trees
0x1bb  /  0x3df3  : in an intricate alpine garden
0x1bc  /  0x3e05  : in a miniature throne room. A crack in the ice leads south
0x1bd  /  0x3e20  :  beside a pool of icy water
0x1be  /  0x3e2c  : ankle-deep in icy water
0x1bf  /  0x3e38  : sloshing along, thigh deep in icy water which is getting deeper
0x1c0  /  0x3e59  : swimming in freezing water
0x1c1  /  0x3e67  : standing below a small hill rising from a lush green grassy valley. There's an opening in the hillside. Far to the east is a watering hole, surrounded by grazing animals
0x1c2  /  0x3ebc  : west of the waterhole. The grazing animals watch you with interest: some of them look very large
0x1c3  /  0x3eed  : by a pool of muddy water. The grazing dinosaurs 
walk slowly away as you approach
0x1c4  /  0x3f1d  : west of the hill
0x1c5  /  0x3f24  : on the prairie
0x1c6  /  0x3f2c  : in a deep pit, presumably an animal trap
0x1c7  /  0x3f43  : by the edge of the pit
0x1c8  /  0x3f4d  : climbing a well-worn path
0x1c9  /  0x3f5d  : on a wide ledge outside a warm cave
0x1ca  /  0x3f6d  : in a large dry cave, warmed by a blazing fire
0x1cb  /  0x3f87  : in a store cave
0x1cc  /  0x3f8f  : in the handicraft cave. The cavemen have obviously been very busy as there are lots of bone bowls and stone dishes on the floor
0x1cd  /  0x3fd3  : the junk-strewn pebble and shell room where the 
cave people make cheap gifts for barter with travellers
0x1ce  /  0x400e  : in the smallest cave
0x1cf  /  0x4015  : in the painting studio. Clearly minimalism is all the rage
0x1d0  /  0x4030  : in the stone age armoury
0x1d1  /  0x403d  : in the trophy cave. Skeleton heads hang from the walls - some of them were human
0x1d2  /  0x4068  : in the treasure vault
0x1d3  /  0x4073  : crossing a wooden bridge over an exceedingly deep crevasse
0x1d4  /  0x4094  : in the invention room. You find odd scribblings 
on the walls and find half-finished tools on the floor
0x1d5  /  0x40c8  : in the invention alcove: "JWAAMTETS" is enscribed high on one wall
0x1d6  /  0x40ef  : in a small recess which sounds hollow underfoot
0x1d7  /  0x410a  : at the end of a road leading north. High stone walls block the view to east and west
0x1d8  /  0x4135  : at a bend in the enclosed road
0x1d9  /  0x4144  : on the road, which now cuts across a small village green. To the north is a small medieval ale-house with wattled walls and a thatched roof
0x1da  /  0x418e  : in the bar: a grubby room with straw on the floor - not at all the sort of place you usually frequent
0x1db  /  0x41be  : on a cobbled street leading past a dense copse to a splendid castle in the east
0x1dc  /  0x41e4  : at the Cobble Square west of the castle. There are pillories and stocks here, surrounded by a jeering crowd
0x1dd  /  0x421c  : in front of the imposing castle entrance. The drawbridge is raised
0x1de  /  0x423f  : in the copse
0x1df  /  0x4245  : at the edge of the copse
0x1e0  /  0x424f  : deep in the copse
0x1e1  /  0x4257  : in the copse
0x1e2  /  0x425d  : on the north bank of the moat
0x1e3  /  0x426c  : standing in ankle deep scummy water below the south bank of the moat
0x1e4  /  0x428c  : at the castle entrance, between two tall battle-scarred towers
0x1e5  /  0x42b0  : in the courtyard within the castle walls. Battered armour and notched swords litter the blood-soaked ground. The Keep stands open to the southeast
0x1e6  /  0x42fb  : in the armoury
0x1e7  /  0x4302  : at the Keep entrance, in a small stone room
0x1e8  /  0x4316  : in a storeroom piled high with kegs and barrels
0x1e9  /  0x4332  : in the rush-strewn Great Hall
0x1ea  /  0x4340  : above a narrow flight of stairs
0x1eb  /  0x4353  : descending the steep stairs
0x1ec  /  0x435f  : in the dungeons which are dank and depressing. There's a red cross on the wall and the earth floor looks disturbed
0x1ed  /  0x4399  : on a beach in a small bay surrounded by overhanging cliffs. Breakers roll in from the sea to the north, rocking the viking longship drawn up on 
the sand north of you
0x1ee  /  0x43f3  : at the edge of the sea
0x1ef  /  0x43fb  : on board the ship
0x1f0  /  0x4405  : between the sea and towering cliffs
0x1f1  /  0x4419  : on the beach. There's a cave to the southeast
0x1f2  /  0x442f  : outside a sea cave
0x1f3  /  0x4437  : in a low cave smelling of seaweed
0x1f4  /  0x444a  : in an empty cave
0x1f5  /  0x4455  : an old, musty, dry cave floored with very soft earth
0x1f6  /  0x4474  : walking along a sloping east-west passage. The ground is very damp and seaweed clings to the walls
0x1f7  /  0x44a8  : further along the damp passage, beside the entrance to a small cave
0x1f8  /  0x44c8  : in an obnoxious cave deep down in the rocks, beside a slimy little pool
0x1f9  /  0x44ec  : 
0x1fa  /  0x44ed  : in a hands and knees crawl. An opening slopes down to the north
0x1fb  /  0x4510  : 
0x1fc  /  0x4511  : at a junction of the tunnel and a vertical fissure
0x1fd  /  0x4529  : 
0x1fe  /  0x452a  : in a tight fissure
0x1ff  /  0x4535  : above the hole in a cave which shows signs of habitation: the ashes from a recent fire smoulder 
acridly
0x200  /  0x4571  : in the pirate's hideout
0x201  /  0x457d  : in the large, empty chest
0x202  /  0x458b  : in the entrance porch of an impressive country house with exposed oak beams
0x203  /  0x45b7  : in a u-shaped hallway with doors to east and west. A magnificent staircase sweeps upwards to a gallery above
0x204  /  0x45f4  : at the north end of the banqueting hall
0x205  /  0x4605  : at the south end of the hall
0x206  /  0x460f  : at the north end of a long room used for relaxation
0x207  /  0x462a  : at the south end of the long room, between two tables
0x208  /  0x4644  : at the top of the stairway, in the minstrel's gallery. A short staircase leads up
0x209  /  0x4669  : climbing the short stairs. Several wall panels sound hollow
0x20a  /  0x468b  : in the middle of a long east-west portrait gallery. Leaded windows overlook the beautiful knot gardens below
0x20b  /  0x46cb  : at the west end of the portrait gallery
0x20c  /  0x46de  : in a bedroom with a four poster bed
0x20d  /  0x46f0  : in the bedroom of the master of the house
0x20e  /  0x4701  : at the east end of the long gallery
0x20f  /  0x4710  : in a bedroom, hung about with lavender
0x210  /  0x4726  : in the music room
0x211  /  0x472e  : in a hedge maze
0x212  /  0x4736  : in a hedge maze
0x213  /  0x473e  : in a hedge maze
0x214  /  0x4746  : in a hedge maze
0x215  /  0x474e  : in the middle of the maze
0x216  /  0x4758  : in a hedge maze
0x217  /  0x4760  : in a hedge maze
0x218  /  0x4768  : in a hedge maze
0x219  /  0x4770  : in a hedge maze
0x21a  /  0x4778  : down the well, within reach of the water
0x21b  /  0x478d  : on a road leading north through the gates of a walled city
0x21c  /  0x47aa  : outside the north entrance of an amphitheatre: an enormous circular building of gleaming marble 
and decorated with heroic statues. You can hear 
the roar of the crowds inside
0x21d  /  0x4806  : just inside the gates, at a junction
0x21e  /  0x4813  : on the steps of a small temple. Stone columns support the lintel over its doorway
0x21f  /  0x4840  : inside the temple, which contains shrines to many gods
0x220  /  0x485e  : at a road junction
0x221  /  0x4865  : in a spartan barracks, beside an iron-bound locker
0x222  /  0x4883  : inside the locker where soldiers store their weapons
0x223  /  0x489d  : on a long straight road north from the gatehouse. Around you are the buildings of a small garrison town
0x224  /  0x48d4  : in the forum: an open courtyard surrounded by buildings
0x225  /  0x48f5  : in the market, at a vegetable stall. Ladies, wearing long flowing robes gathered at the waist and clasped at the shoulder, are jostling to get the best buy
0x226  /  0x4941  : in the market, at a bread stall
0x227  /  0x4950  : in a butcher's shop
0x228  /  0x495d  : outside a tavern
0x229  /  0x4965  : in the deserted treasury
0x22a  /  0x4970  : in the arena of the amphitheatre, surrounded by 
an immense cheering crowd
0x22b  /  0x4996  : in the south end of the caldarium. Steps lead down into a great square bath decorated with dolphin mosaics
0x22c  /  0x49ce  : beside a stone dolphin which pours out cold water
0x22d  /  0x49e8  : in the hot baths
0x22e  /  0x49f1  : in the hypocaust
0x22f  /  0x49f9  : in the hypocaust
0x230  /  0x4a01  : in the hypocaust
0x231  /  0x4a09  : in the hypocaust
0x232  /  0x4a11  : in the hypocaust
0x233  /  0x4a19  : in the hypocaust
0x234  /  0x4a21  : on a flat rocky plain which stretches for miles. It is covered by fine grey dust. The night air 
is cold. Luminous walkways travel east and west
0x235  /  0x4a74  : at a walkway junction
0x236  /  0x4a7d  : at the Intergalactic Bureau-de-Change
0x237  /  0x4a95  : at the foot of the Milky Way, a long sparkling pathway which climbs up into space
0x238  /  0x4ac3  : halfway up the Milky Way
0x239  /  0x4ad4  : at the top of the Milky Way, amidst brightly twinkling stars
0x23a  /  0x4af6  : lost among the stars
0x23b  /  0x4b00  : on a walkway south. A neon sign flashes "Walkway to Mars"
0x23c  /  0x4b21  : at a walkway junction on the grey plain
0x23d  /  0x4b31  : at the end of the north walkway. If you continue it will be on foot
0x23e  /  0x4b55  : standing on a floating metal platform, suspended in mid-air. To the north is a starship
0x23f  /  0x4b82  : inside the starship
0x240  /  0x4b8a  : in a green sleep room
0x241  /  0x4b97  : in a space swimming pool, splashing around on a 
colossal water drop which wobbles in mid-air
0x242  /  0x4bcb  : in a control room, surrounded by instrument panels
0x243  /  0x4be8  : on the edge of a wide crater
0x244  /  0x4bf6  : in a dull, lifeless crater. High up the west wall is an opening
0x245  /  0x4c1b  : in a colossal habidome
0x246  /  0x4c29  : in a long room. A guard stands beside each door
0x247  /  0x4c43  : in the alcove room. Only one alcove is open
0x248  /  0x4c5a  : in a cubicle
0x249  /  0x4c62  : in a room with no roof. An opening is visible far above
0x24a  /  0x4c81  : outside a sports and aerobotics arena
0x24b  /  0x4c96  : beside a deep tropical pool
0x24c  /  0x4ca3  : in a dark, dingy hole between a ladder and a low tunnel
0x24d  /  0x4cc1  : in the fencing hall
0x24e  /  0x4cc9  : in a robot repair shop
0x24f  /  0x4cd7  : in a fair field full of flowers. Butterflies flitter happily in the bright sunshine and a heady 
perfume fills the air. You could be in paradise
0x250  /  0x4d24  : in front of an ugly arch: "ABANDON HOPE ALL YE WHO ENTER HERE"
0x251  /  0x4d59  : in the Ruined Land. Where trees and grasses once grew is a smouldering wasteland and the sun hangs low as a huge ball of red fire. The heat is terrible and the ground below your feet quivers as though in agony
0x252  /  0x4dc6  : amidst the smoking ruins of a small village
0x253  /  0x4ddb  : on the brink of a deep crack
0x254  /  0x4dea  : at the bottom of a deep, earthy pit. The walls are too crumbly to climb
0x255  /  0x4e0e  : in a stifling maze of decayed earthy passages
0x256  /  0x4e25  : in a putrescent chamber
0x257  /  0x4e33  : at a junction between foul passages
0x258  /  0x4e45  : in a square white room, some sort of experimental laboratory
0x259  /  0x4e68  : in a worse laboratory
0x25a  /  0x4e74  : in a room full of strange plants which grab at you. One flower is enormous
0x25b  /  0x4e9f  : inside the plant. Sharp hairs block your escape 
and the walls ooze digestive juices
0x25c  /  0x4ecc  : climbing down a sticky tube
0x25d  /  0x4edd  : inside the tangled roots of the giant plant
0x25e  /  0x4ef1  : in a low, earthy tunnel
0x25f  /  0x4efe  : at the end of the earthy tunnel. Crude steps lead upwards
0x260  /  0x4f1c  : climbing steep, treacherous stairs
0x261  /  0x4f2f  : squeezing your way up the narrow stairs
0x262  /  0x4f45  : at the top of the stairs. You can feel a trapdoor above
0x263  /  0x4f5f  : under a long table. Seated round it are nine men, presumably the Evil Timelords
0x264  /  0x4f8f  : standing behind the Evil Timelords as they discuss their evil plans
0x265  /  0x4fb5  : at a dark dead end
0x266  /  0x4fc0  : at a dark dead end
0x267  /  0x4fcb  : at a dark dead end
0x268  /  0x4fd6  : at a crossing of country roads
0x269  /  0x4fe7  : on a long, straight road. To the west, it shimmers and fades away
0x26a  /  0x500d  : on a long road. It fades to mist in the east
0x26b  /  0x5023  : lost in the mists of time
0x26c  /  0x502f  : A water scorpion bites you!
0x26d  /  0x5040  : A giant squid attacks!
0x26e  /  0x5050  : Seaweed engulfs you!
0x26f  /  0x505f  : This walkway is under construction and collapses!
0x270  /  0x507d  : Would you like to be resurrected?
0x271  /  0x5092  : Sorry, the sand's run out
0x272  /  0x50a1  : Clouds of sand billow up...


0x273  /  0x50b3  : Into the cauldron!
0x274  /  0x50bf  : 

The recipe is complete! Your surroundings fade 
away as the structure of time is repaired. You have won!


0x275  /  0x50fa  : 
0x276  /  0x50fb  : A symbol of peace
0x277  /  0x5107  : Solid gold. Very Valuable!
0x278  /  0x5118  : A floppy, red and blue cap with bells attached
0x279  /  0x5134  : A 68006, I think
0x27a  /  0x5141  : "This box contains an evil eye;

if opened, you would surely die!"
0x27b  /  0x516c  : It sparkles brightly
0x27c  /  0x5178  : Heavy, but very valuable
0x27d  /  0x5189  : Too small for flying!
0x27e  /  0x5196  : Large, warm and leathery
0x27f  /  0x51a3  : Yeuch!
0x280  /  0x51aa  : Just your size
0x281  /  0x51b5  : Delicious, if you like that sort of thing
0x282  /  0x51cd  : Marked with a skull
0x283  /  0x51d9  : They seem fresh-cut
0x284  /  0x51e7  : A complete set of playing cards
0x285  /  0x51fa  : Hand-embroidered
0x286  /  0x5207  : Very valuable!
0x287  /  0x5210  : Real Ale, of course
0x288  /  0x521d  : Cute
0x289  /  0x5221  : The keys are of all sizes
0x28a  /  0x522f  : An ordinary asbestos glove
0x28b  /  0x5240  : A great ox-horn, bound with gold
0x28c  /  0x5255  : The sands have almost run through!
0x28d  /  0x5269  : Nothing special
0x28e  /  0x5273  : A weapon
0x28f  /  0x5279  : Cor! You look prettier every day
0x290  /  0x528c  : A mediaeval guitar
0x291  /  0x529a  :  matches are left
0x292  /  0x52a6  : I dunno what this does!
0x293  /  0x52b6  : "Hope village"
0x294  /  0x52c1  : The mirror seems to expand, sucking you in!
0x295  /  0x52da  : A fine example of stone age work
0x296  /  0x52ed  : Extremely delicate
0x297  /  0x52f8  : A colourful souvenir
0x298  /  0x5306  : Delicious pastries
0x299  /  0x5311  : A magical herb
0x29a  /  0x531c  : The first hard disc!
0x29b  /  0x5327  : 
0x29c  /  0x5328  : A general-purpose axe
0x29d  /  0x5336  : Small and dainty
0x29e  /  0x5340  : It's full
0x29f  /  0x5347  : Solid silver
0x2a0  /  0x534d  : Wax
0x2a1  /  0x5351  : 
0x2a2  /  0x5352  : It seems to diffract light oddly
0x2a3  /  0x5367  : Heavy and viscious-looking
0x2a4  /  0x537a  : Warm, course fur, rather smelly
0x2a5  /  0x538f  : Empty, but bejewelled
0x2a6  /  0x53a1  : Very small, very thin and very old
0x2a7  /  0x53ae  : Wow!
0x2a8  /  0x53b2  : Very big!
0x2a9  /  0x53b8  : 
0x2aa  /  0x53b9  : a carved tiger
0x2ab  /  0x53c2  : It glows brightly
0x2ac  /  0x53cd  : Spiced bread with pickles
0x2ad  /  0x53dd  : A black metal disc with a gold edge
0x2ae  /  0x53f2  : It shows the picture of a jester
0x2af  /  0x5401  : 
0x2b0  /  0x5402  : A chunk of metallic ore
0x2b1  /  0x5411  : A musical instrument made from a horn
0x2b2  /  0x5428  : To the sunset 
you must go,

keeping high and never low.

In a sheltered, hidden cove

you will find a treasure trove.

Pitfalls you are sure to meet,

you may even get wet feet!,

but in the end you're sure to 
greet

that dreadful scoundrel, Pirate Pete!
0x2b3  /  0x54bd  : Well padded
0x2b4  /  0x54c6  : Tough ropes with lead weights round the edge
0x2b5  /  0x54e0  : Very valuable
0x2b6  /  0x54e8  : A tin-opener of the "butterfly" type
0x2b7  /  0x54ff  : Painted white, with black eye-markings
0x2b8  /  0x551a  : Glass
0x2b9  /  0x551e  : For hacking at hard material
0x2ba  /  0x552d  : The planks are sturdy wood
0x2bb  /  0x553c  : a grapple-firing rocket
0x2bc  /  0x554b  : A short hessian rope
0x2bd  /  0x5557  : The ruby acts as a lense
0x2be  /  0x5564  : If worn, the backpack should help you carry more
0x2bf  /  0x5581  : Magical winged shoes!
0x2c0  /  0x5590  : Battered and rusty
0x2c1  /  0x559b  : A most unusual object!
0x2c2  /  0x55ac  : Kattomush: "Maiow-thwatering goodness for Kitty"
0x2c3  /  0x55cd  : a lethal weapon
0x2c4  /  0x55d6  : A small, valuable vase
0x2c5  /  0x55e3  : It is in poor shape
0x2c6  /  0x55ee  : 
0x2c7  /  0x55ef  : Water? Where?
0x2c8  /  0x55f9  : Pete blocks you
0x2c9  /  0x5601  : Ghostly footsteps plod to the short stairs and fade away
0x2ca  /  0x5622  : A panel moves!
0x2cb  /  0x562c  : A jester appears: "The Lord of Misrule is angry 
for I have lost one of the tools of my trade. Have you seen it?"
0x2cc  /  0x566d  : The god Mercury appears and solemnly hands you a pair of winged sandals
0x2cd  /  0x5697  : "SHOW SOME RESPECT!"
0x2ce  /  0x56ac  : It's very good
0x2cf  /  0x56b5  : The skeleton collapses in a heap of dry bones
0x2d0  /  0x56d0  : The skeleton blocks you
0x2d1  /  0x56de  : The vile caveman is knocked off the bridge. The 
rescued woman thanks you profusely and presses something into your hand
0x2d2  /  0x5720  : You receive 6,000,000 volts up the arm
0x2d3  /  0x573a  : The narcissus bends away, sadly, "I'm doomed to 
spend my life admiring my reflection. But this water's so dirty that I can hardly see to admire 
my beautiful face in it."
0x2d4  /  0x57a2  : "Oy! Pay for that!"
0x2d5  /  0x57b1  : Shame on you! You're in the stocks now!
0x2d6  /  0x57c7  : The Black Knight is in the way
0x2d7  /  0x57ce  : The ground is too hard
0x2d8  /  0x57da  : The ground under your feet gives way
0x2d9  /  0x57ef  : I don't really want that, but thanks!
0x2da  /  0x5806  : It rolls away
0x2db  /  0x580e  : The chest opens and a bearded rogue leaps out: "Ahoy there me hearty! Oi be Pirate Pete what gets me pleasure from robbing weary travellers like thee!"


0x2dc  /  0x5866  : You've nothing left to steal! Pirate Pete is furious..
0x2dd  /  0x5885  : The stone blocks you
0x2de  /  0x5890  : The dogs turn up their cultured noses
0x2df  /  0x58a9  : A gladiator steals the buckle and runs south to 
the arena!
0x2e0  /  0x58c9  : It comes loose
0x2e1  /  0x58d1  : You're not strong enough
0x2e2  /  0x58e1  : The grating blocks you
0x2e3  /  0x58ed  : It entangles the lion
0x2e4  /  0x58f7  : The trident pins the net in place, holding the lion securely
0x2e5  /  0x5914  : The gladiator is too quick for you - he blocks your escape
0x2e6  /  0x5933  : The hot star burns you!
0x2e7  /  0x5941  : The gauntlet finally catches fire! 

0x2e8  /  0x5958  : The water cools the star in a hissing of steam
0x2e9  /  0x596c  : "YOU'RE NOT AUTHORISED TO DO THAT!"
0x2ea  /  0x5990  : There's nothing to break your fall
0x2eb  /  0x59a2  : The mattress breaks your fall
0x2ec  /  0x59b2  : and you climb its rope
0x2ed  /  0x59c0  : The components are too minute to see
0x2ee  /  0x59d3  : Your lightsabre makes short work of the cyberman
0x2ef  /  0x59f2  : The rocket shoots up 

0x2f0  /  0x59ff  : but falls back

0x5a08
