Data length: 26111
0x0  /  0x1eb7  : 't empty 

0x1  /  0x1ebf  : T
0x2  /  0x1ec1  :  

0x3  /  0x1ec3  : 
0x4  /  0x1ec4  : , 

0x5  /  0x1ec7  : . 

0x6  /  0x1eca  : 


0x7  /  0x1ecc  :  and 

0x8  /  0x1ed0  : .


0x9  /  0x1ed3  : north
0xa  /  0x1ed7  : northeast
0xb  /  0x1edc  : east
0xc  /  0x1ede  : south
0xd  /  0x1ee0  : southeast
0xe  /  0x1ee3  : southwest
0xf  /  0x1ee7  : west
0x10  /  0x1eea  : northwest
0x11  /  0x1ef0  : up
0x12  /  0x1ef3  : down
0x13  /  0x1ef7  : in
0x14  /  0x1ef9  : out
0x15  /  0x1efc  : across
0x16  /  0x1f00  : Exits lead 

0x17  /  0x1f08  :  (through a door)
0x18  /  0x1f12  :  (through an open door)
0x19  /  0x1f1f  : 

You are 

0x1a  /  0x1f25  : You own 

0x1b  /  0x1f2a  : And you're wearing 

0x1c  /  0x1f37  : You can see 

0x1d  /  0x1f3e  : 

What now?
0x1e  /  0x1f45  : I don't understand
0x1f  /  0x1f51  : Eh?
0x20  /  0x1f55  : Arfle barfle gloop?
0x21  /  0x1f63  : You'll need to say more than that!
0x22  /  0x1f78  : Could you elaborate?
0x23  /  0x1f86  : Sorry, I can't guess what you mean
0x24  /  0x1f9d  : Could you rephrase that?
0x25  /  0x1fad  : Please be more specific
0x26  /  0x1fb9  : I don't quite understand
0x27  /  0x1fc8  : What a mouthful! I'm only an ignorant micro
0x28  /  0x1fe4  : You can't do that
0x29  /  0x1fee  : Don't be silly!
0x2a  /  0x1ff9  : You can't see 

0x2b  /  0x2002  : You don't have 

0x2c  /  0x200c  : You already have 

0x2d  /  0x2016  : You can't carry any more
0x2e  /  0x2025  : You can't take that!
0x2f  /  0x2032  : You can't wear 

0x30  /  0x203b  : You're carrying too much to take 

0x31  /  0x2050  : It is dark, you cannot see
0x32  /  0x205f  : The light is dazzlingly bright
0x33  /  0x2070  : Nothing happens
0x34  /  0x2079  : Doesn't seem to work
0x35  /  0x2087  : There's no effect
0x36  /  0x2094  : Really stop?
0x37  /  0x209d  : Would you like to play again?
0x38  /  0x20b1  : Really restore?
0x39  /  0x20bb  : 

Please answer AFFIRMATIVE or NEGATIVE
0x3a  /  0x20d9  : You scored 

0x3b  /  0x20e0  :  out of 1000
0x3c  /  0x20e9  : It is nothing special
0x3d  /  0x20f4  : nothing.


0x3e  /  0x20fb  : You can't go in that direction
0x3f  /  0x210b  : You bump your nose on a door
0x40  /  0x211b  : The door closes behind you


0x41  /  0x2129  : It's already open
0x42  /  0x2133  : It's already closed
0x43  /  0x213e  : There's nothing here worth opening
0x44  /  0x2151  : There's nothing here worth closing
0x45  /  0x2164  : There's nothing to attack!
0x46  /  0x2172  : You find nothing of interest
0x47  /  0x217f  : The only visible exit is 

0x48  /  0x218e  : What do you want to do with 

0x49  /  0x219f  : You find 

0x4a  /  0x21a5  : . It holds 

0x4b  /  0x21ad  : Indicator lights flicker
0x4c  /  0x21bc  : 
0x4d  /  0x21bd  : 
0x4e  /  0x21be  : 
0x4f  /  0x21bf  : 
0x50  /  0x21c0  : 
0x51  /  0x21c1  : ceramic body armour
0x52  /  0x21cf  : a translucent visor
0x53  /  0x21de  : dark glas the ses
0x54  /  0x21e7  : a hospital gown
0x55  /  0x21f1  : an intricate bracelet
0x56  /  0x21fe  : a battered bubble helmet
0x57  /  0x220e  : a kevlar leotard
0x58  /  0x221b  : a glittering necklace
0x59  /  0x222a  : 
0x5a  /  0x222b  : 
0x5b  /  0x222c  : an aerosol paint can
0x5c  /  0x223a  : an LL9 batpak
0x5d  /  0x2245  : the body of a crew-member
0x5e  /  0x2254  : a debt card
0x5f  /  0x225e  : a cute pussy cat
0x60  /  0x226a  : a freezer coffin
0x61  /  0x2274  : a square cup
0x62  /  0x227d  : a pair of linked cylinders
0x63  /  0x228b  : an electro-flute
0x64  /  0x2299  : a fire extinguisher
0x65  /  0x22a6  : a diagnostic probe
0x66  /  0x22b2  : a sealed flas the k
0x67  /  0x22bb  : a red form
0x68  /  0x22c2  : an orange form
0x69  /  0x22cc  : a yellow form
0x6a  /  0x22d6  : a green form
0x6b  /  0x22dd  : a hand-gun
0x6c  /  0x22e5  : a holo wand
0x6d  /  0x22ed  : a bunch of keys
0x6e  /  0x22f6  : 
0x6f  /  0x22f7  : a lance
0x70  /  0x22fe  : a portable las the er
0x71  /  0x2307  : a mempak
0x72  /  0x230f  : 
0x73  /  0x2310  : a memory rope
0x74  /  0x2319  : 
0x75  /  0x231a  : 
0x76  /  0x231b  : an ultrasound scalpel
0x77  /  0x2329  : a yin-yang screwdriver
0x78  /  0x2339  : a titanium shovel
0x79  /  0x2346  : an adjusting spanner
0x7a  /  0x2352  : a red ticket
0x7b  /  0x235a  : a green ticket
0x7c  /  0x2362  : 
0x7d  /  0x2363  : a bomb
0x7e  /  0x2368  : a bumble bearing
0x7f  /  0x2373  : a maxwell sink
0x80  /  0x237d  : a peg warp
0x81  /  0x2385  : a 101-way ribbon cable
0x82  /  0x2396  : a stacker lift
0x83  /  0x23a1  : 
0x84  /  0x23a2  : 
0x85  /  0x23a3  : 
0x86  /  0x23a4  : 
0x87  /  0x23a5  : 
0x88  /  0x23a6  : a lamp
0x89  /  0x23ab  : a video viewer
0x8a  /  0x23b7  : a silver tray
0x8b  /  0x23c1  : a floating table
0x8c  /  0x23ca  : a toolbox
0x8d  /  0x23d2  : 
0x8e  /  0x23d3  : You hear nothing extra
0x8f  /  0x23de  : 

A psychobot taps you on the shoulder. "Ahem. Your behaviour patterns seem irrational". You feel a hypo.. Then nothing
0x90  /  0x2426  : I didn't think you meant it
0x91  /  0x2437  : I didn't expect you to say that!
0x92  /  0x244d  : Time passes
0x93  /  0x2456  : There's no one to give it to
0x94  /  0x2467  : You can't fill 

0x95  /  0x2471  : You can't empty 

0x96  /  0x247c  : There's no door here!
0x97  /  0x2487  : Yeuch!
0x98  /  0x248d  : 
0x99  /  0x248e  : 
0x9a  /  0x248f  : 
0x9b  /  0x2490  : 
0x9c  /  0x2491  : 
0x9d  /  0x2492  : 
0x9e  /  0x2493  : 
0x9f  /  0x2494  : 
0xa0  /  0x2495  : 
0xa1  /  0x2496  : Welcome to Snowball, an adventure with 7K rooms 
copyright (c) Level 9 Computing 1983.

The interstar freezer, Snowball 9, has entered its target 
starsystem. And it will soon enter the star unless you can do something!

Enter English phrases (without punctuation) to play, Save the Snowball 
to win.
0xa2  /  0x2531  : In 

0xa3  /  0x2535  : On 

0xa4  /  0x2539  : It's empty
0xa5  /  0x2540  : There's a woman in the coffin
0xa6  /  0x254f  : "PLEASE RETURN YOUR COFFIN FIRST!"
0xa7  /  0x2572  : 
0xa8  /  0x2573  : . You're standing on a coffin
0xa9  /  0x2583  : 
0xaa  /  0x2584  : 
0xab  /  0x2585  : The panel has 10 buttons: black, brown, red, orange, yellow, green, blue, purple, grey and white
0xac  /  0x25c5  : The panel has yellow and green buttons
0xad  /  0x25dc  : The button is easy to press
0xae  /  0x25ea  : 
0xaf  /  0x25eb  : The door ahead opens
0xb0  /  0x25f7  : The door behind you closes
0xb1  /  0x2604  : The door is too smooth to grip
0xb2  /  0x2613  : The trapdoor's too high to reach unless you stand on something
0xb3  /  0x2634  : You scramble through a trapdoor
0xb4  /  0x2644  : The door slides open
0xb5  /  0x264e  : You can feel a pit in the floor
0xb6  /  0x265e  : There's a trapdoor in the floor
0xb7  /  0x266c  : There's a trapdoor in the ceiling
0xb8  /  0x267c  : The tube walls are very thin
0xb9  /  0x268b  : You notice a lever beside you
0xba  /  0x269a  : There are LEDs under the bed
0xbb  /  0x26aa  : The machine is a bit loose
0xbc  /  0x26b9  : You notice signs of digging
0xbd  /  0x26ca  : "SORRY! A COLONIST MAY BE LOOSE ON WHITE LEVEL! 
ELEVATOR SERVICE TO AFFECTED AREAS IS SUSPENDED!"
0xbe  /  0x272a  : You can't see it
0xbf  /  0x2733  : You've nothing to dig with
0xc0  /  0x2741  : You can't dig here!
0xc1  /  0x274c  : You dent the shovel
0xc2  /  0x2756  : You're in a tiny hole
0xc3  /  0x2762  : You're in a large hole
0xc4  /  0x276f  : You're at the bottom of a deep pit
0xc5  /  0x2781  : The bottom of the hole collapses. You fall into 
space!
0xc6  /  0x279c  : 

You've no air to breathe!!


0xc7  /  0x27b1  : 

Your air supply is running out!


0xc8  /  0x27c6  : 

The paint explodes in the vacuum!


0xc9  /  0x27da  : There's no web that way. You sure?
0xca  /  0x27ec  : Your attempts to change direction are futile
0xcb  /  0x2807  : Deep snow blocks you
0xcc  /  0x2814  : You bump into a wall. Ouch!
0xcd  /  0x2825  : A crate's in the way
0xce  /  0x2830  : Padding blocks you
0xcf  /  0x283c  : The elevator arrives with a whoosh and its door 
opens
0xd0  /  0x285a  : The floor shakes and the door opens
0xd1  /  0x286c  : A coffin slides from an aperture
0xd2  /  0x287f  : The indicator lights are
0xd3  /  0x288b  :  black
0xd4  /  0x2890  :  brown
0xd5  /  0x2895  :  red
0xd6  /  0x2898  :  orange
0xd7  /  0x289e  :  yellow
0xd8  /  0x28a4  :  green
0xd9  /  0x28a7  :  blue
0xda  /  0x28ac  :  purple
0xdb  /  0x28b2  :  grey
0xdc  /  0x28b5  :  white
0xdd  /  0x28ba  : The coffin slides away


0xde  /  0x28c8  : The lid above rises and a light comes on..
0xdf  /  0x28df  : "OK, take something"
0xe0  /  0x28ef  : "I say! Where's your red ticket?"
0xe1  /  0x2904  : "Not so fast, Citizen. Hand over a green ticket!"
0xe2  /  0x2924  : The android crushes 

0xe3  /  0x2931  :  to pulp!
0xe4  /  0x2939  : The robot takes it and mutters OK
0xe5  /  0x294d  : "That'll do nicely!!"
0xe6  /  0x295e  : "Oi! Where's your authorisation form for that?"
0xe7  /  0x297c  : The robot snarls and grabs it back. You need the right form
0xe8  /  0x299d  : The robot blocks you: "Present your authorisation first!"
0xe9  /  0x29c1  : "Huh! No good to me!"
0xea  /  0x29d1  : "Spose I could let you have something.."
0xeb  /  0x29ee  : A damaged janitor droid is slumped amidst the junk.


0xec  /  0x2a0f  : "Groan!"
0xed  /  0x2a16  : "Please give me a spare part", it wheezes
0xee  /  0x2a2e  : Clank.. Scratch.. "help me"
0xef  /  0x2a43  : The robot tries it in place: 

0xf0  /  0x2a54  : it's OK. The droid is mended! It rummages around for a reward to give you, then bounces away
0xf1  /  0x2a89  : GRAUNCH! ZZZAP! hiss..
0xf2  /  0x2a9d  : A dead droid lies nearby
0xf3  /  0x2aad  : The robot fends you off!
0xf4  /  0x2abc  : The droid needs 

0xf5  /  0x2ac7  : A notice reads "ADMIN"
0xf6  /  0x2ad8  : A notice reads "STORES"
0xf7  /  0x2aea  : The nutrimat machine is decrepit. It's also loose
0xf8  /  0x2b07  : It moves a bit
0xf9  /  0x2b0f  : The machine is psionic and designed to dispense 
your favourite drink
0xfa  /  0x2b38  : . A gap leads west behind the machine
0xfb  /  0x2b4a  : A robot head pokes out 

0xfc  /  0x2b5a  : "Greetings, Respected Citizen. You are most welcome!"
0xfd  /  0x2b7c  : You slide down a garbage chute..
0xfe  /  0x2b91  : "BUG OFF, FLESHIE!"
0xff  /  0x2ba4  : and retracts again with a snort of disgust
0x100  /  0x2bbc  : "DROIDS ONLY!"
0x101  /  0x2bcb  : The table massages you. It's 

0x102  /  0x2bdd  : most invigorating
0x103  /  0x2be9  : not too bad
0x104  /  0x2bf0  : becoming very painful
0x105  /  0x2bfe  : fatal!
0x106  /  0x2c03  : The trashbank sucks it in
0x107  /  0x2c13  : The machine fills it with thin lentil custard
0x108  /  0x2c2e  : The custard tastes even worse than it looks
0x109  /  0x2c48  : It's empty
0x10a  /  0x2c4f  :  
full of liquid
0x10b  /  0x2c59  : A scruffy robot shuffles from the 

0x10c  /  0x2c70  : The scruffy robot shuffles 

0x10d  /  0x2c82  : cyladder
0x10e  /  0x2c88  : onto the cyladder and is carried up
0x10f  /  0x2c9a  : top of the cyladder
0x110  /  0x2ca4  : ramp above
0x111  /  0x2caa  : up the ramp
0x112  /  0x2caf  : onto the cyladder and is carried down
0x113  /  0x2cc2  : ramp below
0x114  /  0x2cc7  : A dumpy droid scuffles about
0x115  /  0x2cdb  : : "Tsk! Tsk! Always dusty"
0x116  /  0x2cf0  : : "How untidy! Dear, dear"
0x117  /  0x2d01  : : "I'll never get it clean"
0x118  /  0x2d16  : The cyladder has descended, leaving a hole!
0x119  /  0x2d31  : The cyladder rejects you
0x11a  /  0x2d40  : You fall through the open cyladder
0x11b  /  0x2d52  : You are carried down
0x11c  /  0x2d5d  : You're carried up
0x11d  /  0x2d68  : You lever it out with the screwdriver
0x11e  /  0x2d7b  : The battery's deep inside, you can't get a grip
0x11f  /  0x2d97  : 

The screen lights!


0x120  /  0x2da0  : 

The screen fades


0x121  /  0x2da9  : Your coffin code is blue mortuary
0x122  /  0x2dbe  : And there's a frozen crewmember in green with code
0x123  /  0x2dd9  : It is closed
0x124  /  0x2de0  : A crewmember is inside
0x125  /  0x2dee  :  (tight shut)
0x126  /  0x2df8  : 
0x127  /  0x2df9  : 

That's your 100th wall!


0x128  /  0x2e0c  : 

You float down..


0x129  /  0x2e18  : It IS lit
0x12a  /  0x2e1f  : It already is
0x12b  /  0x2e27  : You've no power
0x12c  /  0x2e33  : It illuminates brightly
0x12d  /  0x2e42  : It fades to black
0x12e  /  0x2e4c  :  shining brightly
0x12f  /  0x2e59  : With what, eh?
0x130  /  0x2e63  : You cut a gaping slas the h and the escaping air sucks you out!
0x131  /  0x2e83  : Too heavy!
0x132  /  0x2e8d  : The stacker halps you carry it
0x133  /  0x2e9e  : A machine grabs and opens the coffin!


0x134  /  0x2eb6  : "Gimme Liquid Sustenance!"
0x135  /  0x2ecb  : "Must inform.. habidome code.. need water"
0x136  /  0x2ee7  : "Need water to converse"
0x137  /  0x2ef7  : "EEEEEK! YEEEAH! AAAAR!" The screams attract the Nightingales..
0x138  /  0x2f1e  : A Nightingale is rolling away east
0x139  /  0x2f2b  : A Nightingale is here! Its sperical body divides to reveal syringes and grabs. Then it reaches for you..
0x13a  /  0x2f60  : A black spherical Nightingale is advancing from 
the west
0x13b  /  0x2f79  : A clanking noise comes from the west
0x13c  /  0x2f8c  : You can hear quiet clanking
0x13d  /  0x2f9d  : The clanking fades away
0x13e  /  0x2faa  : The clanking pauses outside your room..
0x13f  /  0x2fbf  : Loud clanking comes from outside
0x140  /  0x2fd4  : You hear quiet clanking outside
0x141  /  0x2fe7  : There's a faint machanical noise
0x142  /  0x2ffb  :  A nightingale enters. Its vast bulk splits and 
a hypo las the hes out..
0x143  /  0x3026  : 

The coffin holding the crewmember is held in place


0x144  /  0x3042  : The recoil spins you round
0x145  /  0x3052  : The gun matches your speed to the ground's
0x146  /  0x3069  : You could enter a spidroid "hopper"
0x147  /  0x307e  : She drinks it gratefully. Apparently you should 
visit the habidome whose code is
0x148  /  0x30b5  : You need a spanner
0x149  /  0x30bf  : A massive snowdozer stands beside a pile of fuel blocks, a doorway leads into it. One wide track needs welding
0x14a  /  0x30fe  : A colossal snowdozer towers over you
0x14b  /  0x3111  : No, you CAN'T weld anything here
0x14c  /  0x3127  : You can't weld without 

0x14d  /  0x3135  : You successfully weld the snowdozer's track. It 
is mended!
0x14e  /  0x3156  : The dozer won't start until mended
0x14f  /  0x3168  : It turns! A voice intones "Please Leave The Snowdozer"
0x150  /  0x3185  : The dozer lumbers off, pushing iceblocks into the hole as it goes
0x151  /  0x31ac  : "OUT OF FUEL!"
0x152  /  0x31bb  : It turns! Engines Roar! The Snowball turns away 
from the sun.. YOU HAVE WON!


0x153  /  0x31ea  : 
0x154  /  0x31eb  : 
0x155  /  0x31ec  : 
0x156  /  0x31ed  : 

Sorry, you seem to be dead


0x157  /  0x3201  : The monorail shuttle arrives and its doors open
0x158  /  0x321b  : The shuttle rushes to the next station and opens its doors
0x159  /  0x3238  : It whistles


0x15a  /  0x3241  : A distraught butler robot pushes past and rushes off
0x15b  /  0x3264  : The cat scuffles about, cleaning


0x15c  /  0x3278  : It completely cleans the ramp
0x15d  /  0x3287  : The ramp is coated in unislime
0x15e  /  0x3295  : The cat sucks up 

0x15f  /  0x32a0  : 

1 Instructions

2 Info

3 Desk

4 Library

5 Maps

6 Redisplay
0x160  /  0x32d2  : 

INFO

1 Damage

2 Flight Log

3 Droids

4 Passengers

5 Exit
0x161  /  0x3301  : 

DESK

1 In-tray

2 Out-tray

3 Files

4 Diary

5 Exit
0x162  /  0x332c  : 

MAPS

1 Overview

2 Freezers

3 Accommodation

4 Engine Unit

5 Exit
0x163  /  0x3362  : 

IN-TRAY

1 Flight

2 Beta Missing

3 Help!

4 Exit
0x164  /  0x338a  : 

OUT-TRAY

1 Send

2 Exit
0x165  /  0x33a0  : instructions: "wear visor, look and blink". (Interface design copyright (c) Level 9 Computing 1983)
0x166  /  0x33d9  : a comprehensive technical library with millions 
of entries
0x167  /  0x33fd  : the ship to be undamaged
0x168  /  0x340c  : that the Snowball has veered off course. It's heading for the sun
0x169  /  0x342a  : all droid positions
0x16a  /  0x3438  : that all 1,800,000 passengers are well
0x16b  /  0x3451  : an impenetrable filing system
0x16c  /  0x3463  : a page-a-day diary. The author was worried about "Alpha"
0x16d  /  0x3488  : a map of the Snowball: engine unit at the front, towing a great hollow ice-asteroid
0x16e  /  0x34b2  : maps of the 10 great freezer disks
0x16f  /  0x34c5  : the accommodation dome embedded in the south of 
asteroid wall
0x170  /  0x34e6  : the engine unit: four motors round a vast bay below the control room
0x171  /  0x350c  : a lengthy message querying the Snowball's flight plan
0x172  /  0x3526  : a worried message about two crew-members who seem to be missing
0x173  /  0x354d  : "Help! Alpha is battering down the door"..
0x174  /  0x3565  : "Transmission u/s"
0x175  /  0x3573  : It becomes brighter
0x176  /  0x357d  : The screen changes to show 

0x177  /  0x358b  : The screen shows 

0x178  /  0x3594  : The screen flickers as you look
0x179  /  0x35a7  : . 
Then you return to the menu
0x17a  /  0x35b8  : A massive waldroid guards the ladder
0x17b  /  0x35ce  : A figure with a petrol bomb stands at the west of the room 

0x17c  /  0x35ed  : The room is on fire!
0x17d  /  0x35f7  : The blaze intensifies
0x17e  /  0x3605  : The fire blazes fiercely
0x17f  /  0x3615  : Flames are melting the walls
0x180  /  0x3626  : The robot blocks you
0x181  /  0x3632  : You slip and fall
0x182  /  0x363c  : A las the er blas the t spears out
0x183  /  0x3649  : Burning petrol engulfs you
0x184  /  0x365b  : It plays a scale, from low notes to very high
0x185  /  0x3676  : . The petrol bomb shatters, surrounding its owner in fire. She staggers back through a hidden airlock - you will not see her again!
0x186  /  0x36c0  : The tray reflects a las the er beam back on itself. You hear an explosion
0x187  /  0x36e4  : Nitrogen blas the ts out
0x188  /  0x36f1  :  
and kills the fire
0x189  /  0x36fd  : Paint puffs from the can
0x18a  /  0x370b  : 

The paint blinds the robot which staggers away
0x18b  /  0x3726  : Snowball IX explodes!
0x18c  /  0x3732  : "Keep back or I throw the bomb!"
0x18d  /  0x3747  : "You cannot get to the controls!"
0x18e  /  0x375a  : "You won't stop me!"
0x18f  /  0x3768  : The flas the k joins invisibly with the helmet, recharging its air
0x190  /  0x3789  : You feel a surge of accelleration
0x191  /  0x379c  :  400
0x192  /  0x37a1  : at a junction of monomol ropes. Some look negociable
0x193  /  0x37bd  : in the web
0x194  /  0x37c2  : at a junction
0x195  /  0x37ca  : at a junction in the web. Plas the teel ropes lead away
0x196  /  0x37e1  : at a web junction. Ropes lead in many directions
0x197  /  0x37fe  : at a junction of the web
0x198  /  0x3806  : at a junction of the web
0x199  /  0x380e  : at a junction of the web
0x19a  /  0x3816  : in the web
0x19b  /  0x381b  : at a junction of the web
0x19c  /  0x3823  : in the web
0x19d  /  0x3828  : at a junction of the web
0x19e  /  0x3830  : at a junction of the web
0x19f  /  0x3838  : in the web
0x1a0  /  0x383d  : at a junction of the web
0x1a1  /  0x3845  : at a junction of the web
0x1a2  /  0x384d  : at a junction of the web
0x1a3  /  0x3855  : near the web base
0x1a4  /  0x385e  : holding a rope
0x1a5  /  0x3867  : at a junction of the web
0x1a6  /  0x386f  : at a junction of the web
0x1a7  /  0x3877  : on a rope joining solid ice. It fans out as it enters the snow
0x1a8  /  0x389a  : floating in space
0x1a9  /  0x38a4  : in space near the inner surface of the hollow snowball protecting the freezers
0x1aa  /  0x38ce  : about to hit the fast moving ice-below. You'd better match velocities..
0x1ab  /  0x38f8  : on a flat snowfield north of an immense unclimbably smooth cliff. A pylon stands nearby
0x1ac  /  0x392b  : on trodden snow between a tall pylon and a hemidome calling itself the "Snowball Hilton"
0x1ad  /  0x395a  : on churned and rutted snow below a tall pylon
0x1ae  /  0x3974  : beside the northern ice-cliff which has a tiny cave at its base. A pylon stands nearby
0x1af  /  0x39a6  : on smooth snow beside a pylon, dwarfed by the north cliff
0x1b0  /  0x39c3  : on trampled snow outside a major snowdesic dome. Brilliant light from an entrance split in the hemidome illuminates a nearby pylon
0x1b1  /  0x3a09  : on smooth snow, beside one of a chain of pylons. A ladder leads up the pylon to a cabin
0x1b2  /  0x3a30  : on soft snow outside a sagging warehouse. A dark plas the tic path leads from the warehouse to a nearby pylon
0x1b3  /  0x3a66  : at the rim of a colossal hole, hundreds of meters in width. Stars are visible in its depths. The 
ice-rim is splintered and gouged as if great heavy objects have been pushed over the edge
0x1b4  /  0x3ad1  : on a smooth icefield, lightly dusted with powder snow
0x1b5  /  0x3aec  : in a large hanger packedwith stratogliders queued for launch. The doors of the first are open ready for embarcation
0x1b6  /  0x3b2b  : on a shuttle platform. A button protrudes from the barrier
0x1b7  /  0x3b4a  : on a ladder up the pylon
0x1b8  /  0x3b58  : in the Robodome. A wide, rippled ramp leads down into the ground
0x1b9  /  0x3b78  : on a straight ramp
0x1ba  /  0x3b81  : at the west corner of the cave
0x1bb  /  0x3b8d  : at the north corner of the cave
0x1bc  /  0x3b9a  : at the south corner
0x1bd  /  0x3ba0  : at the east corner of the cave
0x1be  /  0x3bad  : at the base of a straight ramp, in the middle of a cave hacked from the ice
0x1bf  /  0x3bce  : in a snowrail carriage. Uncomfortable lumpy benches are moulded from the trash-strewn floor and 
the filthy windows are opaque. There's a "go" button
0x1c0  /  0x3c24  : in the high control bubble of the Snowdozer. An 
engraved panel at the front of the cab has a keyhole set into it
0x1c1  /  0x3c5e  : in the snowdozer's engine room
0x1c2  /  0x3c6c  : 
0x1c3  /  0x3c6d  : 
0x1c4  /  0x3c6e  : on a significant cylindrical ledge above steps to a toroidal walkway. Transpex tubes lead away through a maze of wires and machinery
0x1c5  /  0x3cc0  : floating in a flexible transpex tube through the central torus of a major freezer unit. Scaled-up mechanisms are visible through the soft walls 
and, far below, a circular path surrounds you
0x1c6  /  0x3d2e  : following a winding transpex tunnel between vast lumpy metallic discs. Tiny light sources flicker far below, providing the only illumination
0x1c7  /  0x3d7f  : on a toroidal walkway
0x1c8  /  0x3d8c  : on a curving path in a 100m torus. A wide glas the sy tube spans the space above through a net of wires and pipes. A button protrudes from the floor
0x1c9  /  0x3dda  : on a toroidal walkway
0x1ca  /  0x3de7  : on a toroidal walkway
0x1cb  /  0x3df4  : on a toroidal walkway beside a ramp. Tubes criss-cross the space above
0x1cc  /  0x3e19  : on a toroidal walkway
0x1cd  /  0x3e26  : in the winch room beside a pair of linedrives. A trapdoor is bolted to the low ceiling and monofibes hang down into the gloom
0x1ce  /  0x3e5f  : clinging to ropes in the gloom
0x1cf  /  0x3e6d  : on the elevator roof
0x1d0  /  0x3e79  : in a blue glas the s elevator. A sliding door makes up one wall; the others are featureless apart from a panel of multi-coloured buttons. Square trapdoors show in floor and ceiling
0x1d1  /  0x3ed9  : clinging to a single rope below the elevator
0x1d2  /  0x3ef0  : in a grimy pit. A rope hangs down from above
0x1d3  /  0x3f0b  : in a curving e/w corridor south of a wide entrance. A button protrudes from the floor and indicator lights decorate the ceiling
0x1d4  /  0x3f4e  : in a spotless white alcove beside a complex revival machine
0x1d5  /  0x3f6f  : in a curving east-west corridor below indicator 
lights
0x1d6  /  0x3f8a  : in a curving e/w corridor beside a green door. Lights show above it
0x1d7  /  0x3fac  : in a curving e/w corridor beside a blue door. Lights show above it
0x1d8  /  0x3fcf  : at the entrance to a blue mortuary beside indicator lights and a control panel
0x1d9  /  0x3ff7  : by the entrance to a green mortuary beside lights and a panel
0x1da  /  0x4014  : in a blue mortuary beside a smooth ceramic slab. Lights twinkle beside a trapdoor on the ceiling
0x1db  /  0x4043  : in a green mortuary beside a smooth slab. Indicators illuminate a trapdoor above
0x1dc  /  0x406c  : at the south end of a narrowing marblon cylinder. A button emerges beside an airlock door
0x1dd  /  0x4097  : at the north end of a widening marblon cylinder. A button pokes from the floor beside an airlock door
0x1de  /  0x40c7  : in a wide simulated-marble tube. An immovable grill is set into the floor, and an empty padded cell can be seen between the bars
0x1df  /  0x410e  : in a vast smooth-surfaced cylinder beside a contoured ramp
0x1e0  /  0x4129  : standing on smooth simrock on the side of a large tube. A cyladder descends through red light
0x1e1  /  0x4158  : standing inside a substantial smooth cylinder. A ramp leads down beside you and a similar, larger ramp is just visible opposite, across the tube
0x1e2  /  0x419f  : in a carpetted massage parlour hung about with red velcron drapes. The ceiling is polished to a 
mirror finish. A sumptuous leather couch stands 
in the middle of the floor
0x1e3  /  0x41fb  : in a bare storeroom
0x1e4  /  0x4205  : in a large low room, surrounded by lights and vids. A barely-audible high pitched humming emerges from a vast display panel with the legend "Snowball IX Freezer Control" to the south. A luminous cyladder rises through the ceiling
0x1e5  /  0x4280  : in the southeast corner of freezer control
0x1e6  /  0x4292  : in the northeast corner of freezer control
0x1e7  /  0x42a6  : behind the display panel. You are surrounded by 
the shiny warm cases of a dozen holojectors
0x1e8  /  0x42d7  : in a wood-grained library
0x1e9  /  0x42e8  : in a cramped mempak archive. Locked racks hold titles like Fusion Mechanics, Genetics by Numbers, The Last Christians, Choosing Your Small Business Android, COBOL for the Arcturan Gigabrain, Playgirl the First Hundred Years, and The Human Race and How To Win. Each pack zaps selected highlights (much better than its real contents) at your midbrain
0x1ea  /  0x43c0  : in the condo: a small, comfortable rest area. An airbed is suspended from the ceiling
0x1eb  /  0x43ed  : in a small tiled room. Very little space is needed to hold a wc, shower and basin but there's nothing of any game-relevance
0x1ec  /  0x442e  : in the diner: a minute corner of the condo, equipped for eating etc. A "natural wholefood no chemicals" machine is fixed to the wall, alongside 
a square hole for garbage
0x1ed  /  0x4492  : in a cupboard
0x1ee  /  0x449b  : in a narrow service duct, beside an aircon vent
0x1ef  /  0x44b5  : in a tight e/w crawlway
0x1f0  /  0x44c4  : 
0x1f1  /  0x44c5  : in a dusty corner
0x1f2  /  0x44cd  : on a rubbish tip. A garbage chute is supported by corroded wires far above, much too high for you to reach it
0x1f3  /  0x450f  : on a great pile of garbage
0x1f4  /  0x451e  : in an overflowing, broken junk processor (made by GIGO industries)
0x1f5  /  0x454a  : on a wide ramp to heavy plas the teel door. A battery of videyes surround a notable flas the hing sign: "DROID-HANDLED STORE SERVICE. PRIVATE"
0x1f6  /  0x45a2  : on a gently sloping spiral ramp above a vast warehouse. Crates reach the ceiling
0x1f7  /  0x45cd  : at a small counter staffed by a faceless android
0x1f8  /  0x45e9  : at a wide counter staffed by a faceless android
0x1f9  /  0x4605  : in a corner, beside a red ticket machine
0x1fa  /  0x4617  : in a corner beside a green ticket machine
0x1fb  /  0x4629  : in a store room
0x1fc  /  0x4630  : in a beige, kidney-shaped entrance hall south of a buttoned airlock
0x1fd  /  0x4658  : in a tasteful pink and green alcove beside a security door. There's a combination panel
0x1fe  /  0x4686  : in a small round room
0x1ff  /  0x4690  : on narrow, winding stairs leading down to an airlock iris. There is the usual floor button
0x200  /  0x46c0  : 
0x201  /  0x46c1  : in a ruined bubble farm
0x202  /  0x46cf  : in an observatory. All the equipment has been systematically broken and the room is in chaos
0x203  /  0x4702  : at the base of Jacob's Ladder. A very long opaque tube, wound about with plaitted plas the teel fibres, rises dead straight above you. A ladder runs 
up the middle
0x204  /  0x4756  : climbing Jacob's Ladder. Looking up and down, you realise it must be miles long! Hovever, in some mysterious way, it seems easier to climb than 
it should
0x205  /  0x47ab  : climbing Jacob's Ladder. Although you're climbing slowly, it feels as if you're moving very rapidly..
0x206  /  0x47e2  : near the top of Jacob's Ladder. Above is the light at the end of the tunnel
0x207  /  0x47fe  : on a tiny platform, suspended in the middle of a colossal metallic cylinder. A yawning gulf separates the platform from a seemingly-small metallic lip round the outside. Four frail walkways join it across the abyss and a major twisted rope 
hangs down to support a corroded 5 klom snowball far below
0x208  /  0x48ab  : on a wide lip west of a colossal red cylinder
0x209  /  0x48c1  : on a wide ledge round the north edge of a huge red cylinder. A thick ramp winds upwards, there's a tiny opening in the cylinder wall, an insubstantial bridge is suspended over the abyss below 
the cylinder, and if you feel tired of life there's always down..
0x20a  /  0x4949  : on a wide ledge south of a the abyss at the bottom of a colossal red cylinder. A 5 klom snowball hangs from a strong (!) wire down the middle of the tube. A spindly bridge joins the wire
0x20b  /  0x49aa  : on a wide ledge east of the abyss. A small hole 
enters the cylinder wall nearby, and a narrow bridge leads out over the abyss
0x20c  /  0x49ed  : on a wide sloping ramp west of the red cylinder
0x20d  /  0x4a03  : on a wide sloping ramp south of the red cylinder
0x20e  /  0x4a19  : on a wide sloping ramp east of the red cylinder. Squinting up through the glare, you can make out a bunch of enormous clawhooks - each attached 
to a segmented wire
0x20f  /  0x4a76  : at the top of the wide ramp, north of the red cylinder. The ramp curves west through a pair of heavy blas the t doors
0x210  /  0x4aaa  : in a wide, dark east-west corridor. The snowdozer is jammed in a pair of buckled blas the t doors to 
the east
0x211  /  0x4adc  : at a T-junction where the dark passage ends at a brightly lit corridor. Looks risky..
0x212  /  0x4b0c  : in a bright n/s corridor, at a pair of locked doors. You don't have time to explore the rooms beyond them: the important thing is to go south to the Control Room
0x213  /  0x4b5f  : at a junction in a north-south corridor
0x214  /  0x4b6e  : at the end of the corridor, beside the entrance 
to the control room
0x215  /  0x4b8d  : beside the main instrument panel. The only control that you will ever understand (without psychomods/RNA boosts) is a red lever: "manual/autopilot"
0x216  /  0x4be5  : in a sloping crawlway
0x217  /  0x4bf2  : in a sloping crawlway
0x218  /  0x4bff  : 
0x219  /  0x4c00  : in the southwest corner of freezer control, beside a control chair. The south wall is a wavery and obscure confusion of flickery projected vids
0x21a  /  0x4c47  : in a comfortable cave carved into warm sandstone. Bright sunlight streams in from the east
0x21b  /  0x4c76  : in a beige alcove at the rear of the cave. A small fire burns at one side, and there's a wide ledge strewn with cut meadowsweet at the other
0x21c  /  0x4cbe  : in one cubicle of a great library. Thousands of 
people are studying at similar cubicles around, 
their hushed voices filling the air with a low murmering
0x21d  /  0x4d18  : in a soft, pink room. Gentle shapes move restfully across the walls to soft musical rhythms
0x21e  /  0x4d4f  : in a grey room, lit by flickering candles
0x21f  /  0x4d66  : in a solid black room filled with a glaring white light. Despite the intensity of the illumination, you know it does not show everything clearly. Yet increasing the brightness would only dazzle: concealing more certainly
0x220  /  0x4ddf  : on a wide sunlit beach of yellow sand. Several large rocky outcrops rise up all around. Gulls call as they soar overhead
0x221  /  0x4e2a  : on a desert island in the middle of a sweeping coral atoll. Palm trees rise overhead: their fallen fronds forming a soft heap
0x222  /  0x4e72  : in a superb recreation lounge, surrounded by a great variety of ways of passing the time: dream-games, exercisers, learndromats, fundroids etc. 
All are irrepairably smashed
0x223  /  0x4ed8  : in a sumptious bathroom with sunken bath, jacuzzi etc.
0x224  /  0x4efa  : in a bright meadow, full of flowers and sweet grasses
0x225  /  0x4f19  : under the shade of an old apple tree. The ground is covered with thick, soft moss
0x226  /  0x4f43  : in a forest glade (yes, really). Warm sunlight filters through the branches overhead, and cute little furry animals peer out from the undergrowth. Narrow leaf-strewn pathways lead in all directions through fragrant vegetation
0x227  /  0x4fc8  : in a snake-pit. Venemous reptiles are slithering towards you
0x228  /  0x4fea  : in an open-plan control room. As the ship flies 
itself there are few controls, just an assortment of computers and displays of no interest to anyone. They're decades out of date - only kept in case the modern stuff fails
0x229  /  0x5068  : in a cylindrical airlock between two iris doors
0x22a  /  0x5081  : in a featureless clindrical airlock between two 
iris doors
0x22b  /  0x50a2  : in a cubic airlock between two iris doors
0x22c  /  0x50b8  : in a vertical airlock between two iris doors
0x22d  /  0x50cf  : in an ice tunnel
0x22e  /  0x50d9  : in a tiny stratoglider. It is extensibly damaged
0x22f  /  0x50f4  : in a padded room
0x230  /  0x50fc  : in the flexible bubble body of a spidroid
0x231  /  0x5113  : in a vast docking bay, surrounded by piles of metallic junk. The massive exterior doors are open to space and, through them, lights are visible 
in the far south. A thickly knotted rope stretches into the void. At the back of the docking bay 
is an airlock iris with a floor button
0x232  /  0x51a5  : in the bright, tidy docking bay of the crew habidome. An airlock iris (with button) leads further into the dome
0x233  /  0x51df  : sitting on a plas the teel container high up in the Robot Stores. More crates stretch south as far as you can see, while to the north is a revolting 
expanse of garbage. There's a square aperture in the wall by your head
0x234  /  0x5254  : north of a wall of crates
0x235  /  0x5262  : in a cramped space between crates and piles of rubbish
0x236  /  0x5282  : on a sloping junk heap
0x237  /  0x528f  : in a gangway between stacked cases
0x238  /  0x52a2  : at the base of a spiral ramp, surrounded by stacked crates and containers
0x239  /  0x52c7  : in a gangway between stacked cases
0x23a  /  0x52da  : in an aisle between stacked cases
0x23b  /  0x52ec  : in the stores. Piles of cases stretch in all directions
0x23c  /  0x5309  : in an aisle between stacked cases in the stores
0x23d  /  0x5321  : in an aisle between crates in the stores
0x23e  /  0x5336  : in a gangway between stacked containers
0x23f  /  0x534d  : in a sponge-lined coffin
0x240  /  0x535a  : lying on a comfortable couch
0x241  /  0x536a  : in a broken waldo coccoon
0x242  /  0x5378  : on the airbed, floating amidst warm air currents
0x243  /  0x5394  : in a padded cell. The walls are lined by Tuffkwilt (TM) padding, and the only door (in the ceiling) cannot be opened by you: a wide passageway is visible through its bars. A "Nutrimat" machine is the only furniture
0x244  /  0x540f  : seated at the console
0x245  /  0x541a  : 
0x246  /  0x541b  : 
0x247  /  0x541c  : 
0x248  /  0x541d  : 
0x249  /  0x541e  : 
0x24a  /  0x541f  : 
0x24b  /  0x5420  : 
0x24c  /  0x5421  : 
0x24d  /  0x5422  : 
0x24e  /  0x5423  : 
0x24f  /  0x5424  : 
0x250  /  0x5425  : 
0x251  /  0x5426  : 
0x252  /  0x5427  : 
0x253  /  0x5428  : 
0x254  /  0x5429  : 
0x255  /  0x542a  : 
0x256  /  0x542b  : 
0x257  /  0x542c  : on a great pile of garbage
0x258  /  0x543b  : 
0x259  /  0x543c  : in the southwest corner of Freezer Control, beside a control chair. To the south is an alcove full of machinery
0x25a  /  0x5470  : in a beige room
0x25b  /  0x5478  : in a beige bedroom
0x25c  /  0x5482  : in a pink room
0x25d  /  0x5488  : in a pink bedroom
0x25e  /  0x5491  : in a russet room
0x25f  /  0x549a  : in a russet bedroom beside a crude pit
0x260  /  0x54ae  : in a yellow room
0x261  /  0x54b5  : in a yellow bedroom
0x262  /  0x54bf  : in a well-equipped, but spartan, recreation lounge
0x263  /  0x54dd  : in an ugly bathroom
0x264  /  0x54e9  : in a pale green room
0x265  /  0x54f3  : in a green bedroom
0x266  /  0x54fc  : in a large round room with many exits
0x267  /  0x550f  : in a crudely gouged pit
0x268  /  0x551d  : 
0x269  /  0x551e  : 
0x26a  /  0x551f  : 
0x26b  /  0x5520  : 
0x26c  /  0x5521  : 
0x26d  /  0x5522  : 
0x26e  /  0x5523  : 
0x26f  /  0x5524  : 
0x270  /  0x5525  : 
0x271  /  0x5526  : 
0x272  /  0x5527  : 
0x273  /  0x5528  : 
0x274  /  0x5529  : 
0x275  /  0x552a  : 
0x276  /  0x552b  : 
0x277  /  0x552c  : The armour is scarred by hot metal splas the hes. It's just your size
0x278  /  0x5550  : Very intricate: translucent with an embedded sensor web
0x279  /  0x5572  : Ordinary sun-watcher specs
0x27a  /  0x5584  : An ugly garment which fits like a second skin.. 
perhaps a hippo's
0x27b  /  0x55af  : Clustered glowgems indicate
0x27c  /  0x55c1  : A standard USAR vac-hat. It would attach to a suit collar and has a connector at the back
0x27d  /  0x55f7  : Just your size: full-body with monokini reinforcement and a circular metal collar. Very tough material
0x27e  /  0x5639  : It's an impressive status symbol: as worn by the elite
0x27f  /  0x565a  : 
0x280  /  0x565b  : 
0x281  /  0x565c  : A light, pressurised, 100 ml can. Paint jets out if you squeeze it
0x282  /  0x5684  : A miniature dilithium crystal battery
0x283  /  0x569b  : Dead, I'm afraid
0x284  /  0x56a8  : The card is green, tastefully inlaid in purple
0x285  /  0x56c5  : The cat feels hard and boney, with a large circular mouth. It vibrates as you hold it
0x286  /  0x56f7  : It's smooth and black with indicators showing
0x287  /  0x570f  : The expanded polystyrene cup is an engineering triumph. Even its defects (the slow leaking of the contents and the release of toxins from the plas the tic) led directly to the crucial Maxwell Heatsink!
0x288  /  0x577f  : The two cylinders are labelled O2 and C2H2 respectively
0x289  /  0x57a0  : The flute can play high or low notes. Or, indeed, a tune
0x28a  /  0x57c6  : A one-shot, carbon-dioxide fire extinguisher: "squeeze to activate"
0x28b  /  0x57f3  : An infomatic probe for android faults. Attach to your robot
0x28c  /  0x5819  : The flas the k is labelled "Mineral Air, Spring-bottled for natural freshness". There's a flexiconnector at one end
0x28d  /  0x585d  : A P45! It's incomprehensible jargon
0x28e  /  0x5873  : A UB40, written in Eurogibburocratish
0x28f  /  0x588f  : An ominous P1. Simple and concise, but all it does is reference other forms
0x290  /  0x58bc  : The form is almost entirely propoganda for the current government's policies
0x291  /  0x58e8  : It has no ammunition and a wide, tapering nozzle
0x292  /  0x5907  : The wand whistles and vibrates as it moves
0x293  /  0x5922  : The obligatory bunch of keys that crops up in all adventures
0x294  /  0x5944  : 
0x295  /  0x5945  : It looks like a welding lance
0x296  /  0x5956  : The las the er is partially melted and will never work again
0x297  /  0x5975  : According to the label, it holds details of passengers
0x298  /  0x5998  : 
0x299  /  0x5999  : It's very odd
0x29a  /  0x59a2  : 
0x29b  /  0x59a3  : 
0x29c  /  0x59a4  : Very sharp
0x29d  /  0x59ab  : It's an ordinary screwdriver with a double-curved blade to maximise screwtop grip
0x29e  /  0x59df  : The shovel has a light foamed blade: ideal for digging snow
0x29f  /  0x5a01  : The spanner will fit any bolt
0x2a0  /  0x5a13  : It's red
0x2a1  /  0x5a18  : It's green
0x2a2  /  0x5a1e  : 
0x2a3  /  0x5a1f  : It looks dangerous
0x2a4  /  0x5a2b  : Looks like something out of a robot
0x2a5  /  0x5a40  : A droid component
0x2a6  /  0x5a4c  : A robot part
0x2a7  /  0x5a54  : A robot spare
0x2a8  /  0x5a5c  : A tow-behind lifter, suitable for moving coffins
0x2a9  /  0x5a78  : 
0x2aa  /  0x5a79  : 
0x2ab  /  0x5a7a  : 
0x2ac  /  0x5a7b  : 
0x2ad  /  0x5a7c  : 
0x2ae  /  0x5a7d  : Battery-powered
0x2af  /  0x5a88  : The viewer has openings for a battery and a mempak
0x2b0  /  0x5aa7  : It's perfectly polished
0x2b1  /  0x5ab6  : It floats in mid-air
0x2b2  /  0x5ac2  : A very well-engineered toolbox
0x5ad4 0x2
0x6eed
